<!-- ---
layout: null
---
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/author/Bekah/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2025-07-07T11:39:29-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://localhost:4000/author/Bekah/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">BekahHW | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Code. Community. Content.</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Debugging Mobile Navigation Bugs with AI Code Assistants: Continue vs Copilot vs Cursor</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/Which-Code-Assistant-Fix-Real-Problems-Best" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Debugging Mobile Navigation Bugs with AI Code Assistants: Continue vs Copilot vs Cursor" />
      <published>2025-06-30T00:00:00-04:00</published>
      <updated>2025-06-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/Which%20Code%20Assistant%20Fix%20Real%20Problems%20Best</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Which-Code-Assistant-Fix-Real-Problems-Best">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A follow-up to “Which Code Assistant Actually Helps Developers Grow?” This time, testing how AI assistants handle debugging existing code problems.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, I &lt;a href=&quot;https://bekahhw.com/Which-Code-Assistant-Helps-Developers-Grow&quot;&gt;tested three AI coding assistants on building a new feature&lt;/a&gt;. This time, I wanted to see how they handle something most developers deal with daily: debugging existing code problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was debugging a mobile responsiveness issue on my Astro + Tailwind site (see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BekahHW/siblings-write/&quot;&gt;GitHub Project here&lt;/a&gt;). The navbar wasn’t collapsing on mobile, causing layout issues. Instead of a full navigation bar cramming into mobile view, I needed a proper hamburger menu. Instead of manually rewriting it, I tested how three AI code assistants—Continue, Copilot, and Cursor—would solve it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/240b8dcxjht9ly0hg9v1.gif&quot; alt=&quot;gif showing the responsive layout issue on mobile is fixed when deleting the nav bar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what I told each assistant:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“There’s an issue with mobile view on the site. I think the main problem is with the navbar. But I don’t think it makes sense to have a nav bar for a mobile site. We should make the site responsive and add a sticky nav bar with a hamburger menu instead of the full navigation bar once the site hits mobile-sized screens.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR&lt;/strong&gt;: I tested Continue, GitHub Copilot, and Cursor to debug a broken mobile navbar in an Astro-based site. Continue offered the best explanations and teaching moments, Cursor was fast but made extra assumptions, and Copilot was fast but error-prone. If you’re debugging UI bugs, Continue’s Chat mode helps you understand why things break, not just how to fix them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;can-continue-debug-a-responsive-nav-issue-in-astro&quot;&gt;Can Continue Debug a Responsive Nav Issue in Astro?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used &lt;a href=&quot;https://continue.dev/&quot;&gt;Continue&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.continue.dev/agent/how-to-use-it&quot;&gt;Agent mode&lt;/a&gt;, giving it context from &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Header.astro&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Nav.astro&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;BaseLayout.astro&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/bg21110n6vfs19es00l5.png&quot; alt=&quot;Continue.dev suggesting hamburger menu fixes in Astro project&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-good&quot;&gt;The Good&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Created a dedicated hamburger menu component&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Asked for permission between file changes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When I got a transparency issue with the menu panel, it fixed it in one go&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It added comments to understand the steps it was taking in the code and debug logs in the code to help me see what was working and when&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Everything worked within 12 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-learning-experience&quot;&gt;The Learning Experience&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I tested the same fix using Continue’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.continue.dev/chat/how-to-use-it&quot;&gt;Chat mode&lt;/a&gt; instead of Agent mode, it took longer but provided much more thorough explanations. The conversation was more educational, walking me through the reasoning behind each change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;verdict&quot;&gt;Verdict&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continue balances efficiency with learning. Agent mode got me working code fast, while Chat mode taught me the “why” behind the solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/9ss3rdoqhm59mkjjqxbl.png&quot; alt=&quot;Copilot output showing approach to fixing broken layout with overlapping nav menu&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-copilot-handles-responsive-navbar-bugs&quot;&gt;How Copilot Handles Responsive Navbar Bugs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copilot started by unnecessarily converting a Svelte component, then immediately threw a TypeScript error:
&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Argument of type 'EventTarget' is not assignable to parameter of type 'Node'&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure why it decided that the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ThemeToggleButton&lt;/code&gt; needed to be converted. At the very least, that’s outside of the scope of this PR, in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/fi883ls0s34e83ux1zra.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image description&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was able to solve the problem pretty quickly when I used the “Fix with Copilot” function, explaining, “You should cast e.target to Node when passing it to .contains() to resolve the type error.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-real-problem&quot;&gt;The Real Problem&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hamburger menu initially didn’t appear at all. The responsiveness was “fixed” because the navigation disappeared, but users couldn’t access any menu items.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After back-and-forth debugging, Copilot resorted to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;!important&lt;/code&gt; declarations (not ideal) and the old “turn the background red” debugging trick. Even when the menu became visible, clicking it did nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, we identified JavaScript as the culprit. Copilot fixed it, but then the menu links appeared directly over the page content without any background container. More back-and-forth with questionable styling decisions followed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was to the point where I definitely could fix this faster than having a back-and-forth with Copilot, so I called it. After that, I also realized there was a bug where, after expanding the hamburger menu on mobile and then switching to desktop view, the mobile menu remained open on top of the restored navigation bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/tvvd7pmfl9gm2usc0k1w.png&quot; alt=&quot;nav panel on top of page text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;: About 20 minutes, with me ultimately fixing the styles myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning Value&lt;/strong&gt;: Minimal. Copilot told me what it was doing, but didn’t really explain its approach or help me understand the underlying problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cursor-fixes-more-than-you-askhelpful-or-harmful&quot;&gt;Cursor Fixes More Than You Ask—Helpful or Harmful?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cursor’s response was immediate and organized:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/7vx5vt6fdw9b2utz4gre.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cursor's initial message detailing what needed to be done to implement the hamburger menu&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-process&quot;&gt;The Process&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Automatically read the global CSS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Outlined exactly what needed to change and why&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provided all necessary file updates&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hit the same cross-page JavaScript issue as Copilot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-interesting-part&quot;&gt;The Interesting Part&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cursor went beyond my request, automatically improving mobile styles across the site that I hadn’t asked for. This raises an interesting question: should AI assistants make assumptions about what you “really” need?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;: About 15 minutes to complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning Value&lt;/strong&gt;: Good explanations of changes. I appreciate that it gives more information on why errors were happening in the context of using Astro.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/vsk81fkbeau7jkmdtafh.png&quot; alt=&quot;showing the issue and how it understands and corrects it&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;context-switching-costs&quot;&gt;Context Switching Costs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s something I noticed that none of the assistants addressed: familiarity bias. Cursor and GitHub Copilot felt nearly identical to use, so I moved faster with them. Continue required slightly more of a learning curve, which actually slowed me down initially but provided better educational value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t a knock against Continue. It’s a reminder that switching tools comes with costs, even when the new tool might be better in the long term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;debugging-vs-building-different-skills-required&quot;&gt;Debugging vs. Building: Different Skills Required&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This debugging scenario revealed something my first test missed, that building new features and fixing existing problems require different AI assistance approaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;building-new-features&quot;&gt;Building New Features&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clear requirements&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blank slate approach&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Focus on “what should this do?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;debugging-existing-code&quot;&gt;Debugging Existing Code&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Understanding legacy decisions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identifying root causes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Focusing on “why isn’t this working?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continue did well with the debugging mindset, asking permission before changes and explaining the reasoning. Copilot and Cursor were more aggressive about “fixing” things, sometimes creating new problems in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;which-ai-coding-assistant-wins-for-debugging&quot;&gt;Which AI Coding Assistant Wins for Debugging?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For Learning&lt;/strong&gt;: Continue, especially in Chat mode. It helped me understand not just what was broken, but why the original approach failed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For Speed&lt;/strong&gt;: Cursor, if you don’t mind AI making assumptions about improvements you didn’t request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-bigger-picture&quot;&gt;The Bigger Picture&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This comparison reinforced something I mentioned in my first post: the tool is only part of the equation. Each assistant performed differently not just because of their capabilities, but because of how they approached the problem-solving process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continue treated debugging as a learning opportunity. Copilot treated it as a code completion task. Cursor treated it as a comprehensive redesign project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to know which coding assistant helps developers grow when you’re debugging, try this: Before asking for a fix, ask the AI to help you understand why the original code failed. The debugging skills you develop will be more valuable than any individual fix.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      
        <summary type="html">A follow-up to “Which Code Assistant Actually Helps Developers Grow?” This time, testing how AI assistants handle debugging existing code problems.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Which Code Assistant Actually Helps Developers Grow?</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/Which-Code-Assistant-Helps-Developers-Grow" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Which Code Assistant Actually Helps Developers Grow?" />
      <published>2025-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</published>
      <updated>2025-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/Which%20Code%20Assistant%20Helps%20Developers%20Grow</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Which-Code-Assistant-Helps-Developers-Grow">&lt;p&gt;Over the past year, we’ve had a ton of conversations at &lt;a href=&quot;http://virtualcoffee.io/&quot;&gt;Virtual Coffee&lt;/a&gt; about AI. If you’ve opened up X or LinkedIn, you probably realize that people have very strong opinions about AI. At Virtual Coffee, we’re a pretty close-knit community, so there are a lot of concerns about the impacts of AI, how junior developers grow (or stay stagnant) with AI, whether or not to adopt it as a team, and whether to use it without telling your boss. At the heart of a lot of these conversations is the feeling that you’re somehow “cheating” if you use AI, and that you won’t learn or grow if you’re using it. I think the sentiment comes from the right place, caring about people, but I think there are a lot of options and approaches you can take to prevent that. I believe that when we consider the evolving landscape in tech, we also need to think about the changing landscape of tech education. Most of us will end up using AI in our workflow, either out of necessity or because our team mandates it. That’s why I also think that AI coding assistants actually have the ability to help everyone grow in ways they couldn’t before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/ykdojo/status/1932149031196856738&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/6unkesc921s6jw892qz6.png&quot; alt=&quot;ykdogo tweet&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;learning-vs-speed-trap&quot;&gt;Learning vs. Speed Trap&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your approach to learning with AI assistants definitely matters. And not all AI coding assistants will help increase developers’ coding skills. Learning about the code you’re writing, how your team approaches problems, and how to utilize AI as part of your workflow is necessary to grow in tech. Teams don’t need someone who can prompt their way to a working solution but can’t debug it when it breaks. Most AI coding assistants are optimized for speed and not for learning. They’re designed to get you from problem to solution as quickly as possible. If your goal is skill development, you should think of AI adoption more like onboarding a mentor, rather than replacing you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;context-aware-guidance&quot;&gt;Context-Aware Guidance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most effective learning-focused assistants should understand what you’re trying to do and what you should learn from doing it. They highlight patterns, point out potential issues, and suggest alternative approaches that might teach you something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I’m testing out a couple of AI coding assistants on a new feature. (I’m interested in doing a follow-up post that uses it on an existing file. Let me know if that’s something you’d like to see!)  I tested out each coding assistant on a new feature I’m adding to my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.siblingswrite.com/&quot;&gt;writing site&lt;/a&gt;, with this simple prompt:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I want to create a game for this site, where people (not logged in) can add a word to a story. Once the story hits 300 words, it locks the submission. No one should be able to submit more than 3 words in a row.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are my takeaways for Continue, GitHub Copilot, and Cursor. I gave the same initial prompt for each of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;continue&quot;&gt;Continue&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://continue.dev/&quot;&gt;Continue&lt;/a&gt; stands out here because their philosophy explicitly addresses the learning problem. Their documentation talks about “amplifying intent” rather than replacing it, and they specifically warn against becoming a “human clipboard.” You can explore ideas through “vibe coding” during creative phases, but when it comes to production work, they emphasize that developers need to stay in control. It’s open source, model-flexible (bring your own LLM), and encourages creating custom assistants that reinforce your team’s coding standards. For teams focused on growth and increasing their developers’ coding skills, Continue offers both transparency and control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before giving me any kind of code, it gave me an initial planning response, outlining a step-by-step approach to the user story. Seeing the plan helps the user to walk through the task with Continue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/uuws98nat1n8qrflz4nn.png&quot; alt=&quot;Overview of the approach Continue takes to implement feature&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this, it provided commented code along with a reusable template. The inline comments break down some of the logic, and helps the user understand the process it went through to generate the code. After the code, it summarized all the changes it had made. 
You might notice it mentions Flask, but this is actually an Astro app. That was my mistake. When I initially set up the assistant, I had configured it with Python-focused instructions and directed it to Python documentation, since my rules were originally written for a Python assistant. Once I updated those settings and specifically shared my repository with the assistant, Continue was able to properly follow my project’s styling conventions and leverage the existing components.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, it gave both an overview of what was implemented and ideas for improvement. I appreciate that it provided more context about its approach, commented code throughout the new file, and offered inspiration for my next iteration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/3iwg6njdy7a2fk8plmf8.png&quot; alt=&quot;Overview of the approach it took and the improvements I could make&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without having to ask further questions about the decisions it made and the approach it took, I think it provided a good amount of context for the developer to understand the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;copilot&quot;&gt;Copilot&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/features/copilot/&quot;&gt;GitHub Copilot&lt;/a&gt; is known for excelling at code completion and includes agent-based features. It can speed up repetitive tasks, but the learning tends to happen through osmosis. You need to recognize the patterns in suggestions and might pick them up over time. You have to be more active with your learning by asking Copilot about the decisions it made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copilot’s approach was a lot different from Continue’s. It jumps straight into code generation without context-setting or explanation of its approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It did provide a “wrap up” after the code, but it wasn’t as thorough or complete as what I got from Continue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/3wmwmu4lse15u873zasm.png&quot; alt=&quot;Wrap up of the implementation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For what it’s worth, Copilot also told me that creating a Svelte component was the best option, and then, when I questioned it, Copilot told me that Astro was actually the best path. It was flexible with the approach once I questioned it, but it definitely required me to go down the rabbit hole with it. Learning is definitely passive with Copilot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cursor&quot;&gt;Cursor&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cursor.com/&quot;&gt;Cursor&lt;/a&gt; offers an AI-first editor experience with agent modes, but their emphasis on “AI that builds with you” raises questions about how much actual building the developer is doing during complex tasks. Although I’m just doing a basic test for this post with a brand new feature, I did experiment a bit with its interactive, AI-native IDE experience by highlighting some of the code it generated and asking, “What does this do?” I plan on doing more of that in a follow-up post for comparison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After being given the same prompt as Continue and Copilot, Cursor walked me through the approach it was taking and included what files it looked at to get there. However, it automatically created a Svelte file for the game (I did have Svelte installed in the project), and I had to do a lot of back and forth with it to understand the decisions it made and why. I’ve actually never used Svelte, so this was something I had to dig into deeper to understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/g2kk5qu91tqrqk2ewtc3.png&quot; alt=&quot;initial overview of the approach&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things I appreciated about Cursor’s experience was that it explained piece by piece and required me to accept changes. That forces the user to think about what’s being implemented. It also auto-corrected some of its own errors, which is a good learning opportunity to see how it debugs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/317dusccwjklrckjxf0s.png&quot; alt=&quot;explaining where the issues lies in the error&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish it would have automatically added code comments throughout, but the explanations were valuable. The takeaways at the end walked through what the user could do and the functionality. It was more thorough than Copilot, but I liked the improvements suggestion that Continue had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/ailxygg7jc0uprc177n0.png&quot; alt=&quot;wrap up of features and how it works&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;building-a-learning-first-ai-strategy&quot;&gt;Building a Learning-First AI Strategy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this exploration is important for new folks coming into tech, and for teams serious about using AI to help their team grow and not just ship faster. The path here should:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start with Intent&lt;/strong&gt;: Before adding any AI tool to your workflow or your team’s, clearly define your goals. Are you trying to help yourself or junior developers on the team understand architectural patterns? Learn a new framework? Improve code review skills?
Different learning goals might call for different AI approaches.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Choose Tools with Teaching DNA&lt;/strong&gt;: Look for AI assistants that were designed with education in mind, not just productivity. Continue’s emphasis on amplifying developer intent rather than replacing it is a good example of this thinking.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implement Learning Safeguards&lt;/strong&gt;: Whatever tool you choose, build processes that encourage learning by requiring explanations for AI-generated solutions, having regular code review focused on understanding, not just correctness, adding pair programming sessions where AI suggestions become discussion points, documenting decisions and trade-offs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Measure Learning, Not Just Output&lt;/strong&gt;: Track whether your developers are asking better questions over time, not just whether they’re closing tickets faster. Are they suggesting alternatives during code review? Can they debug issues in AI-generated code? Are they learning patterns they can apply without AI assistance?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want developers who are using AI to understand problems. That’s the difference between an AI assistant and an AI mentor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wrapping-up&quot;&gt;Wrapping Up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the best AI coding assistant for individuals and teams focuses on developer skill growth. Based on philosophy, approach, and explicit focus on learning, Continue seems to understand this distinction better than most. But the tool is only part of the equation. The bigger part is approaching AI adoption with learning as the primary goal, not just productivity.
The most productive teams and developers understand what they’re building, whether with or without AI help.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      
        <summary type="html">Over the past year, we’ve had a ton of conversations at Virtual Coffee about AI. If you’ve opened up X or LinkedIn, you probably realize that people have very strong opinions about AI. At Virtual Coffee, we’re a pretty close-knit community, so there are a lot of concerns about the impacts of AI, how junior developers grow (or stay stagnant) with AI, whether or not to adopt it as a team, and whether to use it without telling your boss. At the heart of a lot of these conversations is the feeling that you’re somehow “cheating” if you use AI, and that you won’t learn or grow if you’re using it. I think the sentiment comes from the right place, caring about people, but I think there are a lot of options and approaches you can take to prevent that. I believe that when we consider the evolving landscape in tech, we also need to think about the changing landscape of tech education. Most of us will end up using AI in our workflow, either out of necessity or because our team mandates it. That’s why I also think that AI coding assistants actually have the ability to help everyone grow in ways they couldn’t before.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Comparing 5 AI Coding Assistants: Which One’s Right for You?</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/Comparing-AI-Coding-Assistants" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Comparing 5 AI Coding Assistants: Which One's Right for You?" />
      <published>2025-06-24T00:00:00-04:00</published>
      <updated>2025-06-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/Comparing%20AI%20Coding%20Assistants</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Comparing-AI-Coding-Assistants">&lt;p&gt;A couple of days ago, I saw &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/jeromehardaway_microsoft-ceo-admits-that-ai-is-generating-activity-7340817881154134016-Ld9Q&quot;&gt;Jerome Hardaway’s LinkedIn post&lt;/a&gt;, and it really resonated with me. I like the idea of thinking of AI coding tools as “really great intern[s]. Fast, helpful, capable in the right hands – but still needs supervision, clear direction, and someone to clean up afterward.” There are a couple of projects that I’m working on this summer: the author site that I share with my brothers that uses Astro, a new project I’m launching for &lt;a href=&quot;https://oss-communities.netlify.app/&quot;&gt;osscommunities.com&lt;/a&gt;. This seems like the perfect opportunity to find the right tool that’s worth adding tool to my workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/ah6h6875jlzj6p5oknx4.png&quot; alt=&quot;Jerome Hardaway's full post&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-ai-assistant-philosophy&quot;&gt;My AI Assistant Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve always been a proponent of using AI just like any other tool in your toolbox. It’s there to help you level up, work more effectively, and move faster. If I were a carpenter who was too afraid or skeptical to try a hammer, I wouldn’t be as effective as other carpenters. And honestly, as a mom of four, I’ve been looking for ways to be more efficient for years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we all know, your coding assistant is only as good as you guide it to be. You have to make sure to correct it when it hallucinates, to double-check its work, to help it understand what you actually need. For me, it’s all about finding the best partner for the work I’m doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ai-assistant-tools--their-promises&quot;&gt;AI Assistant Tools &amp;amp; Their Promises&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose these five AI coding assistants based on different approaches to the same problem: Continue.dev for its open source flexibility and developer-first philosophy, Cursor for its AI-native editor approach, GitHub Copilot as the established market leader, Tabnine for its enterprise angle, and Windsurf as the rebranded dark horse. In my opinion, these represent the current landscape of AI code completion tools, from open source flexibility to enterprise privacy to AI-first design philosophies. Here’s a little more on each:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-continuedev&quot;&gt;1. &lt;a href=&quot;https://continue.dev/&quot;&gt;Continue.dev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Their Promise&lt;/em&gt;:  Amplify developers, don’t replace them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My Expectation&lt;/em&gt;:  I think Continue.dev’s chat, autocomplete, edit, and agent modes in one tool sounds interesting and comprehensive. I’m hoping this flexibility translates to better suggestions for my workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-github-copilot&quot;&gt;2. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/features/copilot/&quot;&gt;GitHub CoPilot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Their Promise&lt;/em&gt;:  AI that builds with you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My Expectation&lt;/em&gt;:  I’ve used CoPilot before, so this is the obvious choice since I already have experience with it. But I’m really curious to compare it to other tools out there to see how it stacks up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-cursor&quot;&gt;3. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cursor.com&quot;&gt;Cursor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Their Promise&lt;/em&gt;:  Cursor is a powerful AI-first code editor that enhances your development workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My Expectation&lt;/em&gt;:  The real test for me is whether building the editor around AI from day one actually feels different than VS Code with AI-extensions and whether or not the experience feels disjointed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-tabnine&quot;&gt;4. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tabnine.com/&quot;&gt;Tabnine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Their Promise&lt;/em&gt;:  Tabnine claims that it is the world’s most contextually aware AI software development platform, helping mature engineering teams speed up and simplify
their entire development process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My Expectation&lt;/em&gt;:  They seem to be targeting enterprise developers, but I’m curious if their focus on “mature engineering teams” translates to better suggestions for solo projects like mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-windsurf&quot;&gt;5. &lt;a href=&quot;https://windsurf.com/about&quot;&gt;Windsurf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Their Promise&lt;/em&gt;:  Windsurf is a next-generation AI IDE built to keep you in the flow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My Expectation&lt;/em&gt;: The “dream bigger” messaging is heavy on inspiration, but there’s not a lot of specifics. I want to see how well that translates to the user experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-next&quot;&gt;What’s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not looking for the tool that writes the most code for me.  I’m looking for the best AI coding assistant that makes me a better developer while helping me ship faster. The goal isn’t just to find another autocomplete tool. My goal is to discover which AI code assistant deserves a permanent spot in my development workflow. Whether that ends up being Continue.dev’s customizable approach, Cursor’s seamless integration, or one of the other contenders, I’ll share what I’ve learned in the coming weeks. Stay tuned for the full AI coding assistant comparison and see which tool actually lives up to the productivity promises.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      
        <summary type="html">A couple of days ago, I saw Jerome Hardaway’s LinkedIn post, and it really resonated with me. I like the idea of thinking of AI coding tools as “really great intern[s]. Fast, helpful, capable in the right hands – but still needs supervision, clear direction, and someone to clean up afterward.” There are a couple of projects that I’m working on this summer: the author site that I share with my brothers that uses Astro, a new project I’m launching for osscommunities.com. This seems like the perfect opportunity to find the right tool that’s worth adding tool to my workflow.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Test Drive Before You Buy: Your Guide to AI Code Assistant Trials in 2025</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/Guide-to-AI-Coding-Assistant-Trials" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Test Drive Before You Buy: Your Guide to AI Code Assistant Trials in 2025" />
      <published>2025-06-23T00:00:00-04:00</published>
      <updated>2025-06-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/Guide%20to%20AI%20Coding%20Assistant%20Trials</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Guide-to-AI-Coding-Assistant-Trials">&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://bekahhw.com/Taking-Time-to-Breathe-A-New-Chapter-Begins&quot;&gt;my last post&lt;/a&gt;, I talked about spending time this summer looking at different AI tools. I want to get hands-on, figure out what I want to integrate into my workflow. But before I spend time (and money) testing things out, I wanted to start with the free/trial periods. So you’re starting at the beginning of this journey with me. The question that I started with is: Which AI code assistants will actually let me take them for a proper test drive? In this post, I’ll share what I found across five top AI Coding Assistants—Continue, Windsurf, Cursor, GitHub Copilot, and Tabnine—and what I’m interested in learning as I put them to the test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-trial-landscape-whats-actually-available-with-ai-assistants&quot;&gt;The Trial Landscape: What’s Actually Available with AI Assistants&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After digging through pricing pages, here’s what you can try without putting in your credit card:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://continue.dev/&quot;&gt;Continue.dev&lt;/a&gt; is one of the most flexible and accessible AI Coding Assistants out there.  It’s open source, which means you can literally use it forever for free if you just bring your own API keys, and it supports any model you choose, including Claude 4 Sonnet, 4o, llama3.1 8b. Continue’s IDE extension has gained a lot of recent attention (20K+ GitHub stars), and integrates into tools that you might already use (VS Code and JetBrains). You can also create public assistants and invite your entire team.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://windsurf.com/&quot;&gt;Windsurf&lt;/a&gt; surprised me here. Their free tier includes 25 prompt credits per month, all premium models, unlimited Fast Tab completions, and even a 2-week Pro trial to test the advanced features. Built by the Codeium team, it’s essentially giving you a full-featured AI IDE for nothing. The supercomplete feature claims to understand your entire workspace to give intelligent suggestions across files.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;tabnine.com&quot;&gt;Tabnine&lt;/a&gt; offers a “Dev Preview” that’s completely free for qualified users, giving you AI code completions for current line and multiple lines, plus AI-powered chat. There’s also a paid Dev plan at $9/month with more advanced features. The Dev plan includes their foundational AI agents that can autonomously generate code, tests, docs, and fixes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;cursor.com&quot;&gt;Cursor&lt;/a&gt; gives you a Pro two-week trial as part of their free Hobby plan, plus 2,000 completions to play with. After that, their Pro plan is $20/month. It’s a significant jump but with unlimited agent requests and tab completions, two weeks is enough time to test their agent mode on a real project and see if the autonomous coding capabilities live up to the hype.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/features/copilot&quot;&gt;GitHub Copilot&lt;/a&gt; offers a solid 30-day free trial on their Pro plan before charging $10/month. Thirty days is actually enough time to see if it clicks with your workflow or just generates more bugs than it fixes. Since it’s deeply integrated in the GitHub ecosystem, you’ll be able to see how well it understands project context.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-to-actually-test-during-your-trial&quot;&gt;What to Actually Test During Your Trial&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to avoid some of the common problems I hear developers talk about when they sign up for AI Coding Assistants. I want to do more than test drive a car and park it in a lot. Here’s the approach I’m trying to take:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-real-world-gauntlet&quot;&gt;The Real-World Gauntlet&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Test it on your actual codebase.&lt;/strong&gt; I have some existing projects that I’ve created over the years. My blog is a Jekyll site that I have done only enough updating to keep things running over the past couple of years. It definitely has some “why did past me write this” code in the codebase. I want to make sure that AI can handle past me. (I’m actually interested in creating a Continue assistant to help update my Jekyll site.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Try it on unfamiliar territory.&lt;/strong&gt; I need my AI Coding Assistant to be a force multiplier. When I’m working in my strengths, it doesn’t take me as long. But when I use it with code that I’m not super familiar with, I need it to be good. I don’t want it to help me write bad code faster. Test both scenarios. I have a new project I’ve been wanting to work on, and this seems like a good use case.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See how it handles context.&lt;/strong&gt; Can it understand your team’s coding conventions? Does it remember what you were working on five files ago? Context awareness separates the good from the great. This is not applicable for what I’m working on right now, but this is super important if you’re working with a team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-stress-test&quot;&gt;The Stress Test&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should try to push these tools to their breaking point. (Semi-related, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/AIMemory/comments/1lg6axl/so_our_smartest_llms_kind_of_give_up_when_we_need/&quot;&gt;I posted about LLMs giving up when we need them the most. Feel free to add to the conversation!&lt;/a&gt; Ask them to refactor a complex function. Have them write tests for edge cases you know are problematic. See if they can debug that one weird issue that’s been haunting your team for weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal is to find the AI Assistant that fails gracefully and teaches you something useful in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-hidden-costs&quot;&gt;The Hidden Costs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where the trial period becomes really important. Most AI assistants have usage-based pricing that can get out of hand really quick. You can eat through your budget if you’re not careful. During your trial, pay attention to those usage meters since they’re previewing your future bills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start with the free tiers. Continue if you want maximum control, Windsurf if you want simplicity, Tabnine if you just want better autocomplete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use the trial period to answer this question: Does this tool make you a better developer, or just a faster typist? At the end of the day, you’re responsible for all production code you ship. If you don’t understand your code, AI is a temporary solution to your problem, and that approach can end badly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s your homework (and we can do it together, just comment which one you’re testing below!):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pick one tool from the list above&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set it up on your current project&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use it for a week on real work (not tutorials)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask yourself: “Am I learning, or just copying?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan on starting with Continue and working my way through the list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The right AI assistant will enhance and amplify your skills, not replace them.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      
        <summary type="html">In my last post, I talked about spending time this summer looking at different AI tools. I want to get hands-on, figure out what I want to integrate into my workflow. But before I spend time (and money) testing things out, I wanted to start with the free/trial periods. So you’re starting at the beginning of this journey with me. The question that I started with is: Which AI code assistants will actually let me take them for a proper test drive? In this post, I’ll share what I found across five top AI Coding Assistants—Continue, Windsurf, Cursor, GitHub Copilot, and Tabnine—and what I’m interested in learning as I put them to the test.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Taking Time to Breathe: A New Chapter Begins</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/Taking-Time-to-Breathe-A-New-Chapter-Begins" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Taking Time to Breathe: A New Chapter Begins" />
      <published>2025-06-10T00:00:00-04:00</published>
      <updated>2025-06-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/Taking%20Time%20to%20Breathe:%20A%20New%20Chapter%20Begins</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Taking-Time-to-Breathe-A-New-Chapter-Begins">&lt;p&gt;As of June 1st, I’m no longer with the Linux Foundation. While I’ll share more details about this transition in a future post, I wanted to take a moment to reflect on what comes next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going through an acquisition is intense, especially when you’re leaving what was truly your favorite job. The experience has been both professionally enriching and personally challenging, and I’ve realized how important it is to give yourself permission to pause and process major changes rather than immediately jumping into the next thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s exactly what I’m doing this summer: taking a pragmatic approach to my career and family life. I’m giving myself time to breathe, to explore opportunities I didn’t have bandwidth for before, and to be intentional about my next steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-coming-this-summer&quot;&gt;What’s Coming This Summer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My primary focus for the coming months will be diving deep into AI tools and their practical applications. I’ve been wanting to explore more AI tools, but I haven’t had the time to until now. As someone who’s spent considerable time thinking about content strategy and audience development, I’m fascinated by how AI is reshaping not just what we create, but how we create it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can expect a lot of AI-related content from me in the weeks ahead. I don’t have an exact plan mapped out, so it might be everything from tool reviews and practical use cases to my thoughts on how these technologies are changing the content landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;looking-forward&quot;&gt;Looking Forward&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll have more to share about my long-term plans soon, but for now, I’m embracing this period of exploration. Thanks for following along on this journey. The next few months should be interesting.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      
        <summary type="html">As of June 1st, I’m no longer with the Linux Foundation. While I’ll share more details about this transition in a future post, I wanted to take a moment to reflect on what comes next.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Beyond Stars and Forks: Why Open Source Needs Better Collaboration Metrics</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/Beyond-Stars-and-Forks" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Beyond Stars and Forks: Why Open Source Needs Better Collaboration Metrics" />
      <published>2025-05-29T00:00:00-04:00</published>
      <updated>2025-05-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/Beyond-Stars-and-Forks</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Beyond-Stars-and-Forks">&lt;p&gt;When we were working on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://opensauced.pizza/learn/intro-to-oss&quot;&gt;Intro to Open Source&lt;/a&gt; course, one of the biggest painpoints we noted with new contributors was the frustration they felt when their PRs weren’t merged in in what they felt was a reasonable amount of time. They had done their research, found an issue, gotten assigned, and then…nothing. No feedback. No merge. Just silence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a familiar story. I’ve had contributors tell me, “My PR has been sitting there for two weeks and I haven’t heard a thing.” And I get it. There are so many reasons this happens, including burnout, abandoned projects, the lottery factor, and it’s rarely about bad intentions. That’s why I always tell contributors to join the community before contributing. It helps you understand the project’s rhythms, how to communicate with maintainers, and whether it’s a space that supports new members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve read anything I’ve written in the last five years, you know I care deeply about the open source community. But how we have traditionally evaluated projects and metrics doesn’t give enough insight into the most meaningful parts. A lot of times, these metrics—stars, forks, downloads, and DORA metrics—miss the most important part of the story: how people collaborate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-different-approach-to-open-source-metrics&quot;&gt;A Different Approach to Open Source Metrics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/saucedopen/status/1900339926832734635&quot;&gt;OpenSauced shut down&lt;/a&gt;, I’ve been exploring different options for understanding the collaboration problem. 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://collab.dev/&quot;&gt;Collab.dev&lt;/a&gt; isn’t a replacement for OpenSauced, but it’s telling a different (and important) part of the story and capturing how people collaborate. It surfaces the human patterns behind the code, like review responsiveness, contributor distribution, and merge dynamics. Industry-accepted metrics like DORA are valuable for understanding software delivery performance, but not so much in the human department. They can tell you how fast code gets deployed, but not whether contributors feel supported, welcomed, or left in the dark. Open source is as much about relationships as releases, and we need metrics that reflect that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-collaboration-visibility-gap&quot;&gt;The Collaboration Visibility Gap&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem isn’t just that our current metrics are incomplete. Vanity metrics have been touted as meaningful indications of the project’s health, and, to be direct, they’re just not that important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we consider the challenges maintainers face every day, we’ll see that it’s often difficult to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identify which contributors are most likely to become long-term participants.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pinpoint exactly where the review process stalls or breaks down.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Understand if the community environment genuinely feels welcoming to newcomers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Distinguish between sustainable growth and problematic scaling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The path isn’t clearer for potential contributors either. They often struggle to determine:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whether the project actively reviews and merges community contributions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How long it typically takes for contributions to be reviewed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Which maintainers are most responsive in the contributor’s area of interest.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If there’s a healthy balance between contributions from the core team and the wider community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many of us, we have to make a decision about where to invest our time and energy. It can be a real letdown if we’ve invested time and realized we made the wrong decision, coming out of it with nothing to really show for the work we’ve done. For instance, I wanted to learn more about &lt;a href=&quot;https://dub.sh/cognee&quot;&gt;cognee&lt;/a&gt;, an AI Memory management framework, recently, so I created a &lt;a href=&quot;https://dub.sh/cognee-collab&quot;&gt;collab.dev cognee page&lt;/a&gt; to learn more about the collaboration happening. When you first look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://dub.sh/cognee-gh&quot;&gt;cognee on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, it looks like a growing open source project with a decent star count, active issues, and regular commits. But looking at Collab.dev’s dashboard, I get a richer story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-story-cognees-data-tells-through-collabdev&quot;&gt;The Story Cognee’s Data Tells through Collab.dev&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;contributor-distribution&quot;&gt;Contributor Distribution&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we think about good contributor distribution in an open source project, that usually means responsibilities, activity, and knowledge aren’t tied to a few people. Distribution allows for decreased burnout, project resilience, and creates a more welcoming environment. What we see with cognee is a genuinely balanced project. With 51% of contributions coming from the core team and 49% from the community, cognee has built real community ownership without abandoning maintainer responsibility, and we can make a connection with a collaborative environment and higher motivation to support the project from the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/neq300a2e09po9wobend.png&quot; alt=&quot;Contributor distribution graph&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pr-lifecycle-metrics&quot;&gt;PR Lifecycle Metrics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It continues to get interesting. The review funnel shows that 88% of PRs receive reviews and 85.2% get approved. That approval rate tells a story about quality control and contributor experience. It suggests that either the project has excellent contribution guidelines that help people submit good PRs, or the maintainers are actively helping contributors improve their work rather than just rejecting it. On top of this, there’s a quick turnaround with a median response time of 1.9 hours and 42% of reviews happening within an hour. They’re not waiting three weeks for a review. The maintainers are cultivating a positive contributor experience through their responsiveness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/iv2x52ng29yysttfl1e9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;cognee lifecycle metrics&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-this-tells-us-about-the-human-story&quot;&gt;What this tells us about the Human Story&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a maintainer, I’ve been in the situation where I don’t have the capacity to immediately respond to contributors, and sometimes they even have to wait weeks for my response. Obviously, this isn’t ideal. Usually, what happens is that the person has moved on, they may not respond at all, or they’re less likely to contribute again. What we see from cognee’s numbers is that they don’t have that same problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When someone contributes to cognee, they aren’t left wondering whether or not their efforts are valued. They get fast enough feedback to stay engaged and iterate quickly. Their turnaround time for a review (1.6hrs) is a good way to encourage repeat contributors. Additionally, with a median merge time of 19.5 hours signals to contributors that their work has real and immediate impact. And they’re able to see their contributions available to users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-collaboration-pattern&quot;&gt;The Collaboration Pattern&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you look at these metrics together, they’re telling a story of intentional collaboration design, a story that thinks about the contributor and maintainer experience. They’ve created systems and habits that make collaboration feel responsive and worthwhile. What’s telling about this data is also what’s &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; happening. We don’t see any pile-ups of unreviewed PRs. There are no huge gaps between approval and merge. There are no signs of contributor frustration or maintainer overwhelm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This collaboration story matters, not just to show that cognee looks like a good place to contribute, but because this can become a replicable story. Other projects can learn how to make collaboration feel good for the contributors involved. We can look at the data and the project and better understand what systems and practices created these patterns, and we can reach out to maintainers of projects we admire to ask: How do you build review workflows that are both thorough and fast? How do you maintain quality while staying responsive to community contributions?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collaboration quality doesn’t have to be something we guess at. We can learn more through the data and find projects that have the capacity to take contributions from community members. (And if you’re interested, collab.dev also has a nifty comparison tool. You can check out my &lt;a href=&quot;https://dub.sh/cognee-mem0&quot;&gt;mem0 v. cognee comparison&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-bigger-picture-measuring-what-matters&quot;&gt;The Bigger Picture: Measuring What Matters&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re in a stage of open source where complex human dynamics determine whether open source projects succeed or fail. Collaboration metrics can help lead to better outcomes. When we measure collaboration effectively, we can:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reduce contributor burnout by identifying overwhelmed maintainers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Increase successful first contributions by directing early contributors to responsive projects&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build more sustainable projects by understanding what healthy collaboration looks like&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create feedback loops that help projects improve their community practices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In open source, we’ve proven that collaborative development can create incredible value, but we can’t ignore the sustainability challenges, maintainer burnout, and the difficulty of scaling human collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Better visibility into collaboration patterns can help us to understand the future health of open source. We need tools that help us understand not just what code exists, but how effectively people work together to create and maintain it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open source has always been about people working together. Our metrics should reflect that meaningful work.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      
        <summary type="html">When we were working on the Intro to Open Source course, one of the biggest painpoints we noted with new contributors was the frustration they felt when their PRs weren’t merged in in what they felt was a reasonable amount of time. They had done their research, found an issue, gotten assigned, and then…nothing. No feedback. No merge. Just silence.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Breaking Bottlenecks: How Organizations Build Systems of Balanced Reciprocity</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/reciprocity-systems" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Breaking Bottlenecks: How Organizations Build Systems of Balanced Reciprocity" />
      <published>2025-05-19T00:00:00-04:00</published>
      <updated>2025-05-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/reciprocity-systems</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reciprocity-systems">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In this third post of my series on giving and taking, we explore how to design systems that prevent burnout, distribute contributions, and transform individual reciprocity intelligence into organizational strength.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2020, when I lost my first developer job due to the pandemic, I was taking every interview I could get. One of them happened to be for a DevOps role at a well-known company. I didn’t even know what DevOps was at the time, but the hiring manager had reached out and asked me to interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first interview went well, and she invited me back for a second. The catch was that the second interview would only happen after I read &lt;em&gt;The Unicorn Project&lt;/em&gt; by Gene Kim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Unicorn Project&lt;/em&gt; follows Maxine, a senior developer reassigned to a troubled initiative called the Phoenix Project. Through Maxine’s journey, we see how siloed knowledge, approval bottlenecks, and rigid processes destroy productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Five years later, as I think about reciprocity, I started thinking about this book again. It wasn’t just about technical problems. It was also about reciprocity. When knowledge, permissions, or capabilities concentrate in one person, that person becomes a constraint.
Here’s the paradox: The most generous givers often become the biggest bottlenecks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I’ve been a bottleneck as the founder of the tech community, &lt;a href=&quot;https://virtualcoffee.io/&quot;&gt;Virtual Coffee&lt;/a&gt;. I was the one who knew how everything worked. I was the one who could answer questions. I was the one everyone came to when they needed help.
My desire to make sure I could take care of everyone’s needs created a system-wide constraint, and it was holding back the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Research confirms this: teams with concentrated expertise are less resilient and adaptive than those with distributed knowledge systems. If your team depends on a few generous people to keep everything running, you’re building risk. The good news is that you can turn individual reciprocity into a scalable system for trust, flow, and contribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;from-diminisher-to-multiplier&quot;&gt;From Diminisher to Multiplier&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before looking at specific design principles, we need to shift our mental model. In &lt;em&gt;Multipliers: How the Best Leaders Make Everyone Smarter&lt;/em&gt;, Liz Wiseman contrasts two leadership approaches:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;diminishers-who-drain-capability&quot;&gt;Diminishers (who drain capability):&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hoard knowledge and decision-making&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Solve problems for others&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create dependency through “helping”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Become bottlenecks despite good intentions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;multipliers-who-amplify-capability&quot;&gt;Multipliers (who amplify capability):&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Distribute knowledge and authority&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create challenges that build capability&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Establish systems that enable independence&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove themselves as bottlenecks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might be thinking, “Wow, I know some really well-intentioned givers who fall into the category of diminisher.” Or maybe you’re that well-intentioned giver. When you solve problems for others instead of building their capability, you’re not giving sustainably. You’re creating an unhealthy reciprocity system where people remain dependent on your giving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;building-trust-through-multiplier-principles&quot;&gt;Building Trust Through Multiplier Principles&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the multiplier mindset as our foundation, we can see how sustainable reciprocity depends on trust. In &lt;em&gt;The Infinite Game&lt;/em&gt;, Simon Sinek emphasizes that trusting teams are a hallmark of enduring organizations. But trust is something that needs to be developed through measurable signals of care, consistency, and safety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In reciprocity systems, that means not just measuring outcomes, but tracking patterns of help-giving, shared responsibility, and psychological safety. If your contributors know that support flows in multiple directions and that they won’t be punished for asking questions, they’re more likely to give back in ways that strengthen the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trust becomes the infrastructure for reciprocity. Without it, your systems fall into suspicion, gatekeeping, and imbalance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With trust and this multiplier mindset as our foundation, let’s explore five design principles for balanced reciprocity systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;five-design-principles-for-balanced-reciprocity&quot;&gt;Five Design Principles for Balanced Reciprocity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;design-principle-1-documentation-as-scaled-giving&quot;&gt;Design Principle #1: Documentation as Scaled Giving&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a lot of givers, documentation can be a way to continue giving without requiring the emotional energy and time of 1:1 mentorship. This realization made a huge impact on empowering volunteers to take leadership roles at Virtual Coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Documentation transforms individual expertise into organizational capability. Amazon’s documentation culture ensures that knowledge is accessible and decisions are transparent. Their “six-pager” narratives and strict documentation protocols mean that information doesn’t bottleneck with individuals, and that teammates are thinking deeply about the information that’s being presented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;documentation-culture-implementation&quot;&gt;Documentation Culture Implementation:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create decision logs that explain not just what was decided, but why&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Record short video walkthroughs of common processes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Establish a “document first, then assist” culture where documentation is updated before individual help is given&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build knowledge bases with practical how-to guides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;design-principle-2-progressive-responsibility-frameworks&quot;&gt;Design Principle #2: Progressive Responsibility Frameworks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Unicorn Project&lt;/em&gt; describes how Maxine creates a “dojo” environment where people learn by doing, gradually taking on more responsibility. Progressive responsibility creates clear pathways from dependence to contribution. Google’s “Googler to Googler” and “Globetrotters” programs rotate employees through different teams, giving them the opportunity to learn new skills and understand perspectives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Progressive responsibility allows for knowledge transfer at a manageable pace, and creates a culture of continuous learning and adaptability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Progressive responsibility frameworks create clear pathways from dependence to contribution:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supported Phase&lt;/strong&gt; - High guidance, low autonomy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collaborative Phase&lt;/strong&gt; - Shared responsibility&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Independent Phase&lt;/strong&gt; - Minimal guidance, high autonomy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contributory Phase&lt;/strong&gt; - Becoming a giver within the system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a lot of ways, good open source contributor ladders do the same thing. At OpenSauced, one of our indicators of success was contributors moving through our repos, from their first contribution in our Learn track to working on our app. As they progressed, they learned more about our projects, our approach to open source, and our codebase, and, as a result, were more likely to support or mentor new contributors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;implementation-ideas&quot;&gt;Implementation Ideas:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create explicit onboarding levels with clear graduation criteria&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Establish “participation ladders” showing pathways to greater responsibility&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Design contribution opportunities with varying levels of commitment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build “help tokens” systems where people earn the right to ask for help by helping others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;design-principle-3-flow-optimized-boundaries&quot;&gt;Design Principle #3: Flow-Optimized Boundaries&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Constant interruptions destroy flow and can lead to burnout. Spotify’s model of autonomous squads, organized into tribes and guilds, helps teams set boundaries while still cross-pollinating knowledge. Teams choose their own frameworks and manage their own workflows, reducing unnecessary interruptions and approval bottlenecks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;flow-optimized-boundaries-implementation-ideas&quot;&gt;Flow-optimized Boundaries Implementation Ideas:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Establish “office hours” for help-giving rather than allowing constant interruption&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create asynchronous help systems (like dedicated Slack channels)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Implement “focus time” protocols where helping is intentionally paused&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build request queues rather than allowing direct interruptions
&lt;em&gt;The Unicorn Project&lt;/em&gt;’s second ideal—Focus, Flow, and Joy—applies directly to reciprocity systems. Constant interruptions to help others destroy flow, creating resentment even among the most generous givers. Creating flow-optimized boundaries guards against this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;design-principle-4-expertise-distribution-systems&quot;&gt;Design Principle #4: Expertise Distribution Systems&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expertise needs to be distributed, not centralized, to maximize impact. Employee rotation programs at Google, General Electric, and the Mayo Clinic intentionally move people across roles and teams, making sure that no single person becomes a bottleneck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;expert-distribution-systems-implementation-ideas&quot;&gt;Expert Distribution Systems Implementation Ideas:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rotate responsibility for answering common questions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Implement peer learning sessions where everyone teaches something&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create expertise directories so people know who knows what
Establish skill-sharing programs where people exchange knowledge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;The Unicorn Project&lt;/em&gt;, the breakthrough comes when the team creates systems to share knowledge rather than centralizing it. When giving becomes part of the infrastructure rather than depending on specific individuals, reciprocity becomes sustainable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;design-principle-5-balancing-feedback-mechanisms&quot;&gt;Design Principle #5: Balancing Feedback Mechanisms&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without feedback loops, reciprocity systems drift toward imbalance. Regular retrospectives, community health surveys, and visualization of help patterns help organizations spot overburdened givers and chronic takers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;balancing-feedback-mechanisms-implementation-ideas&quot;&gt;Balancing Feedback Mechanisms Implementation Ideas:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Conduct regular “reciprocity retrospectives” examining giving and taking patterns&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create visualization tools showing help requests and contributions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Implement periodic capacity check-ins to identify overburdened givers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Design gentle interventions for chronic taking patterns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Balanced systems build trust through transparency. When contributors see that their feedback leads to visible changes, and that overburdened givers are protected, it signals that the organization is worthy of their continued investment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sinek’s perspective underscores this: “The true value of a leader is not measured by the work they do. A leader’s value is measured by the work they inspire others to do.” Feedback systems signal to your people: We see you. We’re listening. We’re building something together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;from-principles-to-practice-overcoming-common-challenges&quot;&gt;From Principles to Practice: Overcoming Common Challenges&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even with these five principles in place, organizations often encounter obstacles when transforming their reciprocity systems:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Knowledge that resists documentation:&lt;/strong&gt; Some expertise is difficult to capture in writing or videos. When Maxine left her previous team in &lt;em&gt;The Unicorn Project&lt;/em&gt;, they struggled because her understanding of the system lived mostly in her head.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The “this is how we’ve always done it” syndrome:&lt;/strong&gt; New systems often face resistance, especially from those who’ve benefited from the old ways of working.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Territorial thinking:&lt;/strong&gt;Teams and individuals sometimes protect their knowledge as a form of job security or status preservation.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;small-experiments-with-big-impact&quot;&gt;Small Experiments with Big Impact&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don’t have to overhaul your entire organization overnight. Consider starting with these manageable experiments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Document your most-asked question.&lt;/strong&gt; What’s the one thing people constantly interrupt you to learn? Create a guide, record a walkthrough, or build a decision tree.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Establish dedicated help hours.&lt;/strong&gt; Protect your focus time while still being available by setting clear boundaries for when you’re available to give assistance.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design one progressive challenge.&lt;/strong&gt; Identify someone who regularly asks for help, and create a graduated challenge that builds their capability instead of solving their problem.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Run a simple reciprocity retrospective.&lt;/strong&gt; In your next team meeting, discuss: “Where are we seeing bottlenecks? Who seems overwhelmed with requests? How can we distribute knowledge better?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These small shifts can create ripple effects throughout your organization’s reciprocity culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reciprocity-culture-is-designed&quot;&gt;Reciprocity Culture is Designed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Healthy reciprocity doesn’t happen by hoping the right people show up. It happens when organizations intentionally design feedback loops, distribute ownership, and normalize trust. That’s what I build,  whether it’s in open source, startups, or developer communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal isn’t equal giving at all times, but resilient systems that handle the natural ebb and flow of contribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Wiseman says, “The goal isn’t to be the smartest person in the room-it’s to make everyone in the room smarter.” The same is true for giving: build systems where giving and receiving flow naturally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organizations that design for reciprocity unlock scale. If you’re trying to build those systems—or recover from being the bottleneck—I’d love to hear how you’re approaching it.  How does your organization distribute knowledge and responsibility? What small experiment can you start this week?&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      
        <summary type="html">In this third post of my series on giving and taking, we explore how to design systems that prevent burnout, distribute contributions, and transform individual reciprocity intelligence into organizational strength.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Reciprocity Intelligence: A Core Skill for Modern Work</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/reciprocity-intelligence" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reciprocity Intelligence: A Core Skill for Modern Work" />
      <published>2025-04-15T00:00:00-04:00</published>
      <updated>2025-04-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/reciprocity-intelligence</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reciprocity-intelligence">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In this second post of my series on giving and taking, I explore why reciprocity intelligence—the ability to navigate giving and receiving effectively—isn’t just nice to have anymore. If you missed the first post, &lt;a href=&quot;https://bekahhw.com/company-culture-of-reciprocity&quot;&gt;start here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-dont-talk-aboutreciprocity-intelligence-but-we-should&quot;&gt;We Don’t Talk about…Reciprocity Intelligence (but we should)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve always been drawn to the idea that core skills like empathy, communication, and resilience aren’t fixed skills, but learnable ones. You also might know them as “intelligences”: emotional intelligence, cultural intelligence, and even digital intelligence. Basically, they shape how we understand and navigate relationships and environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there’s one form of intelligence I don’t hear people talking about even though it defines how we operate in teams and communities: reciprocity intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reciprocity intelligence is the ability to move skillfully between giving and receiving. It’s knowing when to offer help, when to ask for it, and how to manage the emotions that come with both. It’s recognizing that generosity is situational and not a permanent identity. You’re not always a “giver” or a “taker.” You shift based on your capacity, your context, and your needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news is that like any intelligence, reciprocity intelligence is something you can grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-research-behind-reciprocity-skills&quot;&gt;The Research Behind Reciprocity Skills&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although it’s not likely referred to as reciprocity intelligence, the concept is gaining attention in research that is focused on its underlying skills. For example, Grant and Dutton (2012) found that when people are encouraged to think about times they gave or received help, they’re more likely to keep that generosity going at work. Even small reflection prompts can lead to more giving and collaboration on teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last twenty years, we’ve seen gratitude journaling become wildly popular. It should be no surprise that the focus is often on giving or receiving, and it has been proven to boost your mood and strengthen your relationships. These studies aren’t directly about reciprocity, but they show how simple reflection can spark more positive social behavior and help reduce stress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the neuroscience angle, Harbaugh and his team (2007) used brain scans to show that giving to others lights up the brain’s reward centers. Generosity feels good. Voluntary giving seems to bring the biggest reward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this isn’t a single culture thing either. Cross-cultural research from Henrich et al. (2005) shows the idea of reciprocity shows up in cultures all over the world, and is practiced in many different ways. So what we can take away from this is that reciprocity is universal, but the actual skills to navigate it are shaped by culture and can be taught.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;seasons-of-giving-and-taking&quot;&gt;Seasons of Giving and Taking&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my experience with &lt;a href=&quot;https://virtualcoffee.io/&quot;&gt;Virtual Coffee&lt;/a&gt; over the past five years, I’ve moved through distinct phases of giving and receiving. When I founded the community, I was primarily in a giving season and spent a lot of time organizing, mentoring, and speaking to early career developers. But eventually, I started to recognize the signs of burnout. This was also an opportunity to become a matcher or taker. I had to accept help, to allow others to contribute, to recognize that if I did it all on my own, I was on a fast-track to helping no one. I had to find that balance. And I needed to understand what that balance meant for me and take that knowledge and understanding with me to everything I did so I didn’t face burnout doing the things I love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This recognition, that we all move through seasons where we may give more or receive more, is central to reciprocity intelligence. The skill development means that you should be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Recognize your current season without shame or guilt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Communicate your capacity transparently&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build a “reciprocity bank” through consistent giving when able&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Withdraw thoughtfully when needed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-hidden-costs-of-false-giving&quot;&gt;The Hidden Costs of False Giving&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe one of the most insidious challenges in workplace or community dynamics is what I call “false giving.” False giving is generosity theater. It looks like help, but it costs more than it contributes. And when it’s unchecked, it spreads by slowly draining the energy of the real contributors. Sometimes people “pass” as givers by volunteering. But when they deliver substandard work, it ultimately creates more work for others. What makes this particularly damaging is that it masquerades as contribution, offers support for the team/community, promises decreased workloads, etc. In reality, it takes value, time, and unplanned resources from your team. It becomes a virus that, if not addressed, can go deep into your veins and seriously damage your team’s health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Research on team dynamics and “social loafing” shows that when team members perceive others as not contributing, it can lead to frustration and resentment within the group (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ijip.in/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/18.01.375.20241202.pdf&quot;&gt;Social Loafing and Its Effects on the Workplace&lt;/a&gt;).Teams generally function better and show more mutual respect when members are honest about their limitations and boundaries (for reference, check out: &lt;a href=&quot;https://rework.withgoogle.com/en/guides/understanding-team-effectiveness&quot;&gt;Understand team
effectiveness&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vantagecircle.com/en/blog/team-dynamics/&quot;&gt;Team Dynamics: The Backbone of Effective Collaboration&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;have-the-hard-conversations&quot;&gt;Have the Hard Conversations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a huge proponent of having hard conversations when you need to, and this especially applies to team dynamics. In the first year of Virtual Coffee, we read &lt;em&gt;Radical Candor&lt;/em&gt;, and it opened my mind to understand the disservice you do when you don’t give people honest and candid feedback. The fact is, when someone consistently takes without investing, it burns people out and damages relationships, teams, and communities. I’ve witnessed firsthand how just one or two chronic takers can deplete an entire team’s motivation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reciprocity intelligence includes the ability to address imbalances directly. This is why it’s important to be able to give to others by having honest conversations about their impact. With this approach, you can better understand how to have that conversation in a way that makes clear what the boundaries of giving and taking are. Early conflict resolution can address giving and taking imbalances that create healthier team dynamics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;developing-your-reciprocity-intelligence&quot;&gt;Developing Your Reciprocity Intelligence&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mentioned earlier that you can grow in reciprocity intelligence. That’s not helpful unless you know how. Based on both research and experience, here are some practical steps I think you can use to develop your reciprocity intelligence:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;practice-reciprocity-awareness&quot;&gt;Practice Reciprocity Awareness&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Track your giving and taking behaviors across different relationships&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Notice which interactions energize versus deplete you&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identify your “giving strengths” (the types of contribution that come naturally).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, you might like taking someone a meal after they’ve had a child, but feel depleted when you have to organize three weeks’ worth of meals for them. Or maybe you enjoy pair programming with a junior developer, but creating a mentorship plan for junior developers felt exhausting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being aware can help you restructure your giving to focus on your strengths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;build-recovery-into-giving&quot;&gt;Build Recovery into Giving&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set boundaries around your giving to prevent burnout&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Schedule recovery time after intensive giving periods&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Develop rituals that help you recharge your “giving battery”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might find that you need a 2-for-1 giving rule, where for every two giving activities you might need a recovery activity (reading, taking a walk, an evening without community responsibilities, etc.). Identify necessary boundaries to prevent burnout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;learn-to-receive-gracefully&quot;&gt;Learn to Receive Gracefully&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Practice accepting help without feeling diminished&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Express specific appreciation for support&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Recognize that allowing others to give benefits them too&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you need to practice saying “thank you,” instead of “I got this.” It’s also worth noting that when you allow others to help you, they might find joy in helping. You’re empowering them to be a giver in a way that energizes them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;communicate-your-capacity&quot;&gt;Communicate Your Capacity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be transparent about your current giving capacity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Signal shifting capacity before reaching burnout&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Frame limitations as temporary seasons rather than permanent states&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be specific about what you can and cannot handle so people don’t have to guess. You don’t have to offer explanations, but you do have to share that you need help.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A low-level way to communicate capacity is to implement a simple traffic light system: green means I have capacity to help, yellow means I’m at my limit but can handle quick questions or issues, and red means I need to focus on existing commitments or I’m at capacity. Visual cues help set expectations without requiring constant explanations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;invest-in-reciprocity-education&quot;&gt;Invest in Reciprocity Education&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide team training on healthy giving and receiving (this also helps to set expectations)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Discuss reciprocity norms explicitly in your organization&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Recognize and celebrate balanced contributors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anecdotally, I’ve seen givers doing the majority of giving year after year after year until they burnout in communities, as volunteers, on teams, and really any aspect of life. If you’re running a team, think about offering onboarding about reciprocity patterns or having quarterly retros that include a reciprocity patterns that allow for better knowledge sharing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you cultivate reciprocity intelligence experience, you can lower burnout rates, create a more equitable distribution of effort, allow for stronger team cohesion, encourage greater innovation through psychological safety, and see a higher retention rate of top talent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-personal-reflection&quot;&gt;A Personal Reflection&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be hard as a giver to not give, especially if you’re used to giving to others who normally reciprocate. You want to believe everyone will be willing to give back, to send ripples out into the world, but that’s not always the case. The most sustainable communities and teams are those where reciprocity intelligence is valued as a core skill and where members understand the rhythm of giving and receiving that sustains us all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the next post in this series, we’ll explore how to design systems and processes that naturally encourage balanced reciprocity rather than enabling chronic taking or burning out your most generous team or community members.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      
        <summary type="html">In this second post of my series on giving and taking, I explore why reciprocity intelligence—the ability to navigate giving and receiving effectively—isn’t just nice to have anymore. If you missed the first post, start here.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">The Giving-Resilience Balance: Beyond Givers and Takers</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/company-culture-of-reciprocity" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Giving-Resilience Balance: Beyond Givers and Takers" />
      <published>2025-04-08T00:00:00-04:00</published>
      <updated>2025-04-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/company-culture-of-reciprocity</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/company-culture-of-reciprocity">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In today’s workplace, we need both a culture of contribution and the personal strength to thrive independently.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, I read Adam Grant’s “Give and Take.” His framework of givers, takers, and matchers gave really great insight into professional and community interactions. As I reflected on my own experiences, I thought that we might be creating systems that unintentionally cultivate dependency rather than balanced reciprocity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grant’s research shows that givers often succeed in the long run, but only when they give strategically. What does a balanced approach looks like, then?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;beyond-binary-thinking&quot;&gt;Beyond Binary Thinking&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conversation around giving and taking often falls into an oversimplified binary: selfless contributors versus selfish extractors. Although this might be helpful in understanding, we all know that reality is more complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we examine the complexity, some of the things we need to consider are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Context&lt;/strong&gt; - When is giving appropriate versus when is self-reliance necessary?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skill development&lt;/strong&gt; - How do we build both generosity and resilience simultaneously?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Systems design&lt;/strong&gt; - How can organizations encourage healthy giving without creating dependency?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-support-resilience-matrix&quot;&gt;The Support-Resilience Matrix&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We often think about professional development along two axes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Low Resilience&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;High Resilience&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Low Support&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Struggle Zone&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Rugged Individualism&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High Support&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Dependency Zone&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Thriving Zone&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best results happen in the “Thriving Zone,” where people have support when they need it and the confidence to stand on their own when they don’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cultivating-balanced-contributors&quot;&gt;Cultivating Balanced Contributors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To develop professionals or community members who thrive in this balanced space, we need approaches that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teach effective help-seeking&lt;/strong&gt; - The ability to ask for appropriate support rather than expecting or demanding it. For example, a junior developer should learn to ask targeted questions &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; attempting a solution, instead of waiting passively, demanding immediate answers, or asking general questions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why it matters&lt;/em&gt;: This builds confidence, respect among peers, and a culture of learning and independence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Build progressive challenges&lt;/strong&gt; - Gradually decreasing direct support as competence grows. For example, a new team member may start with detailed tickets and then gradually move to leading small features or mentoring others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why it matters&lt;/em&gt;: Team members can grow without being overwhelmed, with support being scaled back as skills improve. That also allows the support team to budget their time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recognize strategic giving&lt;/strong&gt; - Understanding when and how to contribute without burning out. This is especially useful in situations where more senior team members also act as mentors. For example, a senior engineer may avoid burnout by blocking out time weekly for mentorship and not compromising by going over or outside that time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why it matters&lt;/em&gt;: Contributions are more likely to be sustainable and impactful. This is key to avoid exhaustion or resentment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Develop reciprocity intelligence&lt;/strong&gt; - The awareness of give-take dynamics and how to navigate them strategically.  For example, if a team member notices they’ve been receiving more help than giving, they could initiate a peer support circle to balance the dynamic or look at new team/community members and offer to support them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why it matters&lt;/em&gt;: Being aware of giving and receiving patterns helps build trust, equity, and stronger team relationships over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my experience building community and being on teams, the most impactful contributors weren’t necessarily “natural givers.” What set them apart was a thoughtful, strategic approach to contribution. They navigated the balance between support and self-reliance with intention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reimagining-professional-development&quot;&gt;Reimagining Professional Development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a balanced perspective, we need to reimagine how we approach professional development:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mentorship programs&lt;/strong&gt; should gradually transition from high-support to high-autonomy. This requires a deliberate development of mentorship, expectation setting, and growth monitoring. The goal should be to equip mentees to eventually lead, support others, and navigate challenges on their own.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback systems&lt;/strong&gt; that acknowledge contribution while encouraging independence. For example, instead of only praising helpfulness, celebrate moments when someone solved a complex issue independently or helped others develop their own solutions. This helps shift the focus from being the hero to building group resilience and problem-solving abilities.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team structures&lt;/strong&gt; that rotate giving and receiving roles. No one should always be the helper or the one receiving support. When everyone has the opportunity to contribute and to learn, we encourage empathy, shared responsibility, and prevent burnout or stagnation. It’s worth noting that everyone has different strengths, so considering each person’s individual strengths may impact how you rotate roles or what roles people take on.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cultural norms&lt;/strong&gt; that celebrate both generosity and self-reliance. Leaders set the tone for the whole company, which means when they model healthy boundaries, thoughtful help-seeking, and strategic support, it gives permission for others to do the same. This top-down modeling is necessary for making balance a norm rather than an exception.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;moving-forward&quot;&gt;Moving Forward&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neither pure self-reliance nor complete dependency serves us well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By cultivating both giving cultures and personal resilience, we create the conditions for sustainable success—for individuals, teams, and organizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the first in a series exploring the balance between support and resilience in modern professional environments. Next week, I’ll dive deeper into practical strategies for developing “reciprocity intelligence” in yourself and your team.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      
        <summary type="html">In today’s workplace, we need both a culture of contribution and the personal strength to thrive independently.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Agents vs MCP: Is the AI Hype Shifting?</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/agents-v-mcp" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Agents vs MCP: Is the AI Hype Shifting?" />
      <published>2025-04-07T00:00:00-04:00</published>
      <updated>2025-04-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/agents-v-mcp</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/agents-v-mcp">&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been following AI developments at all over the last year, I’m sure you heard about how autonomous AI agents were the next big thing that was going to change the landscape. You might have also heard names like AutoGPT, BabyAGI, and CAMEL AI. These agents could loop through tasks, reflect, plan, and even decide which tools to use. It felt a little like magic or sci fi to be able to give them a goal and watch them figure things out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if you’ve still been following along the AI train, you’ve probably started hearing about the next big thing called Model Context Protocol, or MCP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is this going to overtake agents for the next big thing? How are they different than agents? This 101 post should give you a little more insight into agents and MCP and understand how they’ll continue to impact the AI landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;intern-vs-assembly-line-a-metaphor&quot;&gt;Intern vs Assembly Line: A Metaphor&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since there are a lot of people talking about both of these, there’s no shortage of information, but let’s try to think of it in a practical way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Agents are like highly capable assistants that can independently complete complex tasks when given clear roles, goals, and the right tools. Earlier versions felt like handing a vague task to a junior intern. Today’s agents like those built with CrewAI or LangGraph can function more like specialized team members in a workflow.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MCP are like giving a trained operator access to a tightly organized set of APIs and tools, with a clear understanding of how to use them. The system is grounded, predictable, and effective because it follows a well-defined communication protocol.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-agents&quot;&gt;What Are Agents?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Autonomous AI agents are systems that use AI to think, plan, and take actions on their own. They often use tools, remember what they’ve done, and reflect on their results to improve as they go. They typically use large language models (LLMs) to make decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;agent-strengths&quot;&gt;Agent Strengths&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Great for exploration, ideation, and R&amp;amp;D&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can autonomously coordinate multiple tools and tasks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Modern frameworks (e.g. CrewAI) support reliable, role-based behavior and collaboration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;weaknesses&quot;&gt;Weaknesses&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Still require clear prompts and setup to be effective&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Debugging and transparency can be tricky&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Costly when not tightly scoped&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;real-use-case-research-automation&quot;&gt;Real Use Case: Research Automation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some developers have used agents to research new topics by instructing them to search the web, summarize sources, and provide reports. If you’re like me, you’ve probably done this and found that although the agent is confident, they’re often unreliable and provide outdated or even hallucinated content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;agent-example-autogpt-for-seo-content-research&quot;&gt;Agent Example: AutoGPT for SEO Content Research&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say a starup wants to generate a blog content plan based on competitor analysis and trending keywords. Instead of using a single, looping agent like AutoGPT, they use CrewAI to assign specific roles to multiple agents in a structured workflow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DataFetcher Agent: Crawls top competitor blogs and pulls content.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;KeywordAnalyzer Agent: Extracts trending SEO keywords from the collected content.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ContentStrategist Agent: Generates 10 article ideas tailored to the startup’s niche.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system coordinates their work, uses APIs for data gathering, ensures reliable outputs, and assembles the results in a structured format—like a JSON file or database entry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why does this still qualify as an agent-based approach?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Each agent has a defined role but operates autonomously within that scope.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Agents decide how to accomplish their task using available tools.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The system runs without step-by-step user intervention.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s modular, adaptable, and can evolve with more or fewer agents as needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This structured take on agents is more reliable than early implementations like AutoGPT, but still retains the autonomy and flexibility that define agent-based systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-mcp&quot;&gt;What Are MCP?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Model Context Protocols (MCP) are standards that help AI models connect to real tools, data, and APIs in a reliable way. Instead of guessing, the model knows what tools it can use, what kind of data to expect, and how to respond with clean, structured output.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MCP are all about giving the model clear rules for how to work with real-world systems and information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;strengths&quot;&gt;Strengths&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Predictable and testable&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Grounded in real-time or structured data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Designed for reliability in production&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;weaknesses-1&quot;&gt;Weaknesses&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Less flexible in ambiguous scenarios&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Relies on well-defined schemas and system design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;real-use-case-connecting-models-to-live-apis&quot;&gt;Real Use Case: Connecting Models to Live APIs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With MCP, a model can understand how to query an external weather API, get user-specific account info, or return a JSON object for further processing without the unpredictability of hallucinations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;mcp-example-anthropics-model-context-protocol-for-travel-booking&quot;&gt;MCP Example: Anthropic’s Model Context Protocol for Travel Booking&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say a travel app startup wants users to get real-time booking options through natural language without risking unreliable results. They use Claude with Model Context Protocol (MCP) to connect structured tools like a flight search API and hotel database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s how it works:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The developer registers each tool with clear metadata: what it does, what input it expects, and what output it returns (FlightSearch, HotelAvailability, etc.).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Claude knows exactly how to interact with each tool without guesswork or hallucination.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;` User: “Find me a flight to Berlin next Friday and a hotel under $200 near Alexanderplatz.”`&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Claude parses the input, calls the right APIs, and responds with structured, programmatic output.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is this an MCP approach?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The model operates within a predefined protocol and toolset.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It doesn’t choose its own path by following clear, reliable instructions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The results are testable, repeatable, and safe for production environments.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s built for structure and reliability, not for exploring open-ended tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes MCP ideal for enterprise-scale use cases where accuracy, consistency, and control are more important than creative autonomy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;agents-vs-mcp-side-by-side&quot;&gt;Agents vs MCP: Side-by-Side&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Feature&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Agents&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;MCP (Model Context Protocols)&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Autonomy&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;High&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Low (Structured)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Predictability&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Low&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;High&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Debuggability&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Poor&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Strong&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Best Use Case&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Exploration, ideation&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Live data access, production workflows&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Hallucination Risk&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;High&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Low&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Cost Efficiency&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Low&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;High (due to fewer missteps)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: Agents today can use structured tools too—autonomy here refers to their ability to decide how and when to use them, versus MCP’s pre-defined pathways.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-shift-from-agents-to-mcp&quot;&gt;The Shift from Agents to MCP&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s no doubt that agents have allowed us to do work faster and more efficiently, but most developers want tools that are reliable, testable, and scalable. MCP offer more of that structure by allowing models to function more like connected services. Because of this, they can access and return real information instead of improvising answers. MCP aren’t going to cause the death of agents, but we can think of it like maturing in the process of using language models in real-world applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bonus-should-i-use-an-agent-or-model-context-protocol-mcp&quot;&gt;Bonus: Should I Use an Agent or Model Context Protocol (MCP)?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a very simiplified way to look at it, but hopefully if you’re still trying to figure this out, you might find some insight in the questions below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is your goal quick experimentation or creative exploration?&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;✅ Yes → &lt;strong&gt;Use an Agent&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;❌ No → Next question&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is this going into a production system?&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;✅ Yes → &lt;strong&gt;Use MCP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;❌ No → Next question&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you need precise control over tool usage and structured output (like JSON or API calls)?&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;✅ Yes → &lt;strong&gt;Use MCP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;❌ No → &lt;strong&gt;Use an Agent&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Situation&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Use Agent&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Use MCP&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Prototyping / R&amp;amp;D&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;✅&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Needs structured, reliable output&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;✅&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Calling multiple real-world APIs&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;✅&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;You want fast, creative ideas&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;✅&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Building a user-facing feature&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;✅&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      
        <summary type="html">If you’ve been following AI developments at all over the last year, I’m sure you heard about how autonomous AI agents were the next big thing that was going to change the landscape. You might have also heard names like AutoGPT, BabyAGI, and CAMEL AI. These agents could loop through tasks, reflect, plan, and even decide which tools to use. It felt a little like magic or sci fi to be able to give them a goal and watch them figure things out.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed> -->
