<!-- ---
layout: null
---
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/author/Bekah/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2021-09-20T05:22:10-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://localhost:4000/author/Bekah/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">BekahHW | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Code. Community. Feelings. It's all here.</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Preptember: Maintainer Powerups</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/Preptember-Maintainer-Powerups" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Preptember: Maintainer Powerups" />
      <published>2021-09-12T00:00:00-04:00</published>
      <updated>2021-09-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/Preptember:%20Maintainer%20Powerups</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Preptember-Maintainer-Powerups">&lt;p&gt;When we talk about open source repositories, there can be a lot of moving pieces, especially for maintainers. We’re juggling new issues, duplicate issues, discussions, pull requests, and many of us are volunteers. Although there will always be new challenges, between some simple things maintainers can do to make their repositories more contributor-friendly, and some tools that GitHub provides to help maintainers, we can reduce barriers to entry and reduce friction as we continue open-source projects. Here’s a list to help get you started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;maintainer-checklist&quot;&gt;Maintainer Checklist&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in some of the things maintainers can do to create a positive space for contributions, check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://virtualcoffee.io/member-resources/oss-maintainer-checklist/&quot;&gt;OSS Maintainer Guide&lt;/a&gt; created at &lt;a href=&quot;https://virtualcoffee.io&quot;&gt;Virtual Coffee&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The guide covers important things like documentation, Code of Conduct, the Contributing Guide, and how to make your repository welcoming to new contributors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most important parts of any open source project is to have clear paths of communication. Detailed instructions of how to communicate with maintainers, instructions for creating or working on issues, and when to create a pull request, should be covered in your Contributors Guide. For an example, you can check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Virtual-Coffee/virtualcoffee.io/blob/main/CONTRIBUTING.md&quot;&gt;our Contributors Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;issues&quot;&gt;Issues&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the ways to help contributors and yourself as a maintainer is to utilize issue templates or forms. For a detailed guide on how to do this with your GithHub repository, you can check out their doc &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.github.com/en/communities/using-templates-to-encourage-useful-issues-and-pull-requests/configuring-issue-templates-for-your-repository&quot;&gt;Configuring issue templates for your repository
&lt;/a&gt;. (And a quick note to say that forms are in beta right now, so keep that in mind. Personally, I think they’re pretty awesome so I’d love to see them stick around.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have issues set up, and a contributor wants to add an issue, there’s really no guidance on how to do it. Not only is the contributor left staring at a blank box, but the likelihood of getting all of the information you need as a maintainer to make a decision about the issue isn’t great as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2021/blank_issue.png&quot; alt=&quot;a blank issue input&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But including forms or templates in your repository can eliminate some of those clarifying conversations. And one of the cool things is, you can create different templates/forms depending on your needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2021/issue_forms.png&quot; alt=&quot;a issue form options&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can give a more detailed breakdown of what information you want to see when you read the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to take a look at how we breakdown our issues, you can check each of them out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Virtual-Coffee/virtualcoffee.io/issues/new?assignees=&amp;amp;labels=Type%3A+bug%2CStatus%3A+Needs+Triage&amp;amp;template=bug-report.yml&quot;&gt;Bug report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Virtual-Coffee/virtualcoffee.io/issues/new?assignees=&amp;amp;labels=Type%3A+documentation%2CStatus%3A+Needs+Triage&amp;amp;template=documentation-change.yml&quot;&gt;Documentation Change&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Virtual-Coffee/virtualcoffee.io/issues/new?assignees=&amp;amp;labels=Type%3A+enhancement%2CStatus%3A+Needs+Triage&amp;amp;template=feature-request.yml&quot;&gt;Feature Request&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within that list, we also have Questions/Ideas/Feedback, which takes our contributors to our discussion board where we like to start the conversation before converting it to an issue as we see fit–which I think deserves a post of its own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;labels&quot;&gt;Labels&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make labels your friend. This makes it easy for contributors to quickly scan or to sort the issues on your repository and it makes it easier for you to separate and breakdown possible features, bug fixes, status of issues, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, let the labels work for you. Not only can you create the labels and choose the color of the label, but you can also add a description for what that label means. This makes it easier for your contributors to understand as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2021/label_ex.png&quot; alt=&quot;Reserved for Learners label&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal for everything you do for your repository is to create clear paths of communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you might not get it right every time. In fact, you might try something that you think is great, only to discover that it’s made things more complicated. That’s fine! You tried it, and now you can remove it, edit it, update it, do what works for your project right now. And that’s a good mindset to have. We should always be evaluating and re-evaluating our processes, projects, and ourselves to make sure we’re updating things that need updated and growing.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Open Source" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">When we talk about open source repositories, there can be a lot of moving pieces, especially for maintainers. We’re juggling new issues, duplicate issues, discussions, pull requests, and many of us are volunteers. Although there will always be new challenges, between some simple things maintainers can do to make their repositories more contributor-friendly, and some tools that GitHub provides to help maintainers, we can reduce barriers to entry and reduce friction as we continue open-source projects. Here’s a list to help get you started.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Preptember: Getting ready for Hacktoberfest</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/Preptember-Getting-ready-for-Hacktoberfest" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Preptember: Getting ready for Hacktoberfest" />
      <published>2021-09-07T00:00:00-04:00</published>
      <updated>2021-09-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/Preptember:%20Getting%20ready%20for%20Hacktoberfest</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Preptember-Getting-ready-for-Hacktoberfest">&lt;p&gt;It’s Preptember!!!! What does that even mean? &lt;strong&gt;Story time.&lt;/strong&gt; Last year was the first year I had ever heard about Preptember. We, at &lt;a href=&quot;https://virtualcoffee.io/&quot;&gt;Virtual Coffee&lt;/a&gt; were just starting to get ready to our first &lt;a href=&quot;https://hacktoberfest.digitalocean.com/&quot;&gt;Hacktoberfest&lt;/a&gt; together, and somewhere along the line, someone told us that September was coined Preptember as we prepared to go into Hacktoberfest. And in a lot of ways, for organizers, Preptember is even more work than Hacktoberfest. Because this is month that we prepare for all of our events, that we make sure we have support systems in place for our members, that we do the work to ensure that we’ve thought through every problem imaginable and we set everyone up for success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of Preptember, this is what we’re doing at Virtual Coffee:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;monthly-challenge&quot;&gt;Monthly Challenge&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every month we do a challenge where we try to work on one focus for the month and produce something for the end of the month. This month, we’re asking our Maintainers to prep their repos by reviewing with our checklist and we’re preparing our contributors by asking them to write issues for our &lt;a href=&quot;https://virtualcoffee.io/monthlychallenges/sept-2021/&quot;&gt;Preptember Challenge&lt;/a&gt;. We have discussions going on in the channel and support for every member.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;documentation&quot;&gt;Documentation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We rely so heavily on documentation as part of all of our processes. As part of this, not only do we create documentation for our events, projects, and initiatives, but we also do our best to update them regularly. For example, we recently started using &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Virtual-Coffee/virtualcoffee.io/discussions&quot;&gt;Github discussions for our VCIO repository&lt;/a&gt;. As a result, we needed to add instructions about using the discussion board to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Virtual-Coffee/virtualcoffee.io/blob/main/CONTRIBUTING.md&quot;&gt;Contributing.md file&lt;/a&gt;. This file is the first step in clear communication with our contributors. It explains the process for opening issues, contributing, and submitting Pull Requests (PRs).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;curated-list-of-open-source-repositories&quot;&gt;Curated List of Open Source Repositories&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re very focused on making sure members at all stages of the coding journey have the opportunity to participate in Hacktoberfest. This means that we need a wide variety of repositories that are welcoming, have clear documentation and communication, and are participating in Hacktoberfest. In an effort to create a well-rounded list that isn’t limited by our own experiences and backgrounds, we’ve opened a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Virtual-Coffee/virtualcoffee.io/discussions/321&quot;&gt;public discussion&lt;/a&gt; on our repository to gather suggestions that we’ll review before they are included on our Virtual Coffee list&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;call-for-maintainers-contributors-and-mentors&quot;&gt;Call for Maintainers, Contributors, and Mentors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back by popular demand, we’ll be asking our members to participate in Hacktoberfest with our support by signing up as Maintainers, Contributors, and/or Mentors. As part of this, we’ll ensure that contributors who want mentors will have support, and that maintainers have our support as well, as we support them as we review their repositories and by helping them to create issues for contributors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lunch--learns&quot;&gt;Lunch &amp;amp; Learns&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to make sure that we educate and empower our members as they journey through Hacktoberfest. This month, we’ll be doing three Lunch &amp;amp; Learns on open source related content: An Open Source Project Walkthrough, How to create an Open Source Software Repository, and An Intro to Hacktoberfest and Open Source Contributions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;kick-off-hacktoberfest-event&quot;&gt;Kick-off Hacktoberfest Event&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although we aren’t doing this in September, we’re preparing for it. We want to make sure we have an issue that everyone can participate in, that we can demonstrate, and that we can answer questions about together. This &lt;a href=&quot;https://meetingplace.io/virtual-coffee/events/7070&quot;&gt;event&lt;/a&gt; will give our members the confidence they need to get them started–and maybe even complete!–their first Hacktoberfest pull request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a glimpse of what we’re doing to support our members and we’ll be revealing more details as the month goes on. If you want to support us, you can volunteer–form coming soon!–or &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sponsors/Virtual-Coffee&quot;&gt;sponsor us&lt;/a&gt;.
But if you couldn’t tell from our most recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://virtualcoffee.io/podcast/0309-season-three-wrap-up/&quot;&gt;podcast episode&lt;/a&gt;, we are super excited that we’re working on our second round of Hacktoberfest as a community, and we’re stoked to see how this year turns out.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Open Source" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">It’s Preptember!!!! What does that even mean? Story time. Last year was the first year I had ever heard about Preptember. We, at Virtual Coffee were just starting to get ready to our first Hacktoberfest together, and somewhere along the line, someone told us that September was coined Preptember as we prepared to go into Hacktoberfest. And in a lot of ways, for organizers, Preptember is even more work than Hacktoberfest. Because this is month that we prepare for all of our events, that we make sure we have support systems in place for our members, that we do the work to ensure that we’ve thought through every problem imaginable and we set everyone up for success.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Interview Series: Birthdays, job responses, and feedback</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/The-Interview-Series-Birthdays,-job-responses,-and-feedback" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Interview Series: Birthdays, job responses, and feedback" />
      <published>2021-08-02T00:00:00-04:00</published>
      <updated>2021-08-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/The%20Interview%20Series:%20Birthdays,%20job%20responses,%20and%20feedback</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/The-Interview-Series-Birthdays,-job-responses,-and-feedback">&lt;p&gt;When I was a kid, I used to do Richard Simmons’ Sweatin’ to the Oldies–the VHS dance workout–with my mom. And I &lt;em&gt;loved&lt;/em&gt; the choreography for “It’s my party and I’ll cry if I want to.” Well, that was the foreshadowing to this moment. So just like we had a 2 for 1 deal for birthdays on July 21st–it was both mine and my son’s birthday–I would also get a kind of 2 for 1 deal on the interviews: two rejections in one day on my birthday. Not ideal. But also, I’m a believer that it’s better to know bad news than to be stuck in the limbo of not knowing news. And it’s in the moments after the news, in the process of feelings and feedback that we regroup and define who we are &lt;em&gt;next.&lt;/em&gt; And this post, it’s about all of those things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-i-found-out&quot;&gt;How I found out&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;junior-role&quot;&gt;Junior Role&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hadn’t heard from the team since the interview, but I had expected to hear something early in the week of July 12th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But after the final interview, I offered to talk through the interview process with one of the interviewers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So during that interview retro, my first question was “have you offered the position to someone?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We have.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never received a rejection notification, and that was the first time I heard the news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started Virtual Coffee, a number of women in tech told me it wasn’t a good idea to continue building the community. “People won’t see you as technical. They’ll see you as a project manager,” they said. Can you guess the feedback?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE REASON&lt;/strong&gt;: “We’re looking for someone more technical. If we open up a Project Manager position, we hope you’ll apply!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;senior-role&quot;&gt;Senior role&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also expected to hear back from this job around the week of the 12th. On the 15th, I got a message saying they were still reviewing applications, but there would be a decision by Tuesday, July 20th. When the 20th came and went, I sent a message asking if I could assume someone else had been offered the position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick reply let me know that they pushed back the decision, but I’d know by that afternoon. And I did. We had a quick phone call around 5:00.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE REASON&lt;/strong&gt;: Not enough experience. There would need to be some time to get me up to senior level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Would you say I’m not technical enough?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Absolutely not.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’m just going to take a second to let you think about this.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pause…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you see it? The junior role didn’t think I was technical enough. The senior role quickly answered that wasn’t the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here’s the thing; every team defines their wants and their needs differently. Every team interviews differently. You don’t get a drastic difference in opinion like that, without such a varied and unpredictable system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So, here’s your reminder if you’ve recently been rejected from a job or jobs: interviewing is a system with variables that you can’t control, that you can’t solve. And you *can’t&lt;/em&gt; possibly ever know all of the variables going into those interviews.*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-went-wrong&quot;&gt;What Went Wrong?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-didnt-ask-them-what-they-wanted&quot;&gt;I didn’t ask them what they wanted.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interviews have a performative aspect. If you’re being evaluated by a team, you need to know what each of the team members is looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to ask, as &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/GantLaborde&quot;&gt;Gant Laborde&lt;/a&gt; calls it, “the power question”: what’s a problem that currently exists that the ideal hire would solve?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you get their answers, you’ve got a cheat sheet for your answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I only asked this question to one person, and so I didn’t have the cheat sheet for my interview. I &lt;em&gt;thought&lt;/em&gt; I knew what they wanted based on what problems they talked about, and I focused on that for my answers. But the thing is, sometimes you don’t know all the weaknesses they have or the pressures they’re feeling the most, even if you ask.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the junior role, I leaned heavily into talking about Virtual Coffee and systems and processes because I knew I was originally brought in to interview because of my work with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Could I have talked about specific coding concepts? Yep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Could I have talked about how my experience as an English teacher equipped me to break down complex concepts, communicate ideas to different audiences, speak in front of groups, create and organize content methodically and with structure? Yep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Could I have been more confident when I wasn’t getting non-verbal feedback from my interviewers? Yep, again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should I have spent more time preparing? 100% no, but it doesn’t mean that I didn’t fall down into the self-destruction pit or that I was able to think this through unemotionally after I got the news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-response&quot;&gt;My Response&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where the “Dark Night of the Soul” moment comes in. The moment where you doubt yourself and your place in the world. The moment you wonder if you belong, if you have what it takes. The moment you think maybe you’ve been lying to yourself this whole time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What they said was:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You aren’t technical enough.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;You aren’t experienced enough.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what I heard was:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You aren’t enough.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I cried not because I didn’t get the offers, I cried because I doubted myself, because I felt like I had wasted my time and the time of others. Because maybe I was Icharus, and I was falling down to the ground because I was flying where I didn’t belong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I messaged a friend who has become a mentor to me over the last year, and who I first told about the initial invitation to apply for the Junior Role. And in the course of the conversation, they asked two important questions that allowed me to refocus:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where do you think your technical skills are? Self-evaluate.&lt;br /&gt;
What are your next steps?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;self-evaluation-of-my-technical-skills-a-brainstorm&quot;&gt;Self-evaluation of my Technical skills, a brainstorm&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I need to be more confident. I need to talk about technical concepts as confidently as I talk about community.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I need to have a broader understanding of React and JS concepts, to be able to apply them outside of the codebase I primarily work on.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m good at testing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I can build a component with a mock-up.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I need work on optimizing and doing things like creating custom hooks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I understand key ideas and code, but I need to deepen my roots and learn how/when to use more advanced concepts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A very deliberate self-evaluation is good. It allows for goals and growth plans. It creates a space for making progress. And this was a good time to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;next-steps&quot;&gt;Next Steps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was in 7th grade I wanted to run the hurdles on my track team. I could clear them pretty quickly and could consistently come in second place to an 8th grader. So I asked my coach if I could compete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’re too short,” my coach told me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of those enough statements. You aren’t tall enough, is what he was saying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And maybe it seems silly to remember that story, but this has been one of my greatest motivators. Being underestimated is an invitation to exceed expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t think I can clear these hurdles? Watch me break the record.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch me be technical.
Watch me amplify the technical and community skills of the women in my network.
Watch me do the things Senior DevRels do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have given references for people’s job searches. I have made connections that have led to hires. I have created programs that allowed for experiences that lead to new jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to support good people. So that’s it. That’s the next stage. To find ways to help more people. Because, at the end of the day, people are what matter.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Interview Series" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">When I was a kid, I used to do Richard Simmons’ Sweatin’ to the Oldies–the VHS dance workout–with my mom. And I loved the choreography for “It’s my party and I’ll cry if I want to.” Well, that was the foreshadowing to this moment. So just like we had a 2 for 1 deal for birthdays on July 21st–it was both mine and my son’s birthday–I would also get a kind of 2 for 1 deal on the interviews: two rejections in one day on my birthday. Not ideal. But also, I’m a believer that it’s better to know bad news than to be stuck in the limbo of not knowing news. And it’s in the moments after the news, in the process of feelings and feedback that we regroup and define who we are next. And this post, it’s about all of those things.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Two Companies, Two DevRel Positions, Two Different Interview Processes</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/Two-Companies,-Two-DevRel-Positions,-Two-Different-Interview-Processes" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Two Companies, Two DevRel Positions, Two Different Interview Processes" />
      <published>2021-07-25T00:00:00-04:00</published>
      <updated>2021-07-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/Two%20Companies,%20Two%20DevRel%20Positions,%20Two%20Different%20Interview%20Processes</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Two-Companies,-Two-DevRel-Positions,-Two-Different-Interview-Processes">&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&quot;https://bekahhw.github.io/How-I-Accidentally-Interviewed-for-Two-Jobs,-a-series&quot;&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt;, I talked about how I ended up interviewing for two positions without looking for a job. And what might seem like a process that should be fairly consistent since both were DevRel positions, there were still some pretty big differences that didn’t have to do with the fact that one was for a Senior position and the other a Junior. So here’s the breakdown of each process:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total length, from initial DM to decision&lt;/strong&gt;
Junior position: 71 days
Senior position: 33 days&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;interview-process&quot;&gt;Interview process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;junior-position&quot;&gt;Junior position&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Initial conversation with team lead&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Initial call with hiring manager&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;30 minute presentation before a panel of 5-6 team members with 30 minutes of questions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An hour leadership interview with two team members&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;45 minute interview with the hiring manager&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;45 minute diversity and inclusion interview&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;15 minute wrap up interview with recruiter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total active interview time&lt;/strong&gt;: 4 hours and 45 minutes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;senior-position&quot;&gt;Senior position&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Initial conversation with Director of DevRel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Recorded pair programming with head of DevRel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;15 minute recorded lightning talk on the subject of my choosing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;hour-long behavioral interview with Director of DevRel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total active interview time&lt;/strong&gt;: 3 hours and 15 minutes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;presentations&quot;&gt;Presentations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;junior-position-1&quot;&gt;Junior Position&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the presentation, I was given six different options, ranging from talking about one of their products, to DevOps, to a deep dive into a technical topic, to open-source, and finally, what I chose: how they should approach Online Video Content, Hackathons, Meet-ups, Social media, and Community Management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;my-approach&quot;&gt;My Approach&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although this seemed like the lengthiest subject to tackle, I immediately had ideas. I have worked on pretty much all of these and have learned a lot about systems and processes that empower volunteers to be a part of the process. The trouble with this was that the organization is really large, and I wanted to make sure I had a clear handle on what their approach had been so far, how have they done these things in the past, what had worked, and what could power them up in the future.
Because there wasn’t a clear home base for these things on their site, this process took a long time. I learned a lot about the organization, found things that I didn’t know existed, and started to put together some notes and slides. In total, I ended up with 24 slides for a thirty minute presentation, and an additional walkthrough at the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most challenging aspects was that I had to tackle an approach to five different topics, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; it was really important to me that they understood my philosophy behind my approach that tied all of these things together. So in addition to the deep dive into their organization, creating the presentation and slides, I had to cut down my very long presentation to get closer to a thirty minute presentation. &lt;em&gt;Listen&lt;/em&gt;, I could’ve spent at least an hour talking about each of these individual pieces. This was not an easy or quick job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What happened was I had to take time off work to work on it. I made the (wrong) decision to skip one of my favorite local monthly events with my family to work on it. I worked and worked and worked on it. I’m proud of the final project I submitted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when I got to the interview, it turned out that there was a mistake in the email. It should have said to choose &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; of these (Online video content, Hackathons, Meet-ups, Social media, and community management) and give your approach. So what I put sixty hours into, could’ve taken a fraction of the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total time researching and creating presentation&lt;/strong&gt;: ~60 hours&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;senior-position-1&quot;&gt;Senior Position&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The presentation directions were less specific here: Create a 15 minute lightning talk on the subject of your choosing, record, and email a link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;my-approach-1&quot;&gt;My Approach&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a much shorter process because it wasn’t focused on an understanding of the company. I didn’t jump into the project either. I took some time to look at the current team members, listen and watch what they were currently doing, and tried to image how I could fit on the team. That was a little bit easier because I had already met a handful of them at some point in my coding journey, and I already enjoyed those experiences.
I was still having a hard time imagining how I fit into their world. They seem like a really well-rounded team. So I brainstormed a number of topics and finally wrote really detailed outlines for both, and presented them to three developers I’m close to for their feedback. And from that came The Coder’s Journey: Meeting the mentor, a fifteen minute talk with 40 slides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, here’s where the frustrating part came in. For those of you who’ve had the experience of speaking before a live audience versus recording yourself, you may have felt how hard it is to keep the same energy when there’s no feedback, no head nods, not acknowledgement. And for me, when I deliver a talk, I get super nervous. But, for whatever reason, it works because I can direct and exchange energy with the audience and it balances out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I’m talking to myself into a camera, the only place for that extra energy to go is back to myself. And to top that off were the technical difficulties I faced recording the talk. For me, it was important to get it all in one take to better replicate the live experience. Initially, I had some pacing issues, then some lighting issues, then some video issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I thought I nailed it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then I watched the video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The audio didn’t sync with the video. And I couldn’t fix it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, I was frustrated and starting to get tired of delivering the same talk. So when I hit a point where I finally made it through the material and the sound worked, I was done. I couldn’t deliver that talk to myself, without an audience anymore. Not today, not tomorrow, maybe sometime in the far future. Was it my best performance? For sure no. But it was the best I could do in the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total time researching and creating presentation&lt;/strong&gt;: ~6 hours (If I hadn’t had the technical difficulties with recording, this would have been more like 4 hours)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;interview-highlights&quot;&gt;Interview Highlights&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;junior-position-2&quot;&gt;Junior Position&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One of the questions I asked was about the pain points the team was currently facing. I felt like there was a lot of honesty from the team about the challenges they were facing. It helped me to have a better understanding of what I was potentially walking into.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I loved the Diversity and Inclusion interview. The interviewer did a great job of making me feel heard in the interview, allowing me to talk openly and vulnerably, providing me with a response and conversation. She was also the only mom in tech that I had the chance to interview with 1:1. I think that made a huge difference in the report from the beginning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;senior-position-2&quot;&gt;Senior Position&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The behavioral interview was simultaneously one of the worst and best experiences. We talked through my work history, strengths and weaknesses, and the interviewer provided me feedback on what &lt;em&gt;they&lt;/em&gt; saw as my strengths and weaknesses. It was one of the worst because it was emotionally exhausting talking through some of the challenges I’ve faced in the workplace and really digging in deep to the whys and hows of the situation. It was also the best because I learned a lot about myself in that session. There’s maybe been one or two other times in my life where someone has read me that well. It’s both a jarring and exciting experience. It’s exciting because there’s so much potential for growth in those situations. There are things that are understood that you don’t have to reveal. There’s less of an opportunity to hide. I came out of that interview feeling like I knew there was a person invested in &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt;, and I can’t think of any better outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;overall-highlights&quot;&gt;Overall highlights&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interviewing can certainly be exhausting, but I’m super thankful for all I learned through these two processes. I learned more about the right questions to ask (there will be a post on that!), how to listen better, how to make the process meaningful for myself. I learned about DevRel. I learned about different approaches to DevRel and management and processes. I learned that even though I’ve never been paid as a DevRel, I am doing so many DevRel things and that my 10 years of teaching college English courses is certainly an asset that I can lean into way more than I have been. I learned that taking a more direct approach to asking questions is important to me. I learned that continued communication, whether through DMs or emails or some other mode, is really important for me to understand as much as I can. I learned that feedback is really important, and that’s what I’ll talk about in the next post.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Interview Series" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">In the last post, I talked about how I ended up interviewing for two positions without looking for a job. And what might seem like a process that should be fairly consistent since both were DevRel positions, there were still some pretty big differences that didn’t have to do with the fact that one was for a Senior position and the other a Junior. So here’s the breakdown of each process:</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">How I accidentally interviewed for two jobs</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/How-I-Accidentally-Interviewed-for-Two-Jobs,-a-series" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How I accidentally interviewed for two jobs" />
      <published>2021-07-20T00:00:00-04:00</published>
      <updated>2021-07-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/How%20I%20Accidentally%20Interviewed%20for%20Two%20Jobs,%20a%20series</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/How-I-Accidentally-Interviewed-for-Two-Jobs,-a-series">&lt;h1 id=&quot;part-i-interview-them-first&quot;&gt;Part I: Interview Them First&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve heard people say they interview for practice or for fun. I am not one of those people. I am the opposite of those people. On top of being not one of those people, I am also a person who is incredibly satisfied with my job and life, except as an independent contractor my family and I pay out of pocket for medical insurance. And I have over $70,000 of medical bills sitting on my desk with more coming. So when someone from a notable company in tech reached out to me and encouraged me to apply to a DevRel position, and then when I talked to a friend in tech who encouraged me to apply for a senior DevRel position, I did. This is the first in a series of posts on what I’ve learned through this process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;its-ok-to-say-no-or-recommend-someone-else&quot;&gt;It’s Ok to say no or recommend someone else&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an early-career developer who gets maybe more DMs than most early-career devs because of what I’ve done with &lt;a href=&quot;https://virtualcoffee.io/&quot;&gt;Virtual Coffee&lt;/a&gt;, I’ve had a number of people reach out and ask me to apply for jobs. Usually, I decline and recommend someone else I know. If you look at the job, and it’s not something that’s interesting, within your desired salary, or you find out more about the team and you don’t think you’d be a good fit, it’s ok to pass or to recommend someone else you think would be a good fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-your-research-and-reach-out-to-people-you-trust&quot;&gt;Do Your Research and Reach out to People you Trust&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since coming into tech, I’ve always said that my dream job is working with good people. And that’s 100% true for me. I have been working with good–actually amazing–people. I’ve also seen so many devs fall into really toxic work environments. So if I’m going to leave a situation I’m happy with, I’m going to do my research. For me this means learning about the people on the teams, the companies, and DMing people who I know in tech and asking them about the teams, companies, and/or positions. Through these DMs, I learned:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some tough questions to ask to gauge the strength of the teams and to avoid workplace toxicity;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to gauge the sincerity of responses;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How current teams functioned within the organization and how that would impact the position;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What the current team dynamics are;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;About the projects, processes, and structures the teams use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ask-direct-questions&quot;&gt;Ask Direct Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I wasn’t actively looking for work, I came to the process with a privileged position. I could afford to ask questions that some might be afraid to ask initially. Some of the questions I asked prior to the interviews were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What’s the salary range?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Could I continue organizing Virtual Coffee as part of the job?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are your current pain points?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is the schedule flexible?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What does the health insurance like?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can we talk about the title?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, &lt;em&gt;you’re&lt;/em&gt; interviewing them as well. If you have values or standards that are important to you, it’s ok to be selective from the very beginning. In fact, it was the openness and honesty of the answers that made me feel comfortable going further in the process, which I’ll talk about in my next post, because these weren’t quick and simple processes.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Interview Series" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Part I: Interview Them First</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Notes from Twitter Spaces on Community and Remote Work</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/Notes-from-Twitter-Spaces-on-Community-and-Remote-Work" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Notes from Twitter Spaces on Community and Remote Work" />
      <published>2021-06-28T00:00:00-04:00</published>
      <updated>2021-06-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/Notes%20from%20Twitter%20Spaces%20on%20Community%20and%20Remote%20Work</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Notes-from-Twitter-Spaces-on-Community-and-Remote-Work">&lt;p&gt;My notes from the last two weeks of Twitter spaces I hosted. These are not all my ideas, and I might not agree with them all. But, I wanted to share what we talked about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;community--career&quot;&gt;Community + Career&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-should-you-be-a-part-of-a-community&quot;&gt;Why should you be a part of a community?*&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Helps with career guidance&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Supports you as you grow&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allows for networking opportunities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creates a safe space for exploring new ideas and industries&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Provides opportunities to help others&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;As always, this depends on the community you join. Not all experiences will be the same for all people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;find-the-community-that-supports-its-members&quot;&gt;Find the community that supports its members&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re looking to join a community, here are some signs that the community supports its members:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Authentic and vulnerable relationships and interactions,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Investment in helping each other to grow -&amp;gt; look at how people are answering questions or if help and support posts are mostly answered,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Openness to new ideas and experiences -&amp;gt; are members testing out new ideas or actions? Do you see people saying they’ve done something for the first time as part of that group?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Supportive communities can provide a space for you to try new things. For example, maybe you’re interested in speaking at a conference, but you’re afraid. If you have a supportive community, it’s easier to try out the experience. Give your presentation to the community and ask for feedback. When you have a supportive community, it’s easier to be open to feedback, to learn from the experience, and to work towards your goal of giving a presentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-find-the-right-communities&quot;&gt;How to find the right communities&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make sure they have a code of conduct, esp if you’re part of an under-represented group&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They all you to be a passive member of a community -&amp;gt; soak up the knowledge and experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;signs-of-a-positive-community&quot;&gt;Signs of a positive community&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There’s a Code of Conduct&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For non-discord platforms, when people use their real names&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Members of under-represented groups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;remote-work&quot;&gt;Remote Work&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some companies did even better when they were forced to go remote&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can do the same thing from home that you can do in the office&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PPl are forming networks and relationships outside of the office as a result. There’s less glue, holding you to stick in the current position.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You don’t have the opportunities to network outside of the office&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remote and COVID-remote are two very different things. There are a lot of extra outside stressors. Remote was being thrust on ppl rather than a decision people made.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-work-in-a-physical-office&quot;&gt;Why work in a physical office?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some people prefer to work in the office&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Extrovert!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clear physical lines of communication: You can walk to the person’s office if you have a question.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sometimes a challenge of getting work done&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There’s a different type of productivity -&amp;gt; talking with the people around you allows you to develop relationships more quickly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You build teams much quicker in the office&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Community building is easier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;positives-of-working-remotely&quot;&gt;Positives of working remotely&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Flexibility, especially for parents&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allows parents to take breaks and spend time with their kids&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t have to commute&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allows for productive breaks -&amp;gt; You can start the laundry, dinner, do errands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;navigating-challenges-of-working-remotely&quot;&gt;Navigating challenges of working remotely&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you don’t have a designated office space, it can be a challenge, but if you set boundaries&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set rules for yourself: when to log off. Turn off the computer and don’t touch it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do a full shutdown every night&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Separate work and “home” computer, so there’s no drive to work after work hours&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set a hard limit for work hours&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dealing with stress and the easy access to food&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;miscellaneous&quot;&gt;Miscellaneous&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Normalize kid noises in the back of every meeting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Productivity: there’s kind of no middle ground. There’s ppl who are super productive and not productive at all. This might speak to the type of office-environment that works best for you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We shouldn’t be micromanaging. Daily standup, project tracking, and milestones are enough to evaluated the productivity of the team.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Forcing extra steps to force ppl to report progress, that’s toxic.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If there’s an issue with a person, approach it as “How can we support you? Is there a challenge I can help you with?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Developers should have autonomy and support&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Over-communication &amp;gt; under-communication&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t do remote work on vacation!!!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Team-building remotely: Depending on the team, turn on the cameras, hear the voice of the other person&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whole set of problems returning to office spaces now with mice, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bonus&quot;&gt;Bonus&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;blog post idea: how to structure your team to be productive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Tips" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">My notes from the last two weeks of Twitter spaces I hosted. These are not all my ideas, and I might not agree with them all. But, I wanted to share what we talked about.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Code + Community: the highlight reel</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/Code-+-Community-the-highlight-reel" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Code + Community: the highlight reel" />
      <published>2021-06-07T00:00:00-04:00</published>
      <updated>2021-06-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/Code%20+%20Community:%20the%20highlight%20reel</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Code-+-Community-the-highlight-reel">&lt;p&gt;Last week, we wrapped up our second season of the Virtual Coffee (VC) Podcast with our &lt;a href=&quot;https://virtualcoffee.io/podcast/0209-season-two-wrapup/&quot;&gt;Code and Community episode&lt;/a&gt;. As VC’s been growing over the last year, I’ve been working on the Virtual Coffee model for communities, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/danieltott&quot;&gt;Dan&lt;/a&gt; and I have spent a lot of time talking through navigating the challenges and creating a direction for our unique community with the support and care of the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I was especially inspired to write a highlight version of the episode when I saw Lucia’s tweet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BekahHW?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@BekahHW&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/danieltott?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@danieltott&lt;/a&gt; are leaders in effective, unconventional ways. Listen for their view on metrics, community building, and purpose. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/4FyYJhafO7&quot;&gt;https://t.co/4FyYJhafO7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Lucia Cerchie 🦎 (@CerchieLucia) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/CerchieLucia/status/1400135495984709632?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 2, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are my top takeaways from this episode:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We have so many ideas for the community, but there aren’t enough hours in the day to work on them all. We’re doing our best to prioritize them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We’re more than a slack of people who do meetups, events, and more. We’re “an intimate community for all devs, optimized for you.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The face-to-face conversations are a key part of our identity. And it’s important to us that we keep our breakout rooms small to allow opportunities for everyone to join in the conversation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s easier to stretch and grow when you know you have the support of the community.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We’re inspired by the book &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.radicalcandor.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Radical Candor&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;! Clear and honest communication are important tools for trust and growth.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We think of Virtual Coffee as an open source community.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Building deliberately and creating structures and processes to empower members to help takes time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We’re never going to put content behind a paywall.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tooling with a team can be really expensive, and it’s challenging to find services that allow people to help when you have a small community and no funding .&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The goal of the Virtual Coffee Model is to have a lasting impact on your community, to create ripples that extend far beyond your community.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;So much of community tooling is based on making money off our your members. Since that’s not our goal, it’s been challenging to find a good fit.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;As community leadership, you can see each person individually and you can recognize them, but if you don’t have support in the tools, in the structures, you’re not going to get very far.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Traditional community metrics leave a lot of people out. We value each member participating in the ways that are most comfortable for them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Our focus isn’t to grow &lt;a href=&quot;https://virtualcoffee.io/&quot;&gt;Virtual Coffee&lt;/a&gt;, it’s to support our members.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Community" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Last week, we wrapped up our second season of the Virtual Coffee (VC) Podcast with our Code and Community episode. As VC’s been growing over the last year, I’ve been working on the Virtual Coffee model for communities, and Dan and I have spent a lot of time talking through navigating the challenges and creating a direction for our unique community with the support and care of the community.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">I did something that scared me: I took a week off</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/I-did-something-that-scared-me-I-took-a-week-off" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I did something that scared me: I took a week off" />
      <published>2021-04-26T00:00:00-04:00</published>
      <updated>2021-04-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/I%20did%20something%20that%20scared%20me:%20I%20took%20a%20week%20off</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/I-did-something-that-scared-me-I-took-a-week-off">&lt;p&gt;A friend recently asked me if I am a results or a process person. I told her that I’m a momentum person. I like to move. I don’t like breaks. But when we hit the one year mark of &lt;a href=&quot;https://virtualcoffee.io/&quot;&gt;Virtual Coffee&lt;/a&gt;, and I realized that I hadn’t had a week off in a year I didn’t &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to take time off, but I thought I probably &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt;. And it was the right call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s why:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-had-time-to-work-on-things-i-missed&quot;&gt;I had time to work on things I missed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of the problem of being momentum-driven is that you go with the flow and the things that excite you. And when you have a community of a couple hundred people, there are &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of cool ideas. And I’ve been full force on the Virtual Coffee train for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking time off created time for me to revisit some of the things I love doing. I coded more. I worked on my postpartum wellness app. I spent less time on my phone. I spent time thinking about what I want and where I want to be. I created a new system for tasks and project for myself (it’s colored post-it notes that I stick on my wall, but it’s been great for brainstorming and prioritizing).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got to do a personal training session for the first time in a very long time. I worked on three different kinds of box jumps, because when you’re as short as I am, you’ve gotta make up for that somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had fun. I had energizing conversations. I laughed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-had-the-opportunity-to-do-some-tough-self-evaluation&quot;&gt;I had the opportunity to do some tough self-evaluation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday at 9:00am EDT–when I usually host Virtual Coffee–I worked with my &lt;a href=&quot;https://katiecmckenna.com/&quot;&gt;favorite career coach&lt;/a&gt;, who helped me to breakdown tasks, prioritize, and to think strategically and practically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Just finished meeting with the amazing &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/katiecmckenna?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@katiecmckenna&lt;/a&gt; and it’s always a great use of my time. She asks the hard questions, says the things that are hard to hear, and helps me to believe in myself. (Also, she’s hilarious, kind, and a great author.) &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/TfQDUVAggz&quot;&gt;https://t.co/TfQDUVAggz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Bekah Hawrot Weigel (@BekahHW) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BekahHW/status/1384513366190866436?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;April 20, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She made me break down the hours I spend on work and Virtual Coffee, and helped me realize some hard truths about some bad habits I was forming. She helped me find action items and made plans to hold me accountable. (If she asks, yes I am working on them!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked at how I’ve been doing things from an objective level, from the perspective of “what advice would you give someone else who told you this is what they’ve been doing?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned that burnout happens in different ways and with different feelings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned about the importance of boundaries and clearly setting them up. Because I’ve continually said that I have boundaries, but they’re easy to blur when you don’t have a clear guide to stop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned that I probably wasn’t doing a good job of providing an example for the Virtual Coffee members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned that I need to believe in myself, to acknowledge my strengths rather than devaluing them, and to recognize that what I’m doing–both as a developer and a community builder–is good and worthwhile work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-can-come-back-with-renewed-energy&quot;&gt;I can come back with renewed energy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought I would be anxious the whole week. It was like leaving my kids for a weekend with my parents the first time. I was sad the first day, but then I inhaled deeply and felt renewed and refreshed and ready to jump back in after the break was over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I needed it without knowing that I needed it. As an introvert, I’ve not done a great job of recognizing how impacted I’ve been by constantly being engaged. I’ve somehow developed the ability to get through the week, and then I hit the weekend and feel like I’ve been hit by a truck. I didn’t feel that this weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And one of my “action items” from this break is to take a week off every quarter. Because I know it’s good for me, and it’s good for the community too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-could-see-the-virtual-coffee-pain-points-more-clearly&quot;&gt;I could see the Virtual Coffee pain points more clearly&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating space between myself and the community also allowed me to not be caught up in all the day-to-day organizing and responding and allowed me to see things from a new perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could walk through things without having to &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; the things. And I could much better identify where the chaos happens, where processes can be improved, where things are working well, where the community has really done a great job of innovating and responding to the groups needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;where-im-at-now&quot;&gt;Where I’m at now&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m three days into my first week back at Virtual Coffee, and I’m proud of myself for working on ways to set boundaries, to not let myself fall back into old habits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; happy to see my friends. And that’s part of what makes this so hard. This community, these people, they’re my people. They’re the people I enjoy being around. They’re the people I want to share my wins and losses with. And maybe that’s how all community creators feel, or maybe that’s what happens when you accidentally start a community. I don’t know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I do know that providing the best support for the community means that I’ll need to take more time off, and that I need to prioritize creating clearer paths of communication and support. And it probably means that I need to tell myself that I can do this. Even though I’m afraid that I’m not the best person to be doing this, I can do it, and I can learn, and I can grow into the person I want to while doing this, with the support of the community.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Tips" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">A friend recently asked me if I am a results or a process person. I told her that I’m a momentum person. I like to move. I don’t like breaks. But when we hit the one year mark of Virtual Coffee, and I realized that I hadn’t had a week off in a year I didn’t want to take time off, but I thought I probably should. And it was the right call.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Coding is Pattern-Matching: a growth-mindset perspective</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/Coding-is-Pattern-Matching" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Coding is Pattern-Matching: a growth-mindset perspective" />
      <published>2021-04-20T00:00:00-04:00</published>
      <updated>2021-04-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/Coding%20is%20Pattern-Matching</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Coding-is-Pattern-Matching">&lt;p&gt;A couple of years ago I was talking to a woman who was doing simultaneous Masters degrees from Carnegie Mellon University and running a brain study on chronic depression. When we were talking about her multiple degrees and her musical experience, all while she let me pick her brain about neurology, she said something that stuck with me, “All life is pattern-matching.” She explained the connections between her mathematical and scientific experience with her creative endeavors, and it made sense. Patterns are everywhere, and we learn through recognizing and seeing the patterns, internalizing them, applying them, and eventually understanding them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the approach I try to turn to when I’m frustrated with myself when I don’t “understand” the code that I’m seeing on the page. And &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; is a perspective that I would’ve benefitted from when I was learning to code, but most recently now, it’s what I lean into when I’m frustrated with myself for not understanding new concepts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;but-why-is-a-pattern-matching-perspective-important-to-coding&quot;&gt;But &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; is a pattern-matching perspective important to coding?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know about you, but I’ve let out some desperate cries to the universe to &lt;em&gt;please just let me get this so I can move on!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then one night, the magical neural-pathway fairy comes and sprinkles its coding dust onto my brain and I wake up, and suddenly it’s clicked. And I can’t remember why I couldn’t get it the day before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the perspective that coding is pattern-matching removes (at least some of) that frustration, tames those desperate cries to the universe, and empowers my progress rather than prohibits it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;but-what-does-pattern-matching-for-coding-even-mean&quot;&gt;But &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; does pattern-matching for coding even mean?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you get hung up on “understanding” all of the concepts. And, of course, that’s important. But you shouldn’t be stuck on learning the same thing over and over in the attempt to &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; understand something. That will come later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Pattern-matching perspective: Looking at the patterns in code and being able to replicate those patterns in other projects. You don’t have to know why the pieces work, just that they are the pieces, and how they match.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, let’s look at a JavaScript Object:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;const person = {name: 'Leslie', job:'Parks and Recreation Deputy Director', favoriteFood:'waffles'}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so maybe we need to create another person object. We don’t need to know why there are curly braces here or why there are colons. We don’t &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to know that there are keys and values. We need to recognize the pattern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we need to recognize is that there are general attribute indicators (name, job, favoriteFood), that are followed by colons and then specific information, wrapped in quotes. And all of this is wrapped in curly braces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We’re just breaking down the pieces so we can apply this in our own situation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most important lessons I’ve learned is that the more I apply the code that I’ve learned in practical ways (real world projects), the more I’m able to understand it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If someone would’ve told me that I needed to totally understand all of JavaScript before moving on to React, I would still be learning JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We shouldn’t be waiting to fully understand. Tech changes so quickly that full mastery likely won’t ever happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I’m moving into new projects, I’m taking this mindset with me. I’m looking for patterns and applying them. The next step is recognizing what we need in our coding projects by seeing the patterns in the code. And maybe that sparks an Aha! moment, like I could really use a useEffect here. Or using grid seems like a practical choice here. (But that Aha! moment deserves its own blog post.) And finally, those patterns click in our brains and we start to understand the hows and whys and whats of coding.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      
        <summary type="html">A couple of years ago I was talking to a woman who was doing simultaneous Masters degrees from Carnegie Mellon University and running a brain study on chronic depression. When we were talking about her multiple degrees and her musical experience, all while she let me pick her brain about neurology, she said something that stuck with me, “All life is pattern-matching.” She explained the connections between her mathematical and scientific experience with her creative endeavors, and it made sense. Patterns are everywhere, and we learn through recognizing and seeing the patterns, internalizing them, applying them, and eventually understanding them.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed> -->
