<!-- ---
layout: null
---
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/author/Bekah/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2023-03-03T16:34:01-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://localhost:4000/author/Bekah/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">BekahHW | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Code. Community. Feelings. It's all here.</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">How to Create a Positive Community for Your Open Source Project</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/Building-a-Supportive-Open-Source-Community" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Create a Positive Community for Your Open Source Project" />
      <published>2023-03-02T00:00:00-05:00</published>
      <updated>2023-03-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/Building%20a%20Supportive%20Open%20Source%20Community</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Building-a-Supportive-Open-Source-Community">&lt;p&gt;Over the last couple of years, I’ve spent time maintaining open source projects and an open source community. In the projects I’ve maintained and worked on, creating a positive and safe space for community members is a priority-and one that I appreciate. The people who contribute and interact with your OSS can be the backbone of your project, and cultivating a welcoming space for them is incredibly important to the health and growth of your project and users. Here are some tips to make your open source project friendly to contributors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;create-a-solid-org-level-readme&quot;&gt;Create a Solid Org-level README&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating a solid README for your organization is kind of like the prologue in a novel. In your README, you can tell the story of your project(s) and provide context to people who are interested in being a part of the community. Your README can explain who you are, what your mission is, and how people can contribute and become a part of your community. This is your chance to onboard new community members and make them feel welcomed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;onboard-new-contributors-with-individual-repo-readmes&quot;&gt;Onboard New Contributors with Individual Repo READMEs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onboarding new contributors-and doing it well-is important to your project’s success. To do this effectively, you should create a README for each individual repository. This is where you explain what the repository is all about, the technology being used, and how people can contribute. You should also provide clear guidelines for contributors of all levels, from first-time contributors to seasoned open-sourcerors. Be transparent about your level of support for new contributors, and make it clear how much support you’re able to give.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;communication-is-key&quot;&gt;Communication is Key&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clear communication is incredibly important when it comes to creating a positive experience for contributors. You should have clear paths of communication with your community members, and make sure that everyone is aware of how to get in touch with you. A couple of ways to do this include creating a contributing guide that details the process of contributing. For example, you might ask before someone raises a new issue, they start with a discussion post. If it’s determined to be a priority, the maintainers might convert it to an issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way to support positive communication includes adding issue templates to help guide contributors. You can also add Pull Request templates to make it easier for you-as a maintainer-to understand what work has been done on the repo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, it’s essential to have a clear code of conduct (COC). This creates a safe space for all of your community members to feel supported and empowered to grow. There are lots of templates available for creating a code of conduct, so you can browse through a variety of different ones to determine what works for your community. One note-if you’re using language or taking inspiration from another organization’s COC, you should provide some attribution in yours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to learn more about this, you can check out my YouTube Video &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/scE3jVz35oI&quot;&gt;Creating a Welcoming OSS Community&lt;/a&gt; or hit me up with any quesitons you have.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      
        <summary type="html">Over the last couple of years, I’ve spent time maintaining open source projects and an open source community. In the projects I’ve maintained and worked on, creating a positive and safe space for community members is a priority-and one that I appreciate. The people who contribute and interact with your OSS can be the backbone of your project, and cultivating a welcoming space for them is incredibly important to the health and growth of your project and users. Here are some tips to make your open source project friendly to contributors.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">A Year in DevRel</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/A-Year-in-DevRel" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Year in DevRel" />
      <published>2023-01-23T00:00:00-05:00</published>
      <updated>2023-01-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/A%20Year%20in%20DevRel</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/A-Year-in-DevRel">&lt;p&gt;A year ago today, I started my first job in DevRel. Before I started, I was chatting with the CEO of a consultancy, and one of the things he told me was to document publicly the work I was doing in DevRel to be transparent and have a clear record of the things I was working on. That advice has proven to be really useful over the last year, and it was one of the reasons I started the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.to/bekahhw/series/19583&quot;&gt;Technical Community Building Series&lt;/a&gt; on Dev. It’s also helped me to think through the things I’ve learned over the last year, including the challenges I’ve faced, the successes and failures I’ve had, and my takeaways for the next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;challenges&quot;&gt;Challenges&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;metrics&quot;&gt;Metrics.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I had been doing DevRel-y things the past couple of years, I hadn’t been doing the DevRel thing of tracking everything, spreadsheets, numbers, target goals, etc. Look, I &lt;em&gt;hate&lt;/em&gt; spreadsheets. Someone opens a spreadsheet and my eyes start to glaze over. However, it turns out that spreadsheets are super important in the DevRel world to help measure if things we’re doing are working, planning for the future, and breaking down projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another part of this I found really challenging was figuring out the &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt; numbers to include. “What do you think we’ll get for participation for this event?” “I have no idea, I’ve never done this before.” I’ve had to dig a lot deeper into what I know and try to make my best guesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;burnout&quot;&gt;Burnout&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the year, I took two weeks off. I hoped to do some light work with planning, drafting some blog posts, etc. What did I do instead? I got my second stomach virus in a month, and I was totally exhausted. I didn’t want to move off the couch exhausted–and that never happens to me. Strategy. Writing. Speaking. Event organizing. Twitter spaces. Social media. Planning. Meetings. Meetings. Meetings. I didn’t take breaks when I needed to during the year. I kept pushing through. And then I was so exhausting. I am happy to report that the two weeks were enough time to bring me back to life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;successes&quot;&gt;Successes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;technical-writing-blog-posts&quot;&gt;Technical Writing Blog Posts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite things I did during the year was write a series on Technical Writing for the Deepgram blog, starting with &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.deepgram.com/technical-writing-a-beginners-guide/&quot;&gt;Technical Writing: A Beginners Guide&lt;/a&gt;. The series was well recieved and combined my background as an English teacher with my new life in DevRel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;internal-community-documentation&quot;&gt;Internal Community Documentation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last couple of years, I’ve learned a lot about the importance of internal documentation. As one co-founder said to me, “you always have to be prepared if someone is in a car crash”. I know, it’s morbid, but it’s a common expression used to demonstrate the idea that there should be clear paths of communication and documentation created in case something happens to a person, myself included. If I’m no longer at Deepgram, it’s important that the processes I’ve created still live their to support their DevRel team. This includes hackathons, Twitter Spaces, Small Group Meetups, Community Discovery, and more. It’s thorough and a pretty big time investment, but it’s also an investment in the future and part of the evaluation process. What went well with this event? How can we maximize that next time? Add it to the docs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;community-engagement&quot;&gt;Community Engagement&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether it’s been in our own Deepgram properties or in other communities or at conferences, I’ve talked to a lot of people about what we do at Deepgram and how we do a really great job. One of the phrases I’ve heard repeated quite a few times is, “I wouldn’t have known about Deepgram if you didn’t work there.” That reach is hard to quantify, but getting random DMs from folks I know asking about our product has helped me know that I’m on the right track with building trust and support in the tech community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;failures&quot;&gt;Failures&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, I failed sometimes and I’m willing to admit it. This is how you grow. Look at the failures and examine &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; they’re happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hackathons&quot;&gt;Hackathons&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We didn’t get the return we wanted with the hackathons we participated in while I was on the team. I don’t think it was due to lack of opportunities, as we provided guides, resources, and live events. I underestimated a couple of things: general interest, skill level, and product interest. It can be nerve wracking to participate in a hackathon, especially one that focuses on participants working alone or maybe in pairs. Whether it’s one week or a month, there needs to be clear interest in participating in a hackathon in general. I think there’s a sweet spot for a certain skill level. Often, folks who are newer to tech hesitate a little more when getting involved, and those who have been in tech for a while on the platforms we engaged with seem to have less interest in participating in a hackathon. Finding the right audience is key to success. Lastly, as a speech-to-text API, there are very specific or limited usecases for using DG. That’s not to say that you can’t do something interesting or creative. It’s just to say that there’s a more limited use, which leads to limited user interaction as well. The key to hackathons is finding an audience who wants to use the product first. Or, like the LEGO community, having an ongoing project submission that gets voted on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;small-group-conversations&quot;&gt;Small Group Conversations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to lie. I really thought the series of three small group conversations that were followed by a Twitter Space would be popular. There are a lot of people who are asking for 1:1 meetings to talk about breaking into tech, or want to explore different parts of tech. Hundreds of people expressed interest in the topics, sign-ups were lower than that but decent, and then only a handful showed up. I think part of the problem here is that over the pandemic, we’ve gotten used to signing up for everything and then going if we feel like it. It’s kind of a bummer as an organizer, because it becomes hard to predict what attendace will look like and make something a meaningful experience. Every Tuesday and Thursday we have small group conversations at Virtual Coffee, so it fulfills my need, but I’d love to find a way to extend that experience outside of our community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;takeaways&quot;&gt;Takeaways&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find your community. I say this all the time about everything. But being able to talk to other DevRel folks really helped me get through the last year. To hear about their struggles, to learn from them, and to find more ways to grow has been invaluable to my experience.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set boundaries. That’s one of my goals for this year. Community and DevRel never stop. It’s always onto the next thing, which is one of the reasons I love it. But I frequently load up my plate a little too high and keep taking on more things. This is not good. I’ve created a Trello board to both track what I’m doing, and to give me a visual of the things I’ve taken on to decrease the chances of me overcommitting myself.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Experiment. Sometimes you get it right, sometimes you get it wrong. But what ensures success is examining what experiments worked and why and what didn’t and why. Don’t just move on to the next thing. Understand what you’ve done and the outcomes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a lot of growing pains last year, but that means I grew a lot. I learned more about what it means to be in DevRel, what my strengths are and where my weaknesses are. I learned about working on a team, asking for help, and being more vocal about the things that I think matter. Because at the end of the day, it’s people that matter. And I’m here to make sure that we see everyone as the complex and beautiful person they are.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      
        <summary type="html">A year ago today, I started my first job in DevRel. Before I started, I was chatting with the CEO of a consultancy, and one of the things he told me was to document publicly the work I was doing in DevRel to be transparent and have a clear record of the things I was working on. That advice has proven to be really useful over the last year, and it was one of the reasons I started the Technical Community Building Series on Dev. It’s also helped me to think through the things I’ve learned over the last year, including the challenges I’ve faced, the successes and failures I’ve had, and my takeaways for the next year.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Assume Best Intent</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/Assume-Best-Intent" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Assume Best Intent" />
      <published>2023-01-20T00:00:00-05:00</published>
      <updated>2023-01-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/Assume-Best-Intent</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Assume-Best-Intent">&lt;p&gt;Virtual Coffee has been through a progression of announcements about who we are and what we do. And we’re very thankful for the people who have shared when we get it wrong. One of the times we’ve gotten it wrong was when we included the phrase “assume best intent.” We wanted everyone to assume that we all supported each other, saw each other with an equal lens, and wanted the best for each other. And while that would be great, the truth is that it doesn’t always happen. I’m thankful that one of our members pointed it out to us, and I’m sorry if using that phrase negatively impacted any of our members without us knowing. We’ve since updated our language, and we ask that everyone “lead with kindness, and recognize that the impact of our words matters.” We share our Code of Conduct and our Code of Conduct violation form to ensure that there’s a clear space for folks to share their experiences where they didn’t feel safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a process. When we created this script, I thought that our members felt safe because of these words. And I’m so incredibly thankful that someone was willing to tell us that this often negatively impacted people who identified as part of a diverse group of people. In fact, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/rebekahbastian/2019/06/10/microaggressions-good-intent-is-not-good-enough/?sh=66bb3b357fb1&quot;&gt;according to Forbes&lt;/a&gt;, this language can often lead to microaggressions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;brief queries, comments or actions in day-to-day life that target marginalized groups. They are often not intended to be malicious, but over time they can lead to a toxic work environment and can preclude feelings of belonging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To assume positive intent often doesn’t take into consideration the lived experiences of people who are not like us. And when we assume positive intent, we often don’t take the time to consider the feelings of the person who is on the other side of the conversation. We may say something we believe in that (inadvertently) negatively impacts someone else on our team. We might not mean it that way, but that doesn’t mean that we shouldn’t take responsibility for our own actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, when we are made aware of our actions–and every community and company should provide a clear way to provide feedback–this is our own opportunity to make amends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It starts with listening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Listen to what others have to say without responding. 
Acknowledge what they’re saying.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take time to consider how this impacts our lives, plans, and our beliefs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Apologize fully. Full stop here. If you’re interested in learning more about how to apologize, here are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.canva.com/design/DAFURf8zW74/1tSJ0BleJFdhOdbWWAwYbg/edit?utm_content=DAFURf8zW74&amp;amp;utm_campaign=designshare&amp;amp;utm_medium=link2&amp;amp;utm_source=sharebutton&quot;&gt;the slides from my How to Apologize Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We apologize to show that we’re willing to grow, accept responsibility, and do better next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some resources, as aggregated by the Virtual Coffee Community, about the problems with using the phrase “assume positive intent”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://forge.medium.com/the-problem-with-assuming-positive-intent-ea8385ce961d&quot;&gt;The Problem with Assuming Positive Intent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mailchi.mp/82edd381b364/5-ally-actions-may-20-2022&quot;&gt;Ally Actions - May 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/rebekahbastian/2019/06/10/microaggressions-good-intent-is-not-good-enough/?sh=5e7ad817fb1d&quot;&gt;Microaggressions: good intent isn’t good enough&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Virtual Coffee, we’ve put a lot of time and effort into making our Code of Conduct  a living representation of our community. That means it represents who we are and how we believe we should treat each other right now. But, as a commitment to the community, we believe in always learning and growing, and that means we might change in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Virtual Coffee’s mission is to be a welcoming tech community that allows room for growth and mentorship at all levels and to create meaningful opportunities for learning, leadership, and contribution for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of this mission, we meet people where they are; we’re willing to listen and learn from their experiences, and we’re willing to admit when we’ve messed it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re not always going to get things right. And we’re willing to apologize when we get it wrong. Because what’s more important than what we’ve done in the past is the decisions we’re making right now to make those things right. We have a growth mindset, and we want to grow together.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      
        <summary type="html">Virtual Coffee has been through a progression of announcements about who we are and what we do. And we’re very thankful for the people who have shared when we get it wrong. One of the times we’ve gotten it wrong was when we included the phrase “assume best intent.” We wanted everyone to assume that we all supported each other, saw each other with an equal lens, and wanted the best for each other. And while that would be great, the truth is that it doesn’t always happen. I’m thankful that one of our members pointed it out to us, and I’m sorry if using that phrase negatively impacted any of our members without us knowing. We’ve since updated our language, and we ask that everyone “lead with kindness, and recognize that the impact of our words matters.” We share our Code of Conduct and our Code of Conduct violation form to ensure that there’s a clear space for folks to share their experiences where they didn’t feel safe.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">We All Need Good Feedback</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/We-All-Need-Good-Feedback" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="We All Need Good Feedback" />
      <published>2022-11-27T00:00:00-05:00</published>
      <updated>2022-11-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/We%20All%20Need%20Good%20Feedback</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/We-All-Need-Good-Feedback">&lt;p&gt;When you touch a hot surface, you get feedback when your hand hurts. When you hug someone you care about and who cares about you, those warm feelings are feedback. When you get a like on your post, that’s a type of feedback. Feedback helps you to learn not to touch the burner, to connect you to other people who care about you too, and to decide who to write for. Feedback helps us all to grow, and that’s why it should be built into our processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-feedback&quot;&gt;What is Feedback?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, so this isn’t a difficult question. But, I think many people think it’s getting advice on how to change or just about the mistakes they’ve made. And although that can be part of it, feedback encompasses more than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Feedback is when you receive a response for something you’ve done or created. This can include positive feedback, ways to improve, and also negative responses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-teaching-taught-me-about-feedback&quot;&gt;What Teaching Taught me about Feedback&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest parts of teaching is giving feedback. In graduate school, I wrote ten to thirty-page research papers and often received one to three pages of feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a teacher, I would provide feedback on students’ rough drafts throughout their papers and overall feedback at the end of their papers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point of giving writers thorough feedback was to help them to learn more about their strengths so they could continue to lean into them, discover where they can improve, and to understand the steps they could take to improve on their weaknesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At its core, feedback is given to help someone grow. And the problem with not getting feedback is that it becomes much harder to grow, gauge your progress, and improve. This is why it’s so essential to build feedback into your projects. Not only is it helpful to get feedback, but it’s also important to give feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;giving-good-feedback&quot;&gt;Giving Good Feedback&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; to give good feedback takes time, but here are some tips to get you started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;give-honest-feedback&quot;&gt;Give Honest Feedback&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No one wins if you’re not honest. Remember, the purpose of feedback is to help the other person to grow and improve. If you’re not honest, you’re not giving the person receiving the feedback the opportunity they deserve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;give-feeback-in-a-way-its-best-received&quot;&gt;Give Feeback in a way it’s Best Received&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not everyone accepts feedback in the same form. Find out the best way to provide feedback for each person you’re giving feedback to. It might be written, oral, synchronous conversation, or a combination of methods. Timing is also important. The person should expect feedback is coming. If they’re not expecting it, you’re creating a scenario where they may be resistant or even unable to accept feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;be-specific&quot;&gt;Be Specific&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;positive-feedback&quot;&gt;Positive Feedback&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not This&lt;/strong&gt;: This is great!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do This&lt;/strong&gt;: This is great because you’ve clearly outlined what we should expect to learn by the end of this talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The revision of feedback ensures the speaker realizes that a strength is that a clear purpose statement helps the audience to better follow and understand the talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;negative-feedback&quot;&gt;Negative Feedback&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not This&lt;/strong&gt;: “I don’t understand.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do This&lt;/strong&gt;: I don’t understand how this example demonstrates what you’re asserting above. Can you explain you X relates to Y?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This improved example gives the writer a clearer idea of what you don’t understand and where they need to clarify.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;provide-an-opportunity-for-discussion&quot;&gt;Provide an Opportunity for Discussion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback shouldn’t be a one-way street. For the full benefits of feedback, discussion is essention because it gives the other person the opportunity to ask clarifying questions, to be able to go deeper into the feedback, and even to get support for developing a plan for improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-prime-for-effective-feedback&quot;&gt;How to Prime for Effective Feedback&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the situation and environment isn’t right, even the best feedback can become ineffective. In order to create the best situation for everyone, do your best to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;be empathetic;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;be honest;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;be trusted by the person;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;be consistent in your feedback and your expectations;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;be respectful;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;be private-public feedback can feel like a public shaming;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;give clear expectations at the onset of the project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Giving feedback isn’t easy. It’s especially not easy if you’re working in a space that’s not psychologically safe, where there’s not a built-in process, and where most of the experience with feedback has revolved around negative responses. Giving good feedback takes time, empathy, and care. But ultimately, when we do make it a deliberate part of the process, and we take a person-first approach; we all benefit and are better able to grow together from the experience.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      
        <summary type="html">When you touch a hot surface, you get feedback when your hand hurts. When you hug someone you care about and who cares about you, those warm feelings are feedback. When you get a like on your post, that’s a type of feedback. Feedback helps you to learn not to touch the burner, to connect you to other people who care about you too, and to decide who to write for. Feedback helps us all to grow, and that’s why it should be built into our processes.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Career Goal Setting</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/Career-Goal-Setting" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Career Goal Setting" />
      <published>2022-11-25T00:00:00-05:00</published>
      <updated>2022-11-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/Career%20Goal%20Setting</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Career-Goal-Setting">&lt;p&gt;I’m close to completing my first year on a Developer Relations team. As I evaluate my own performance over the last year and set goals for my next year as a Technical Community Builder, I wanted to share how I’ve broken down my self-evaluation and goal setting. I don’t think you need to be on a DevRel team to find this useful. Based off of my responses to these questions, I’d like to work on creating self-evaluation points and put them in my calender during the next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;self-evaluation&quot;&gt;Self-evaluation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take some time to write down as much as you want for each of these questions. Remember, it’s important to be honest with yourself. You don’t have to show this to anyone. This is just for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-are-your-strengths&quot;&gt;What are your strengths?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can be measurable: I can get a blog post written really quickly, as demonstrated by my four published posts in the last four weeks. But don’t limit yourself to traditionally measurable things: My gut reaction is often right.  And in some cases, it might be something that you consider a strength that others might not: I take my time to make sure I’ve explored a variety of perspectives before jumping into a new initiative. Some people might think this process requires too much time and isn’t necessary. For this exercise, we don’t care about them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-are-your-weaknesses&quot;&gt;What are your weaknesses?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This might be the hard part for you. Think about what impacts your day-to-day work. I want to emphasize here that weakness doesn’t mean failure. Weakness is an opportunity to improve. For example, I think one of my weaknesses is creating technical blog posts really quickly. Maybe this is a part of my background in English education or years of writing screenplays or, maybe it’s a part of me being an introvert, but I really like taking time to think through the story I’m telling, to keep my audience engaged, and create something meaningful. It’s much easier for me to create something that I’m invested in because it’s meaningful. I’m not great at writing pieces that I’m not invested in. But realistically, this is part of devrel, so I have to find a way to get better at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;where-do-you-thrive&quot;&gt;Where do you Thrive?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only understanding where you thrive will be good for you, but it will also be good to share with your manager as well. It’s your manager’s job to figure out how to utilize your strengths as part of the job. It’s your job to share what you think those strengths are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, it’s easier for me to identify my weaknesses rather than my strengths. But I’m also super lucky to be part of a great community where I can ask people what they think my strengths are. I can say that I think communicating my ideas are a strength, thinking through ideas, identifying my/our target audience, writing about what I’m passionate about, and educating others are part of my strengths. I’ve been able to identify these as strengths based on past experiences where I’ve received feedback from my superiors in different job situations. Feedback is often a gift.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really thrive when there are clear expectations. Actually, I’d say a weakness is ambiguous situations where there are no clear goals or growth journeys.  I want to know where I can grow and think about how to break down the steps to that growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-do-i-need-to-succeed&quot;&gt;What do I Need to Succeed?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all need something different. For me, I need feedback. Feedback allows me to better understand how to grow, improve, and be consistent. It’s hard to be motivated to improve if you don’t know how to improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-do-i-want-to-be-doing-more-of&quot;&gt;What do I Want to be Doing More of?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This often builds on your strengths and weaknesses, but it doesn’t have to. There might be something that hasn’t made it onto the list that you want to do more of. I spent tens years in teaching before moving over to tech. I’ve been here about 3.5 years. I didn’t realize it would happen, but I miss teaching right now. I miss the development of the course materials. I miss having discussions with students, and learning and growing with each other. I miss the sense of completion at the end of the semester. I’d love to feel the same reward I did when I was teaching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-i-want-to-be-doing-less-of&quot;&gt;What I want to be doing less of?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What sucks your energy? What makes you feel ineffective? What are the things in your calendar that make you feel like you’ve been wasting your time? Well, you may have read my [Making Better Meetings] (https://dev.to/bekahhw/making-better-meetings-469m) post and this is a big part of what I want to decrease in the next year. I want meaningful meetings with clear agendas, that are within my work hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also spend a lot of times answering DMs with the same questions. I can’t do this next year. I have four kids who are growing so fast, and I don’t have extra time to take away from them. My goal is to blog about the most common questions I receive to share with those who DM me. I’d love to be able to DM everyone back, but at this stage of my life I don’t have the capacity. I have to draw boundaries if I want to be successful next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-three-areas-i-want-to-improve-in&quot;&gt;What are Three Areas I want to Improve in?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, now I’m getting into the goal setting aspect of this. Where do I want to improve?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Public Speaking
I’m nervous every time I speak in public. Some talks I’m better than in others. This year I gave so many brand new talks and that’s not every something I want to repeat again. I think I’ve had 8 next talks in the last year. I don’t want to write a new talk in 2023. I want to improve my speaking ability, be authentic, and stay on topic. For me, it’s important to not over prepare. It’s important to me to deliver the talk with authentic emotion. I’ll continue to apply to conferences, but I think the four talks I’ll focus on in the next year:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to Apologize&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do You Really Need a Community&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Person-Centered Approach to Tech&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Power of Storytelling
To be honest, I’m in love with each of these topics. I think that makes me more effective. I can share what I’m passionate about  in a way that other people can learn from the experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;creating-boundaries&quot;&gt;Creating Boundaries&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do a really bad job of turning off work. My husband suggested I limit the post-work times I talk about work and I think it’s a good idea. Work and community strategy shouldn’t consume my thoughts all the time. In fact, I think I’d be more effective if I didn’t think about it all the time. Allowing yourself to be deliberate with what you think about is incredibly important in working towards a peaceful life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;balancing-time&quot;&gt;Balancing Time&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems like in DevRel, there’s never enough time. There’s the next thing and endeavor. So you don’t have time to improve, grow, reassess. Next year, I’ll be focused on how I can continue to grow, learn, and support others in a way that’s reasonable for me and my family. I can’t feel like I’m always working. And it’s not fair to them to feel like they come second to a slack message. But I have to be effective during working hours. This means that I want to allot a certain amount of time to each of my main tasks during the week and make sure that I don’t prevent myself from fulfilling those tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-your-2022-highlights&quot;&gt;What are Your 2022 Highlights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This builds off of your strengths, but it requires you to be more specific. Think about the things you did, that you feel made an impact in the last year. To be honest, this is really hard for me. What makes it worse it that the last quarter of the year, I’ve been struggling to feel like I’m helping, impacting, or supporting anyone. This is certainly an argument for building in retros for your projects. If you keep track of them as you work through them, it’s easier to remember them at the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m still working on this section, but I’d love to hear what your highlights are!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;career-aspirations&quot;&gt;Career Aspirations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So many of our goals are tied to what we see in our nearby future. At some point we need to look at the bigger future and our life outside of our job. What do we want our career to look like? How can we tie all the things we’ve worked on above to be a part of our career? How does our idea of our career differ from the job we have/want now?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, I would love to keynote a conference. This ties into my goals for what I want to do more of, but does’t exactly tie into what I’m doing now. If I don’t become a keynote speaker in the next year, my team isn’t going to negatively judge my progress, but I’ll realize that I haven’t put in the work to meet my personal goals. So right now, I need to create a list of steps that will help me to actualize those goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And for this part of your growth plan, you should think about your goals and how you can break them down to meet your career aspirations. There’s nothing wrong with identifying your growth plan and following it as you move forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you evaluate yourself, your progress, and your goals, consider what might be immediate to today and what might change. How will you adapt to change? What’s important to you as you work to make change a good experience? How will you take your needs into 2023 and break down those goals? How will you track those goals? Hopefully, after I’ve broken down my goals, I’ll post and do check-ins over the next year. If you want accountability for your own goals, let me know. My first DevRel planning and goal-setting session is this coming week, but I’m always down to do async sessions.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      
        <summary type="html">I’m close to completing my first year on a Developer Relations team. As I evaluate my own performance over the last year and set goals for my next year as a Technical Community Builder, I wanted to share how I’ve broken down my self-evaluation and goal setting. I don’t think you need to be on a DevRel team to find this useful. Based off of my responses to these questions, I’d like to work on creating self-evaluation points and put them in my calender during the next year.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Moms, you’re carrying a lot of plates</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/Moms,-you're-carrying-a-lot-of-plates" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Moms, you're carrying a lot of plates" />
      <published>2021-11-30T00:00:00-05:00</published>
      <updated>2021-11-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/Moms,%20you're%20carrying%20a%20lot%20of%20plates</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Moms,-you're-carrying-a-lot-of-plates">&lt;p&gt;I see you moms. You’re carrying a lot of plates. Your children. Your work. Your family. Your life. Everything. You are carrying more plates than anyone should expect to carry. I know it’s &lt;em&gt;hard&lt;/em&gt;. I know it feels like you aren’t doing a good job at any of those things. But the truth is you’re amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re carrying those plates and they are &lt;em&gt;heavy&lt;/em&gt;. And you’re still pushing forward. You’re tired. I know. It’s exhausting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will get stronger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But you also have to learn how to hand off some of those plates. You have to know when you’ve tried too much weight and when adding one more will be the one that will strain you too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a mother, your identity shifts. You have another human or humans to care for. Your understanding of who you are will change. Your priorities will change. Your past self is a part of who you are, but it’s not &lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt; you are anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you’re awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now I’m going to do my favorite thing and mix metaphors:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to learn how to weed your garden. The things that don’t enrich the soil? Gone. The things that strangle the fruit? Gone. The things that help the plants but only in small doses? Regulate. Protect your garden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Protect yourself. If you give and you give and you give all day long, you are depleting yourself. There will be nothing left to give at some point. You have to find the things that enrich your life so that you can give when you need to. It is ok to take a walk by yourself. It is ok to ask for alone time. It is ok to go to the gym. It is ok to do something that you–and only you–enjoy doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because that’s the thing, you have to care for yourself or eventually no one will be cared for. You can’t be empty and continue to give. When you do that, you move on the negative axis; you accumulate exhaustion, frustration, anxiety, resentment, anger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear moms out there, I encourage you to find things that enrich your lives, to eliminate the things and people who deplete you, and to communicate your frustrations, your emptiness, loneliness, anxieties, to those close to you. To ask others to carry some of your plates. To find communities who can support you. To let yourself &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; your feelings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know if it’s ever &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; hard to be a mom. But I do know that when we allow &lt;em&gt;our&lt;/em&gt; needs to go unmet, we’re heading down a dangerous path. Prioritize. Minimize. Optimize. Boundaries–ok, I just wanted to make that one fit. The point is, don’t try to do everything, master the art of “no,” and let people know when they’ve asked too much of you. Don’t let them minimize your feelings or persuade you that your feelings are wrong. Let that be your red flag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve got you, moms. Make sure you’re enriching yourself too.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      
        <summary type="html">I see you moms. You’re carrying a lot of plates. Your children. Your work. Your family. Your life. Everything. You are carrying more plates than anyone should expect to carry. I know it’s hard. I know it feels like you aren’t doing a good job at any of those things. But the truth is you’re amazing.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">What the heck does it mean to make an image a tensor?</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/What-the-heck-does-it-mean-to-make-an-image-a-tensor" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What the heck does it mean to make an image a tensor?" />
      <published>2021-11-29T00:00:00-05:00</published>
      <updated>2021-11-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/What%20the%20heck%20does%20it%20mean%20to%20make%20an%20image%20a%20tensor</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/What-the-heck-does-it-mean-to-make-an-image-a-tensor">&lt;p&gt;So we’ve learned about &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.to/bekahhw/hello-tensor-52ed&quot;&gt;what a tensor is&lt;/a&gt;, and we know a little bit about &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.to/bekahhw/youre-toxic-using-the-toxicity-model-with-tensorflowjs-5h27&quot;&gt;what you can do with them&lt;/a&gt;, but why the heck would we want to turn an image into a tensor? Well, if we want to use them with TensorFlow.js or for Deep Learning, then we change them to tensors to put them in a useable form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we think about images, we know they’re made of pixels. Together, those small units create an image. Each of these pixels holds a position in the image, and each pixel can be represented by an array of three numbers that correspond with an &lt;a href=&quot;https://css-tricks.com/almanac/properties/c/color/&quot;&gt;RGB (red, green, blue) value&lt;/a&gt; that represents a color.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, for example, if we look at the rgb value (0, 255, 255), we’ll see aqua. Now, you might see a fourth value, and that stands for the transparency of the pixel. That fourth value–the alpha parameter–allows you to set a number between 0.0 (transparent) and 1.0 (opaque). Take that aqua color. If we add an alpha parameter of 0, it will be fully transparent and we won’t be able to see it. If we add .5, then it will be at a middle point for transparency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we transform an image into a tensor, each of those pixels in the position they hold in the image, get transformed into tensors. Once we transform these tensors, we can train our models with this data, among other things. We can mirror images, resize, crop, and manipulate in other ways that are useful to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say that we’re &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.com/&quot;&gt;Air BnB&lt;/a&gt;. We want to be able to quickly look through the images our hosts have submitted but haven’t labeled, so we can provide labels for those images. We know that &lt;em&gt;most&lt;/em&gt; of the properties will have bathrooms. What’s the easiest way to identify a bathroom? If you said by toilets, I would say that you’re right. So we need our image classification to know what a toilet looks like. But not everyone has the same toilet, in the same position, and/or has taken the picture from the same angle. To increase accuracy, we need data taken from different angles, with different size images of toilets, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One way to augment your data is to take an image, like a toilet, and apply a method like &lt;a href=&quot;https://js.tensorflow.org/api/latest/#reverse&quot;&gt;.reverse( )&lt;/a&gt; to the image. By reversing the image to add to our dataset, we have doubled our dataset and made it more reliable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s simplify the steps you need to get there. Let’s imagine that we have an image of a toilet that we have stored in the variable toiletImg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, we’ll convert that image into a tensor–for the example, we’ll grab it from the browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;const toiletTensor = tf.browser.fromPixels(toiletImg)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we have a tensor, but we want to reverse the image:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tf.reverse(toiletImg, 1)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll notice that I have a 1 there. What’s that for? That second parameter indicates that we want to flip the axis that holds the pixels for the &lt;em&gt;width&lt;/em&gt; of the image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one example of what you can do, &lt;em&gt;but&lt;/em&gt; I wasn’t making up the AirBnB example. They have &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/airbnb-engineering/categorizing-listing-photos-at-airbnb-f9483f3ab7e3&quot;&gt;used image classification to help them identify images&lt;/a&gt;. Can you imagine how much time that saved them? There’s a lot of power in Machine Learning, image classification, and possibilities that have been explored and remain to be explored. But you always start with the basics. Let yourself be inspired and then take it one day at a time. And if you’re interested in learning more, check out my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twitch.tv/bekahhw/&quot;&gt;livestreams on TFJS on Tuesday afternoons at 1pm est&lt;/a&gt; or let me know if you want to join our study group on Friday afternoons at 1pm est!&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      
        <summary type="html">So we’ve learned about what a tensor is, and we know a little bit about what you can do with them, but why the heck would we want to turn an image into a tensor? Well, if we want to use them with TensorFlow.js or for Deep Learning, then we change them to tensors to put them in a useable form.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Dear Senior Devs, Use your privilege</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/Dear-Senior-Devs,-Use-your-privilege" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dear Senior Devs, Use your privilege" />
      <published>2021-11-28T00:00:00-05:00</published>
      <updated>2021-11-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/Dear%20Senior%20Devs,%20Use%20your%20privilege</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Dear-Senior-Devs,-Use-your-privilege">&lt;p&gt;Dear Senior Devs,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use your privilege. As privileged tech community members, it’s your job to help fight the gatekeepers on your teams. It is your job to make space at the table for those who have been kept out. To hand the mic to those who are silenced. To allow for a pause in the conversation to ask if there anyone wants to add something to the conversation when you realize that the only people who have contributed to the conversation are the other people of privilege at the table. To recognize our own complicity and remember that unintentional gatekeeping is still gatekeeping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gatekeepers, at the very core, are people or organizations that prevent people from achieving their goals. There are a lot of ways gatekeeping happens–I have a talk that goes through a lot more than this post–but I’m going to focus on &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; senior+ developers can work to prevent gatekeeping on their teams. As the saying goes, you’re as strong as your weakest link. If there is a person on your team who is not supported, who doesn’t have the opportunity to ask questions, who isn’t provided an environment with a growth-mindset, your team suffers in more ways than one. To be honest, I’m most concerned with the impact of that environment on the whole team. Because teams who don’t feel supported are less likely to grow, to innovate, to maintain strong mental health. I’m concerned about the impact on the individuals, especially those who don’t feel seen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If someone is spoken to negatively on the team, use your privilege. There’s a difference between honest feedback and condescending feedback. When the latter happens, stand up for those people on your team. If you are silent, you set the tone: you’re not willing to stand up for someone when they’re being poorly treated. It’s still a sin if it’s a sin of omission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve allowed gatekeeping behavior to happen and not taken action, apologize and don’t do it again. Unintentional gatekeeping happens. Realizing we’ve made a mistake happens. Apologize, but more importantly, take action and make changes so you don’t do it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listen. There will come a time for everyone where we start to forget what it’s like to be new. And for most new developers, it’s exhausting to try to break into tech, let alone do it while fighting off people who want to keep you out. And here’s the thing: for most of us, those encounters aren’t a one-time thing. We face them again and again and those experiences sometimes create a fear that doesn’t leave us. Ask about other’s experiences so you can broaden your vision of the world. Ask how they can better be supported. And do research yourself to see how you can support your team members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever we make someone feel like they aren’t part of the group or that they’re not &lt;em&gt;as valuable&lt;/em&gt; as other members of the group, we’re being gatekeepers, whether or not it’s intentional. When you’re using acronyms or jargon, always define it first. And don’t precede it with the statement, “In case you didn’t know” or “For those of you who don’t know” because you’re creating a separation in the community, an us–the people who are in the inner circle–and them–the people who are outside of our circle. Don’t interrupt others or assume we know others’ questions or intentions. If you allow someone to feel unwelcome because you don’t want to feel uncomfortable, you’re a gatekeeper. So use your privilege to create a supportive and cohesive team.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      
        <summary type="html">Dear Senior Devs,</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Hello, Tensor!</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/Hello-Tensor!" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello, Tensor!" />
      <published>2021-11-22T00:00:00-05:00</published>
      <updated>2021-11-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/Hello%20Tensor!</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Hello-Tensor!">&lt;p&gt;So we’ve been using the word tensor, just throwing it around, but now we’re going to learn a little more about it. You don’t &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to understand everything. This isn’t an in depth exploration of what tensors are or a debate about whether the mathematical definition of tensors versus the computer science definition of tensors. Understanding enough to know &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; you can use tensors should be the goal here, so a basic understanding can allow us to do a better job of using tensors in our development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-tensors&quot;&gt;What are tensors?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tensors are collections of data in a structured type that are optimized as numbers to be ready for calculations. They’re similar to working with multidimensional arrays in JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We use tensors because they can do calculations quickly; they’re created to do many side by side calculations at once and can batch process at high speeds. They also provide us with direct access to data in a useable format. Outside of Machine Learning, there are libraries that use tensors for images, sound, 3d models, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tensors have a rank, shape, and datatype (dtype). According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tensorflow.org/js/guide/tensors_operations&quot;&gt;TensorFlow.js Tensors and operations&lt;/a&gt;, these can be defined as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;rank: defines how many dimensions the tensor contains&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;shape: which defines the size of each dimension of the data&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;dtype: which defines the data type of the tensor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can check what each tensor is by calling the tensor method. If you want to follow along and experiment with tensors, you can fork and use my &lt;a href=&quot;https://codesandbox.io/s/hello-tensor-tfjs-sandbox-dodb3&quot;&gt;Hello Tensor Sandbox&lt;/a&gt;. Inside the sandbox, the only changes you’ll need to make are in &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;src &amp;gt; index.js&lt;/code&gt;. Most of your changes will be to line 5, subbing in the data you’re experimenting with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EXAMPLE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Import * as tf from &quot;@tensorflow/tfjs&quot;;

 const tensorExample =  [1, 2, 3]
	console.log(tf.tensor(tensorExample))
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we check the console, we’ll see a lot of information there. For the purpose of this blog, we’ll go through the three properties defined above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;rankType: “1”
Shape: Array(1) &amp;gt; 0:3
dataType: “float32”
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what does that mean?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ranktype&quot;&gt;RankType&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know that the rank has one dimension. But what is a dimension? Each array has a dimension. Because we only have a single array, it’s a rank 1, a flat dataset. We need only a single index to access the data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we have a rankType of “2”, that means that we have an array of arrays, and we need two indexes to access this data. In other words, we have an x and y coordinate here, and also called a rank-2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;const twoDimensionArray = [ [2,3], [5,6], [7,8] ]
console.log(twoDimensionArray([0,0])
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you think the answer is here?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you guessed [2,3], you’d be correct! Our first indexed array is the outer array. The second, or y-coordinate, refers to the inner arrays. In this case, it’s the [2,3] array.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if we wanted to get [7,8], we would do that by twoDimensionArray([0,2]).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;shape&quot;&gt;Shape&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a single array like in the original example ( const tensorExample = [1, 2, 3]), and if we check the array at the 0 index, we see that there are three items in the array.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, let’s look at a new example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;const = newArray
[
    [
     [2, 3, 9, 0],
     [5, 6, 9, 8]
    ],
    [
      [7, 8, 4, 3],
      [1, 2, 4, 9]
    ],
    [
      [7, 8, 2,1],
      [1, 2, 0,7]
    ]
  ];
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we’d have a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;shape: Array(3)&lt;/code&gt;. And if we expand that, we see:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;0 : 3
1 : 2
2 : 4
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the first index [0] in the array, is the outer array, which contains three arrays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the second index [1] in the array, is the middle set of arrays. Within that set, they contain two sets of arrays, hence the 2. So if we console.log(newArray[0,0]), we get [ 2, 3, 9, 0] and [5, 6, 9, 8].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the last index [2] in the array, is the most inner and that’s the four numbers we see in the inner arrays. And that’s where we get [5, 6, 9, 8].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we need to change the shape of a tensor, we can use the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;reshape&lt;/code&gt; method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;datatype&quot;&gt;DataType&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DataType, or as it’s printed in the console &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;dType&lt;/code&gt; , is a “float32.” This is the default dataType for tensors. If we need to create our tensor in a different form, we can also use bool, int32, complex64, and string.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on your goals, you might need to use a different form, and there’s a way to specify the type that you need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might seem like a lot, but remember these are the basics for understanding so you can use tensors to do some really magical things. And if you’ve walked through these examples and tried them out for yourself, you’ve created your very first tensor. Hello, Tensor!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tensorflow.org/js/guide/tensors_operations&quot;&gt;TensorFlowjs Guide&lt;/a&gt; -&lt;a href=&quot;https://infinite.red/learn-tensorflowjs&quot;&gt;Learn TensorFlow.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="TFJS" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">So we’ve been using the word tensor, just throwing it around, but now we’re going to learn a little more about it. You don’t have to understand everything. This isn’t an in depth exploration of what tensors are or a debate about whether the mathematical definition of tensors versus the computer science definition of tensors. Understanding enough to know how you can use tensors should be the goal here, so a basic understanding can allow us to do a better job of using tensors in our development.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">A Note to Devs Looking for Their First Job</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/A-Note-to-Devs-Looking-for-Their-First-Job" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Note to Devs Looking for Their First Job" />
      <published>2021-11-19T00:00:00-05:00</published>
      <updated>2021-11-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/A%20Note%20to%20Devs%20Looking%20for%20Their%20First%20Job</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/A-Note-to-Devs-Looking-for-Their-First-Job">&lt;p&gt;It’s hard out there, new devs. I’m sorry. So many of you have been fed the fairy tale of an industry with jobs a plenty, bountiful pay, with a steep and rigorous climb that would be worth it when you hit the peak—finally ready to transition from learning to working. I’m sorry so many of you have been let down, have seen the reality of the plentiful jobs for those with 3+ years of experience, the rat race for the available entry-level jobs, and the toxic environments preying on new developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sorry you’ve felt that pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that for many it’s hard to land your first job. It can feel soul-crushing. The interview processes are worse than the standardized tests they made us take in high school. We’re back to impracticality, unnaturally pressurized situations, and a poor indication of how we’ll communicate with our teammates, how we’ll learn as we go, of our abilities to offer new and diverse opinions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And for those of you who land your first jobs in tech and find yourself unsupported, neglected, and feeling like you provide no value in your job, I am sorry. You deserve to have guidance, support, and mentorship. You deserve to be provided with the tools that will allow you to grow. You deserve to be acknowledged for your work, to be encouraged to grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A team should work to cultivate talent, to create a safe space where you are willing to put yourself out there, to get out of your comfort zone. If you are afraid to share or to ask questions, then you have been let down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are good people and teams and communities in tech that are invested in holding the door open for you, in making space for hard and honest conversations that will help you to grow, in creating pathways for you so you aren’t dropped into a new world with no map, no tools, no direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are good companies and teams that realize they don’t have the capacity or structure to support early career developers and admit that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You deserve to know that you will be supported. Ask that question in the interview. Please ask how they’ll support you as an early career developer. Please ask them how they communicate as a team. Please ask them what their approach is to honest, but hard conversations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please open yourself up to honest, but hard-to-hear feedback. Please remember that you are not at the top of the mountain yet, you are just starting the climb and it’s going to feel hard no matter what. But there’s a difference between growing pains and the pain of neglect. You are the hero in your journey, but every hero needs a mentor. It might not be a Yoda, it might be a community, it might be the wisdom you catch in a podcast, it might be a blogpost you read. Most of us are not out there to slay dragons by ourselves. We’re there to combine our skills, our strengths, to level each other up, to be the team that does it together.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="TFJS" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">It’s hard out there, new devs. I’m sorry. So many of you have been fed the fairy tale of an industry with jobs a plenty, bountiful pay, with a steep and rigorous climb that would be worth it when you hit the peak—finally ready to transition from learning to working. I’m sorry so many of you have been let down, have seen the reality of the plentiful jobs for those with 3+ years of experience, the rat race for the available entry-level jobs, and the toxic environments preying on new developers.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed> -->
