<!-- ---
layout: null
---
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/author/Bekah/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2025-11-12T14:19:04-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://localhost:4000/author/Bekah/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">BekahHW | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Code. Community. Content.</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">The Invisible Load: How AI Workflows Can Replace Your Team’s ‘Glue Person’</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/AI-Workflows-Can-Be-The-Glue" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Invisible Load: How AI Workflows Can Replace Your Team's 'Glue Person'" />
      <published>2025-11-06T00:00:00-05:00</published>
      <updated>2025-11-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/AI%20Workflows%20Can%20Be%20The%20Glue</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/AI-Workflows-Can-Be-The-Glue">&lt;p&gt;Every team has one, and, tbh, a lot of relationships have one. The person who remembers. For teams, it might be the person who remembers to update the changelog. Who posts the weekly standup summary. Who follows up on that GitHub issue from three weeks ago. Who makes sure the docs match the latest release. Who bridges the gap between what engineering ships and what the rest of the company knows about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We call this “glue work,” and research shows it disproportionately falls on women in teams, and mothers in relationships. It’s the invisible labor that keeps everything running smoothly, but rarely shows up in performance reviews or promotion discussions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is that glue work is essential, but it shouldn’t be someone’s primary job. And it definitely shouldn’t be the reason talented people get passed over for advancement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what if AI workflows could be the glue instead?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-glue-work-problem&quot;&gt;The Glue Work Problem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tanya Reilly’s essay &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.noidea.dog/glue/&quot;&gt;“Being Glue”&lt;/a&gt; describes how critical but undervalued work like coordinating between teams, translating technical concepts, maintaining documentation, ensuring follow-through often becomes invisible. The people who do it often make everything seem easy. But there’s a cost, and it’s compounding in the background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have one teammate who’s spending hours each week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Updating tickets after standups&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Posting release summaries to Slack&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Making sure customer support knows about new features&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chasing down PR reviews&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Updating documentation after merges&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Following up on blocked issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;when none of this is their actual job, then they may be your “glue.” All of it is necessary. But when they stop doing it, things fall apart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it doesn’t seem that bad right now, but coordination work compounds as teams grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-if-workflows-could-be-the-glue&quot;&gt;What If Workflows Could Be the Glue?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where composed AI workflows change everything. Not because they eliminate coordination work, but because they automate it at the seams between tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his post on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/individual-workflows-scale-linearly-composed-compound-chad-metcalf-x7fyc&quot;&gt;composed workflows&lt;/a&gt;, Continue CEO Chad Metcalf makes an important distinction: a single workflow saves time, but composed workflows compound. When the output of one workflow can trigger the next, you’re doing more than just automating individual tasks. You’re automating the entire coordination system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at what this actually means.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;example-1-the-release-communication-burden&quot;&gt;Example 1: The Release Communication Burden&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current state:&lt;/strong&gt; After every release, someone (usually the same someone) needs to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Draft changelog entries&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Update product documentation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Post to company Slack&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Update customer-facing docs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create support team briefing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Close related Linear issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That “someone” spends 2-3 hours per release on coordination work. Not working on more impactful work. Just making sure everyone knows what shipped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With composed workflows:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Merge to main 
  → Extract changes from PR descriptions 
  → Draft changelog entry 
  → Update technical docs 
  → Generate customer-facing summary 
  → Post to internal Slack 
  → Update support knowledge base 
  → Close related issues
  → Post completion summary
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entire coordination chain runs automatically. The output of one workflow triggers the next. No one spends their afternoon being glue. Instead, they become the human in the loop who reviews and improves the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;example-2-the-follow-up-tax&quot;&gt;Example 2: The Follow-Up Tax&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current state:&lt;/strong&gt; You’re in standup. Someone mentions they’re blocked on a security review. Everyone nods. The meeting ends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three days later, nothing’s happened because nobody remembered to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a ticket&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tag the security team&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Follow up when there’s no response&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Update the original ticket&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let the blocked person know it’s unblocked&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guess who remembers? The glue person, who now spends their time tracking other people’s blockers instead of writing code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With composed workflows:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&quot;Blocked on X&quot; detected in standup notes 
  → Create Linear issue with context 
  → Tag relevant team 
  → Set reminder for 2 days 
  → Follow up if no response 
  → Update original ticket when resolved 
  → Notify blocked person
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The follow-through happens automatically. Nobody has to be the memory keeper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;example-3-the-support-handoff&quot;&gt;Example 3: The Support Handoff&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current state:&lt;/strong&gt; Customer reports a bug in Slack. Engineering fixes it. But somehow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Support never gets notified the fix is live&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Customer still thinks it’s broken&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Docs don’t reflect the fix&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The original Slack thread is forgotten&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone (the glue person) ends up manually connecting all these dots. Every. Single. Time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With composed workflows:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Bug report in Slack 
  → Create Linear issue 
  → PR created and merged 
  → Update documentation 
  → Generate fix summary 
  → Post to support channel 
  → Reply to original Slack thread 
  → Close Linear issue with summary
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entire loop closes itself. From report to fix to notification to documentation to closure. No human glue required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-this-works-where-other-solutions-dont&quot;&gt;Why This Works Where Other Solutions Don’t&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;its-not-about-replacing-people&quot;&gt;It’s Not About Replacing People&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AI workflows aren’t replacing the glue person’s judgment or expertise. They’re replacing the repetitive coordination tasks that shouldn’t require judgment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a PR merges, updating the changelog doesn’t need human insight. Following up on a blocked issue after two days doesn’t require strategic thinking. Posting a deployment summary to Slack isn’t creative work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are mechanical transitions between tasks. Perfect candidates for automation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;it-compounds-over-time&quot;&gt;It Compounds Over Time&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what makes this different from other automation attempts: composition creates compounding value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each workflow you add doesn’t just save time on that specific task. It amplifies the value of workflows already running. The deployment workflow outputs information the changelog workflow needs. The Linear sync workflow triggers the documentation update workflow. The customer support workflow feeds the product insights workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re not just automating individual tasks. You’re automating the entire coordination system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;it-preserves-the-actual-value-of-glue&quot;&gt;It Preserves the Actual Value of “Glue”&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The valuable part of glue work isn’t the mechanical coordination. It’s the strategic connection-making, the pattern recognition, the ability to see across teams and translate context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When AI workflows handle the mechanical parts, the humans who were doing glue work can focus on the strategic parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They can spend time:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identifying patterns across customer feedback&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improving team processes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mentoring junior developers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Solving actually complex problems&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Advancing their technical skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The things that actually deserve their expertise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-composition-advantage&quot;&gt;The Composition Advantage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Individual workflows are helpful. Composed workflows are transformative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Chad Metcalf writes in his post on composed workflows: “Individual workflows give linear improvements. Composed workflows compound.” This distinction is crucial when thinking about how to replace organizational glue work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because here’s what happens when workflows compose: the coordination work stops being a burden on any individual. Instead, it becomes part of the system itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re not asking someone to remember to update the docs after deployment. The deployment workflow triggers the documentation workflow automatically. You’re not relying on someone to follow up on blocked issues. The standup workflow creates follow-up workflows with built-in reminders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is infrastructure that scales with your team. As you grow, the glue work compounds. But with composed workflows, the automation compounds instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;real-team-impact-beyond-time-savings&quot;&gt;Real Team Impact: Beyond Time Savings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s talk about what this actually means for teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;no-more-that-person&quot;&gt;No More “That Person”&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When coordination work is automated, it stops being concentrated on one or two people. The person who used to spend 10 hours a week on glue work can spend those hours on actual engineering. Or product work. Or whatever they were actually hired to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More importantly: they stop being the bottleneck. When knowledge and coordination flows through automated systems rather than through specific people, teams become more resilient. People can take vacation without everything falling apart. New team members can onboard without needing to know who to ask for everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;career-equity&quot;&gt;Career Equity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Glue work is often invisible during performance reviews. “Sarah keeps everything running smoothly” doesn’t translate to promotion decisions the way “shipped three major features” does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When AI workflows handle coordination, engineers can focus on work that’s more visible and valued. This has disproportionate impact on people—often women and mothers—who tend to take on more glue work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;team-velocity-at-scale&quot;&gt;Team Velocity at Scale&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Small teams can coordinate informally. “Hey, remember to update the docs” works when you’re five people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 20 people? 50? Informal coordination breaks down. You need systems. The question is: will those systems be human-dependent, automated, or composed with a human in the loop?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Composed workflows scale. Human coordination doesn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-actually-do-this&quot;&gt;How to Actually Do This&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t start by trying to automate everything. Start with the most repetitive, predictable coordination work on your team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-1-identify-your-glue-work&quot;&gt;Step 1: Identify Your Glue Work&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have an honest conversation. Ask:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What coordination tasks happen after every release?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What follow-ups consistently fall through the cracks?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Where does information get stuck between teams?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Who’s spending time on mechanical updates vs. strategic work?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Write it down. You’re looking for patterns, not one-off tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-2-build-one-workflow&quot;&gt;Step 2: Build One Workflow&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pick the most painful coordination task. The one that happens constantly and requires zero judgment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Changelog updates after merges&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Standup note distribution&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PR review reminders&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Linear ticket status syncing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Documentation updates post-deployment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Build a workflow that handles it end-to-end. Run it for a week. Measure intervention rate—how often does it need human correction?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get that intervention rate below 5%. Then move to step 3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-3-compose&quot;&gt;Step 3: Compose&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at the output of your first workflow. What happens next in the coordination chain?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your workflow posts deployment notes to Slack, what normally happens after that? Maybe documentation gets updated. Maybe customer support gets briefed. Maybe Linear tickets get closed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Build workflows for those next steps. Connect them to your first workflow’s output.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you have composition. One workflow’s completion triggers the next. The coordination chain runs automatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-4-keep-going&quot;&gt;Step 4: Keep Going&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each new workflow amplifies the ones before it. The deployment workflow feeds the documentation workflow. The documentation workflow triggers the changelog workflow. The changelog workflow posts to Slack, which triggers the customer communication workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re not just saving time on individual tasks. You’re building a system where coordination happens automatically at every transition point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-bigger-picture&quot;&gt;The Bigger Picture&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t just about efficiency. It’s about equity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When essential coordination work is visible and automated, nobody gets stuck being the invisible glue. Everyone can focus on the work they’re actually good at, the work that gets recognized and rewarded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teams that build composed AI workflows aren’t just shipping faster. They’re redistributing the coordination burden from people to systems. They’re making space for everyone to do their best work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at your team. Who’s the glue person? What would they be working on if they weren’t constantly coordinating?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the real value of composition.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="AI" />
      
        <category term="Career" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Every team has one, and, tbh, a lot of relationships have one. The person who remembers. For teams, it might be the person who remembers to update the changelog. Who posts the weekly standup summary. Who follows up on that GitHub issue from three weeks ago. Who makes sure the docs match the latest release. Who bridges the gap between what engineering ships and what the rest of the company knows about.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">When We Became What We Do: The Identity Crisis That Companies Mistook for Opportunity</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/The-Community-Identity-Crisis" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="When We Became What We Do: The Identity Crisis That Companies Mistook for Opportunity" />
      <published>2025-11-02T00:00:00-04:00</published>
      <updated>2025-11-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/The-Community-Identity-Crisis</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/The-Community-Identity-Crisis">&lt;p&gt;In March 2020, a &lt;em&gt;weird&lt;/em&gt; thing happened to how we answered the question “Who are you?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the pandemic, most of us had multifaceted identities. I was the person who went to the gym and lifted weights 6x a week, who took my kids to the park all the time, who volunteered at the school, attended the occasional book club, and who took a break by going grocery shopping on Saturday mornings. For many of us, our sense of self was distributed across multiple domains, including social, familial, recreational, and professional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-great-identity-consolidation&quot;&gt;The Great Identity Consolidation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lockdown stripped most of those identities away in a matter of weeks or even days. Even family gatherings and Sunday dinners and holiday traditions moved to Zoom calls or stopped entirely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every space where we’d embody our various identities closed. I couldn’t be “the person who deadlifted on Tuesdays” when there was no weightroom open. You can’t be “the parent who knows everyone at school” when school is a URL. You can’t be “the person who always hosts game night” when gathering is prohibited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our professional identity didn’t just persist. It intensified, because work didn’t stop. In actuality, for a lot of us it intensified or became the one thing we could control. I lost my job, but I could look for another. For many people, work-from-home meant &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; hours. Slack channels kept pinging. Standups kept happening. Deadlines didn’t pause for a pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly, “developer” or “designer” or “product manager” wasn’t just what we &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt;. It became almost the entirety of who we &lt;em&gt;were&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not by choice. By elimination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remote work intensified what researchers called “identity blur” or the breakdown of boundaries between personal and professional life. Not to mention that an entire generation of early-career professionals were doing their identity formation almost exclusively through the professional lens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-tech-communities-exploded&quot;&gt;Why Tech Communities Exploded&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This identity shift created fertile ground for professional communities to thrive in unprecedented ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developer communities, in particular, saw explosive growth. The community infrastructure was already there: Slack, Discord, forums, virtual meetups. But suddenly, these weren’t just places to ask technical questions or network for jobs. They became primary social spaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started Virtual Coffee in March of 2020, I was &lt;em&gt;desperately&lt;/em&gt; looking for &lt;em&gt;people&lt;/em&gt; after I lost my first developer job. It wasn’t supplementing my social life because it &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; my social life. The Tuesday meetups became my weekly social anchor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I wasn’t alone. Across the tech ecosystem, professional communities became all-purpose gathering spaces. The hallway track at conferences had always been valuable, but now people were craving the hallway track without the conference. They wanted the coffee shop where everyone was a developer. They wanted to belong somewhere, and professional identity was one of the few identities still accessible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-numbers-that-told-a-story&quot;&gt;The Numbers That Told a Story&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By 2021, the indicators were everywhere:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Community engagement increased&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Community programs saw increased recognition of their value&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Having an online community became more important in 2020&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Time on social and community platforms jumped dramatically&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But here’s what the numbers &lt;em&gt;weren’t&lt;/em&gt; saying: they weren’t showing that people had discovered a permanent need for professional community. They were showing that professional community was filling a vacuum left by every &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt; kind of community disappearing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Professional community wasn’t competing with other professional communities. It was competing with—and replacing—gyms, coffee shops, happy hours, hobby groups, neighborhood connections, and casual friendships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-company-gold-rush&quot;&gt;The Company Gold Rush&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies looked at those engagement numbers and saw opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you were a tech company in 2020-2021 watching developers flock to online communities, the conclusion seemed obvious: we need a community. If you were hiring and saw that developer engagement was at all-time highs, you might think: we need a community manager. I became a technical community manager because tech was primed to invest in community roles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The role that was previously a nice-to-have became a strategic imperative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies launched Slacks, Discord servers, forums, and user groups. They hired community managers, developer advocates, and DevRel teams. They built content strategies around community engagement. They measured success by the metrics they were seeing everywhere: member counts, daily active users, message volume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The logic seemed on track:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People are engaging with online communities at unprecedented levels&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Our competitors are building communities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Community drives product adoption and loyalty&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Therefore, we need to invest in community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this logic missed &lt;em&gt;context&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-substitution-effect-nobody-acknowledged&quot;&gt;The Substitution Effect Nobody Acknowledged&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What companies were observing wasn’t a permanent shift in how people want to engage with brands or products. It was a temporary substitution driven by extraordinary circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2020-2021, professional communities were standing in for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Local social connections (because we couldn’t gather)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Recreational identities (because hobbies were paused)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Casual professional networking (because conferences were canceled)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Workspace camaraderie (because offices were closed)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;General human connection (because isolation was mandatory)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The engagement wasn’t high because people suddenly valued brand communities more. It was high because professional community was the &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; community many people had access to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about it this way: if you’re working from home, can’t go to the gym, can’t meet friends for coffee, and can’t attend local meetups, where do you find people? If your identity as a weight lifter is on hold because gyms are closed, and your identity as a parent is strained because you’re homeschooling, what’s left? Your professional identity. And where do professionals gather? Online, in communities organized around their work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-success-really-looked-like&quot;&gt;What Success Really Looked Like&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies celebrated metrics that looked like success:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Our Discord hit 10,000 members!”
“Daily active users up 300%!”
“Community engagement is our highest ever!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But a lot of them were ignoring the fact that people weren’t necessarily there because your product was so compelling that they wanted to be part of your brand community. They were there because they were lonely, isolated, and craving connection, and your professional community was one of the only options available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t to diminish the genuine connections people made or the real value these communities provided. Virtual Coffee meant–and still means–the world to me. The developer communities that emerged during this time saved people’s mental health and careers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the &lt;em&gt;reason&lt;/em&gt; for that value was specific to the moment. We were all in crisis, and professional community became a lifeline not because it was uniquely better than before, but because everything else was gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;belonging-doesnt-scale-the-way-companies-hoped&quot;&gt;Belonging Doesn’t Scale the Way Companies Hoped&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But you can’t manufacture the conditions that created pandemic-era engagement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can’t make someone lonely enough to spend three hours a day in your Discord.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can’t make someone isolated enough to treat your Slack like their primary social group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can’t make someone identity-starved enough to build their sense of self around your brand community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you most definitely should not want to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the world reopened, people’s identities re-diversified. The parent identity came back with in-person school. The athlete identity returned with reopened gyms. The friend identity flourished with in-person coffee dates. The hobbyist identity resumed with craft groups and sports leagues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Professional identity didn’t disappear, but it was &lt;em&gt;one of many&lt;/em&gt; identities, not the primary or only identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But companies didn’t anticipate: people wanted to keep both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The connections made during the pandemic weren’t casual networking. They were trauma bonds. We didn’t just share technical knowledge in those slacks and Zoom rooms. We &lt;em&gt;survived&lt;/em&gt; isolation together, processed fear together, figured out how to keep going together. We saw each other at our worst: unmuted kids screaming, laundry piles stacked and thrown across the floor, tears with lost jobs. We celebrated new babies through screens. We mourned miscarriages together in the #heavy channel. We watched marriages fall apart in real-time as people processed isolation and stress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we lost people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when that happened, we couldn’t gather. We couldn’t hug each other. We couldn’t sit together at a funeral. We watched memorial services on Zoom, crying alone in our homes, typing condolences in chat windows, wishing desperately we could just &lt;em&gt;be there&lt;/em&gt; together in person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The grief was compounded by the medium. These were people who’d kept us sane, who we’d talked to nearly every day, who felt like lifelines. And when they were gone, we had to process that loss the same way we’d built the relationship, through screens, at a distance, without the physical comfort that humans need in grief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These weren’t casual professional connections. These were people who’d seen us completely, who’d held space for our fear and loneliness, who’d shared their own vulnerability in ways that rarely happen in professional contexts. The bonds formed under those conditions of shared trauma, radical vulnerability, mutual survival, don’t just dissolve when offices reopen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This wasn’t like moving to a new city and losing touch with old friends, or kids graduating so you stop seeing other parents at pickup. Those transitions are natural drift. This was different. People wanted to maintain these deep connections while returning to physical community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But time is finite. You can’t spend three hours a day in the Virtual Coffee co-working room when you’re back at an actual office. You can’t attend every virtual event when you’re back at the gym, at your kid’s school, at in-person meetups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The decline in engagement wasn’t people abandoning communities they didn’t care about. It was people being pulled between communities they cared about deeply and being forced to choose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people stayed in their pandemic communities because those bonds meant everything. Some drifted away despite wanting to stay connected. Many tried to maintain both and felt guilty about not being as present online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Professional identity didn’t disappear, but it returned to being one of many identities, not the primary or only identity. And with finite time and attention, something had to give.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-misread-that-shaped-a-strategy&quot;&gt;The Misread That Shaped a Strategy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies saw the engagement decline and treated it like a problem to solve rather than a natural consequence of changed circumstances.
The mistake wasn’t that companies built communities. Many of those communities genuinely serve people who need them, and many of those pandemic-era bonds are real and lasting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mistake was thinking they could recreate or sustain trauma-bond-level engagement without the trauma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They thought the pandemic-era engagement levels were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sustainable (Actually, many required conditions no one should want to recreate)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Universal (Actually, many were born of collective crisis)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reproducible (Actually, many were trauma bonds form under specific circumstances)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transferable (Actually, you can’t manufacture that depth of connection on command)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies built community strategies around peak crisis participation and crisis-level bonding. They staffed for engagement that made sense when professional community was substituting for all community and people were processing collective trauma together. They created expectations for involvement that assumed people’s entire social lives would continue to flow through professional channels with that same intensity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When engagement inevitably declined, it wasn’t because the communities failed. People’s lives and needs changed, and then companies panicked. They hired more community managers. They added more features. They pushed harder for participation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But you can’t solve for the absence of shared crisis with better Slack integrations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And with that shift, professional communities changed in character, not just size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many became transactional. People drop in, ask a question, get an answer, leave. They need the &lt;em&gt;resource&lt;/em&gt;, the collective knowledge, the troubleshooting help, the documentation links. But they don’t want or need the &lt;em&gt;connection&lt;/em&gt;. They’re not looking for the coffee shop vibe anymore. They’re looking for Stack Overflow with a pulse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t everyone. Remote workers still exist. Niche specialists still need their people. Global collaborators still benefit from async communication across time zones. People for whom online professional community isn’t a substitute for anything, because it’s genuinely where their professional community exists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But even within those groups, the engagement looks different. It’s purposeful, not ambient. It’s “I’m here when I need something” rather than “this is where I hang out.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then there are the community builders caught in the middle, trying to recreate that pandemic-era connection and intimacy in product-focused communities where most people just want help with their API integration. They’re hosting office hours that get three attendees. They’re planning social events that get polite “maybe” responses. They’re fighting to build connection in spaces where the majority of members are perfectly content with drive-by interactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not that these community builders are doing it wrong. &lt;em&gt;They’re trying to create depth in spaces where most people want efficiency.&lt;/em&gt; They’re optimizing for belonging when most users are optimizing for answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The communities that thrived on trauma bonds and shared vulnerability can’t be replicated in a product community where people just need their build to work. And expecting them to is setting community builders up to burn out trying to recreate something that only existed under very specific, unrepeatable conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-job-is-this-community-actually-doing&quot;&gt;What job is this community actually doing?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2020-2021, professional communities were doing the job of: general social connection, professional development, casual friendship, identity formation, and mental health support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2025, they should be doing the job of: professional knowledge sharing, specific technical support, collaboration, and professional networking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those are different jobs requiring different strategies, different staffing, and different success metrics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Communities that thrive post-pandemic aren’t trying to be everything to everyone. They’re specific about who they serve and why. They’re intentional about the value they provide. They recognize that lower engagement isn’t failure. It’s actually right-sizing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-uncomfortable-truth&quot;&gt;The Uncomfortable Truth&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not every company needs a community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if you needed one in 2020, you might not need one now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if your competitors have one, that doesn’t mean you should too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if engagement was high during the pandemic, that doesn’t mean it should be high now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The companies that will succeed with community in 2025 and beyond are the ones willing to ask: “Is this actually serving a real need, or are we chasing ghosts of pandemic-era metrics?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because belonging doesn’t scale the way we hoped. Identity doesn’t consolidate because we want it to. And crisis-driven engagement isn’t a sustainable business strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the second in a series exploring how our understanding of community has changed from 2020 to 2025. Next: How AI and changing expectations are breaking the communities that remain.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Community" />
      
        <category term="Opinion" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">In March 2020, a weird thing happened to how we answered the question “Who are you?”</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">When ‘Local’ Went Global: The Pandemic Era of International Communities</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/when-local-community-went-global" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="When 'Local' Went Global: The Pandemic Era of International Communities" />
      <published>2025-10-30T00:00:00-04:00</published>
      <updated>2025-10-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/when-local-community-went-global</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/when-local-community-went-global">&lt;p&gt;During the pandemic, I occupied the same space—a Zoom room-with members of the Virtual Coffee community from all over the world. We’ve had members across the US, Canada, South America, Europe, Australia, and Asia. We saw each other whether in an official Virtual Coffee even or eventually in our virtual co-working room that stayed open 24/7. Sometimes we’d chat. Sometimes, we’d just… exist together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the digital equivalent of running into someone in the dairy aisle, except the dairy aisle was a Zoom room, and the “someone” could be in Jakarta, São Paulo, Manchester, or Kansas City.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a brief window in modern history, “local” stopped meaning geography and started meaning something else entirely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-collapse-of-default-community&quot;&gt;The Collapse of Default Community&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before March 2020, most of us didn’t have to think much about what “community” meant. It was simply the people you saw regularly: coworkers, neighbors, your kid’s soccer team parents, the familiar faces at church or the gym. Community was embedded in the infrastructure of daily life and was predictable, physical, and largely determined by proximity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then proximity disappeared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When lockdowns began, the familiar networks evaporated overnight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The impact was immediate and profound. &lt;a href=&quot;https://connect2affect.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/The-Pandemic-Effect-A-Social-Isolation-Report-AARP-Foundation.pdf&quot;&gt;Two-thirds of adults reported experiencing social isolation during the pandemic&lt;/a&gt;. For younger adults, &lt;a href=&quot;https://mcc.gse.harvard.edu/reports/loneliness-in-america&quot;&gt;61% of young felt “serious loneliness” during this period&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We didn’t lose our desire for community. We lost the infrastructure that had been quietly supporting it all along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-great-virtualization&quot;&gt;The Great Virtualization&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What happened next wasn’t entirely new. People had been building online communities for years. But the scale and speed were unprecedented. Suddenly, everyone needed to figure out how to find belonging through a screen. When the physical infrastructure disappeared, we rebuilt it digitally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From massive pandemic hackathons to new Slack and Discord communities, people everywhere began re-creating local-belonging at scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started Virtual Coffee with weekly Tuesday meetings that were regular, predictable, and rhythmic. In a lot of ways, therapeutic. Then, the co-working room that transformed it into something that felt genuinely “local.” That room was open all the time. You could drop in whenever. You’d see who else was around. Sometimes you’d end up in a spontaneous conversation about your project, or someone’s career transition, or absolutely nothing at all.
We added a virtual book club, CodeWars challenges, and another day of coffee chats. Interintellect salons hosted three-hour events where people from diverse backgrounds came together for intellectually stimulating conversation, bridging tech and non-tech interests through Discord.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The magic was in the serendipity. The unplanned encounters. The way you’d sign on to get work done and end up chatting with someone from Nigeria about their startup idea, or find yourself in a breakout room with a developer from Russia who was working through the same frustrating bug you’d just solved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were strangers from different continents creating something that felt remarkably like what a neighborhood coffee shop might have provided. Except our “neighborhood” spanned time zones, and our “coffee shop” never closed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-made-it-work&quot;&gt;What Made It Work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back, I think the pandemic-era virtual communities that thrived shared a few key characteristics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Regularity without rigidity. You knew when things were happening, but you weren’t required to show up. The co-working room was always there. The Tuesday meetings happened every Tuesday. This created rhythm, a temporal equivalent of “I know I’ll see you at the grocery store on Saturday mornings.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Space for the unplanned. I still believe that the most meaningful connections don’t happen during structured programming. They happened in the margins: before the official meeting start, in the co-working room at odd hours, in side channels where someone posted a random question and three people end up in a deep conversation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Low barriers, high humanity. The fact that events moved online opened communities up to people who might have been too uncomfortable to attend an in-person event due to anxiety, financial constraints, or something else, allowing for realtime conversations over Slack or Discord instead of struggling with in-person social time. Nobody cared about ring lights or professional setups–ok, maybe once I learned about those things, I did invest some money to upgrade a little bit. But we still showed up in our kitchens, with kids screaming in the background, with laundry visible behind us. The bar for participation was simply: be present, be kind, be human.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shared vulnerability. We were all figuring it out together. Nobody had their shit completely sorted. That leveled the playing field in a way that’s rare in professional communities. In other words, the senior engineer and the bootcamp student/grad (ie, &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt;) were equally disoriented by the moment we were living through.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-shift-back&quot;&gt;The Shift Back&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, gradually, the physical world opened back up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People returned to offices, or to coffee shops, gyms, schools, or co-working spaces again. The default infrastructure of community came back in-person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the international local communities… shifted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The co-working room got quieter. The Tuesday meetings still happen, but attendance has thinned. Not because people stopped caring, but because they could now get some of those needs met in physical space again. Time—everyone’s most finite resource—got redistributed back to the in-person world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the pandemic, people spent the bulk of their social time at work, and remote work led to loneliness and feeling disconnected. The shared physical space offered opportunities to network, mentor others, and build community that were hard to recreate in a scattered, virtual workforce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This wasn’t a failure. It was just the natural consequence of changed circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it left a lot of questions unanswered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;where-we-are-now&quot;&gt;Where We Are Now&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re in a strange liminal space. Virtual communities haven’t disappeared, but they’re not serving the same function they did in 2020-2022. The urgency is gone. Community programs saw an increased recognition of their value during the pandemic, but that recognition was tied to a specific moment in time—a moment that has passed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People are negotiating between physical and digital belonging in ways we haven’t fully figured out yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And meanwhile, companies are asking: “Why isn’t our community as engaged as it was during the pandemic?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that’s the wrong question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The right question is: &lt;em&gt;“Who actually needs this community now, and what are we building it for?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the pandemic, virtual communities weren’t just filling a professional need. They were filling all our social needs. Professional community became a substitute for general community because it was all we had. The developer slack was my coffee shop, my gym, my after-work happy hour, my weekend hangout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that general social needs can be met locally again for many people, the population who needs online-as-local has shifted back to who it always was:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fully remote workers who’ve left physical proximity to colleagues behind entirely&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Developers who want casual peer conversation without the overhead of professional networking events&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People who want the hallway track experience (those serendipitous conversations that happen between sessions)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Specialists in niche areas where their “local” doesn’t have anyone else working on their specific stack or problem domain&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Disabled folks, caretakers, and others for whom physical gatherings have always been inaccessible&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Global collaborators building projects across continents and time zones&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People who want the coffee shop, but the coffee shop is all technies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These communities still matter deeply. They’re still someone’s local. The mistake isn’t that these communities exist—it’s that companies think everyone needs this, all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The coffee shop didn’t disappear; it just got quieter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;redefining-local-again&quot;&gt;Redefining Local, Again&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The always-on, drop-in, developer coffee shop model didn’t stop working. It just stopped being universal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2020-2022, everyone needed it because everyone was isolated. In 2025, it serves a specific population: people whose physical environment doesn’t provide the technical community they need. This isn’t new. This population always existed. The pandemic just temporarily made everyone part of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The confusion comes from companies who saw engagement numbers during lockdown and thought, “This is what community looks like now.” They built strategies around peak-crisis participation and are now wondering why engagement dropped when the crisis ended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for the people who are fully remote, who do work in niche areas, who actually need virtual-as-local? The future of virtual community isn’t choosing between “always-on” and “seasonal engagement.” It’s recognizing that different models serve different needs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Always-on spaces for people who need virtual-as-local (remote workers, niche specialists, global teams)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Event-driven communities for people who have local networks but want to expand them occasionally&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Project-based cohorts for people collaborating on specific initiatives&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hybrid models that acknowledge some members need daily presence while others drop in monthly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The brief era when local went global taught us something important about what community actually requires. Not geography. Not even, proximity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rhythm, serendipity, and the willingness to show up wherever you are and be &lt;em&gt;human&lt;/em&gt; together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those needs haven’t disappeared. But the population experiencing them has returned to its pre-pandemic size—still significant, still vital, just less universal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question now is: can we build sustainable models for the people who actually need virtual-as-local, without expecting everyone to need it all the time?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first in a series exploring how our understanding of community has changed from 2020 to 2025. Next: Why companies misread the moment and built communities for everyone when they should have built for someone. When the world redefined community, companies thought they could scale it. But belonging doesn’t scale, at least, not the way they hoped.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      
        <summary type="html">During the pandemic, I occupied the same space—a Zoom room-with members of the Virtual Coffee community from all over the world. We’ve had members across the US, Canada, South America, Europe, Australia, and Asia. We saw each other whether in an official Virtual Coffee even or eventually in our virtual co-working room that stayed open 24/7. Sometimes we’d chat. Sometimes, we’d just… exist together.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">A Developer’s Guide to Choosing an AI Coding Assistant That Boosts Productivity Without Overwhelming Your Workflow</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/Boost-Productivity-with-AI" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Developer’s Guide to Choosing an AI Coding Assistant That Boosts Productivity Without Overwhelming Your Workflow" />
      <published>2025-07-09T00:00:00-04:00</published>
      <updated>2025-07-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/Boost%20Productivity%20with%20AI</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Boost-Productivity-with-AI">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finding the assistant that fits just right.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&quot;http://virtualcoffee.io/&quot;&gt;Virtual Coffee&lt;/a&gt; over the last year, we’ve been talking about our experiences with different AI Coding Assistants.  Some of the things I’ve heard include, “It felt like I was constantly being interrupted,” “I barely notice it’s there until I need it,” “Sometimes it feels like it’s micromanaging me, so I turn it off.” A lot of times, it’s the same tool with different experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.to/bekahhw/series/32242&quot;&gt;Over the last couple of weeks, I’ve been writing about my journey to find the &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt; coding assistant&lt;/a&gt;, but I thought it would be useful to distill what I’ve learned so far into a simple guide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what I’m calling this “The Goldilocks Problem.” Some AI coding assistants are too intrusive, some are too passive, and some are just right. But that sweet spot depends entirely on you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This guide is designed to help you find an AI assistant that enhances your workflow without hijacking it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-1-understand-the-types-of-ai-assistant-behavior&quot;&gt;Step 1: Understand the Types of AI Assistant Behavior&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AI tools fall along a spectrum based on how actively they interact with you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-the-background-helper-minimal-intrusion&quot;&gt;1. The Background Helper (Minimal Intrusion)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quiet until called upon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Great for deep-focus devs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Acts like autocomplete on demand&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-the-proactive-partner-moderate-intrusion&quot;&gt;2. The Proactive Partner (Moderate Intrusion)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Offers smart suggestions as you type&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Balances guidance with control&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ideal for those who like nudges but not noise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-the-active-collaborator-high-intrusion&quot;&gt;3. The Active Collaborator (High Intrusion)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Suggests proactively, refactors on its own&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sometimes takes initiative beyond what you asked&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Best for devs who want maximum AI assistance.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can be fun for vibe coding.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-2-audit-your-workflow-style&quot;&gt;Step 2: Audit Your Workflow Style&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The right assistant depends on how you work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-kind-of-coder-are-you&quot;&gt;What kind of coder are you?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flow-state coder&lt;/strong&gt;: You need focus and minimal interruptions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Burst coder&lt;/strong&gt;: You are energized by context-switching and quick input&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-breaks-your-concentration&quot;&gt;What breaks your concentration?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are popups or suggestions distracting?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do you lose focus without a prompt?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-do-you-prefer-to-learn&quot;&gt;How do you prefer to learn?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn-by-doing&lt;/strong&gt;: Prefer code patterns and examples&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn-by-understanding&lt;/strong&gt;: Need deep explanations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-3-match-assistant-style-to-your-workflow&quot;&gt;Step 3: Match Assistant Style to Your Workflow&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you know how you work, you can align that with the assistant type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;option-1-invisible-until-needed&quot;&gt;Option 1: Invisible Until Needed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best for&lt;/strong&gt;: Experienced devs who want help with boilerplate, syntax, and docs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-assistant-features-to-look-for&quot;&gt;What Assistant Features to Look for&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Autocomplete only for common patterns&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Context-aware suggestions that activate on pause&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On-demand doc lookup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tools-to-try&quot;&gt;Tools to try&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://continue.dev/&quot;&gt;Continue.dev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/features/copilot&quot;&gt;GitHub Copilot&lt;/a&gt; (with conservative settings)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;option-2-gentle-guidance&quot;&gt;Option 2: Gentle Guidance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best for&lt;/strong&gt;: Developers who want AI help while staying in control&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-assistant-features-to-look-for-1&quot;&gt;What Assistant Features to Look for&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inline suggestions that feel natural
Code completion that adapts to your style
Suggestions that teach, not just do&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tools-to-try-1&quot;&gt;Tools to try&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Most assistants with moderate config&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Continue’s philosophy is to put the developer in control&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Copilot with smart prompt tuning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;option-3-active-partnership&quot;&gt;Option 3: Active Partnership&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best for&lt;/strong&gt;: Complex projects and devs ready to shift their workflow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-assistant-features-to-look-for-2&quot;&gt;What Assistant Features to Look for&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Full-project understanding&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Multi-file suggestions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proactive refactors and implementations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tools-to-try-2&quot;&gt;Tools to Try&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cursor.com/&quot;&gt;Cursor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Continue.dev (advanced mode)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GithHub Copilot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-4-run-a-workflow-integration-test&quot;&gt;Step 4: Run a Workflow Integration Test&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before committing, test tools with these 5 workflow scenarios:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Morning Startup Test
Does the AI help you pick up where you left off, or get in the way?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Deep Focus Test
Can you stay in flow, or does it interrupt too much?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Context Switch Test
Does it keep up when jumping between files and tasks?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Learning Moment Test
When you hit something unfamiliar, does it help you understand?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Cleanup Test
Can you read and modify the AI’s code later?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-5-signs-an-ai-assistant-is-helping-or-hurting-your-workflow&quot;&gt;Step 5: Signs an AI Assistant Is Helping Or Hurting Your Workflow&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;red-flags-its-disrupting-your-workflow&quot;&gt;Red Flags (It’s disrupting your workflow)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Constantly fighting the suggestions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Code quality or clarity drops&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You rely on it so much that you can’t code solo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You feel anxious when it’s off. (Maybe it’s time to see a therapist too :joy: )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;green-flags-its-enhancing-your-workflow&quot;&gt;Green Flags (It’s enhancing your workflow)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You forget it’s there until you need it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’re learning new patterns&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You feel more confident and productive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tldr-finding-the-right-fit-ai-coding-assistant&quot;&gt;TL;DR: Finding the Right-Fit AI Coding Assistant&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking for an AI assistant that boosts productivity without overwhelming your workflow try GitHub Copilot or Continue.dev if you prefer minimal interruption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose tools with gentle, context-aware prompts if you want help but not takeover. Explore Cursor or advanced Continue setups for high-involvement AI assistance.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="AI" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Finding the assistant that fits just right.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Pros and Cons of the Top AI Code Assistants: Continue.dev, GitHub Copilot, and Cursor (With a Hero’s Twist)</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/Pros-and-Cons-of-AI-Code-Assistants" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pros and Cons of the Top AI Code Assistants: Continue.dev, GitHub Copilot, and Cursor (With a Hero’s Twist)" />
      <published>2025-07-07T00:00:00-04:00</published>
      <updated>2025-07-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/Pros%20and%20Cons%20of%20AI%20Code%20Assistants</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Pros-and-Cons-of-AI-Code-Assistants">&lt;p&gt;Every great hero needs the right weapon. Captain America has his shield, Aragorn wields Andúril, and David brought down Goliath with nothing but a slingshot and unshakeable faith.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As developers, facing the giants of legacy code, impossible challenges, and the eternal question, “Can you just add one small feature?”, having the right “weapon” can mean the difference in how successful we are. The AI coding assistant landscape is about finding your legendary weapon. It’s about choosing our superhero origin story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;choosing-your-coding-weapon-a-heros-guide-to-ai-assistants&quot;&gt;Choosing Your Coding Weapon: A Hero’s Guide to AI Assistants&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;continuedev-pros-cons-and-best-use-cases-&quot;&gt;Continue.dev: Pros, Cons, and Best Use Cases 🪃&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hero Archetype:&lt;/strong&gt; The resourceful underdog who’s powers lie in adaptability and cleverness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“For the battles aren’t won by size, but by skill and choosing your shot”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-metaphor-davids-slingshot&quot;&gt;The Metaphor: David’s Slingshot&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone expected David to suit up in Saul’s armor, but he looked at that heavy gear and said, “Nah, I’m good with my slingshot.” That’s Continue.dev.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While other tools come loaded with corporate armor and preset strategies, Continue says, “Here’s your slingshot. You choose the stones.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pros&quot;&gt;Pros&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shape-shifting: Works with any AI model you choose (GPT-4, Claude, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stealth mode: Can run everything locally&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Weapon crafting: Custom assistant creation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open source: Driven by community improvements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cons&quot;&gt;Cons&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Slight learning curve for setup and workflows&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Less polished UI than commercial tools&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Requires some config to reach full power&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;best-for&quot;&gt;Best For:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Developers who’ve been burned by vendor lock-in&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Power users who want full control&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Anyone building their own coding workflows&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;github-copilot-pros-cons-and-best-use-cases-️&quot;&gt;GitHub Copilot: Pros, Cons, and Best Use Cases 🛡️&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hero Archetype:&lt;/strong&gt; The steadfast leader who inspires confidence through consistency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I can do this all day.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-metaphor-captain-americas-shield&quot;&gt;The Metaphor: Captain America’s Shield&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first Avenger, the one who established what it means to be an AI coding assistant. Steve Rogers’ shield isn’t flashy. It doesn’t shoot lasers. But it’s reliable, trusted by the team, and always ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s GitHub Copilot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pros-1&quot;&gt;Pros&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unbreakable consistency: Works the same way every time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Team integration: Easy to roll out across orgs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Battle-tested: Millions of developers rely on it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Seamless with VS Code and GitHub&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cons-1&quot;&gt;Cons&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Occasionally hallucinates or misinterprets intentions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Offers limited insight into &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; things break&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Not ideal for deeper refactoring or debugging scenarios&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;best-for-1&quot;&gt;Best For:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Developers who want plug-and-play completion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Teams looking for low-friction onboarding&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fast-paced shipping of small features or fixes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cursor-pros-cons-and-best-use-cases-️&quot;&gt;Cursor: Pros, Cons, and Best Use Cases ⚔️&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hero Archetype:&lt;/strong&gt; The chosen one destined for greatness if you’re willing to pay the price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Reforged from the shards of what came before”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-metaphor-aragorns-andúril&quot;&gt;The Metaphor: Aragorn’s Andúril&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reforged from the shards of what came before, Cursor is VS Code reborn and transformed into something powerful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pros-2&quot;&gt;Pros&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Royal bloodline: Built on VS Code’s foundation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;AI-first vision: UI centered around AI workflows&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Multi-realm mastery: Understands and edits your whole codebase&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Composer magic: Suggests multi-file implementations intelligently&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cons-2&quot;&gt;Cons&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Premium pricing tiers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can make sweeping changes outside of scope&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Might be overwhelming for newer devs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;best-for-2&quot;&gt;Best For:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Developers who want deep AI collaboration&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Projects involving large-scale refactors&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Those ready to go “all in” on an AI-native IDE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tldr-pros--cons-of-top-ai-code-assistants&quot;&gt;TL;DR: Pros &amp;amp; Cons of Top AI Code Assistants&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Tool&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Pros&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Cons&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Continue.dev&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Open source, model-agnostic, runs locally, educational modes&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Not as beginner-friendly, more setup required&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GitHub Copilot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Fast completions, trusted by teams, easy to use in VS Code&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Can hallucinate, struggles with context-aware fixes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cursor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;AI-native IDE, great for refactoring and large changes, smart UI&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Expensive, can overreach and change more than intended&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="AI" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Every great hero needs the right weapon. Captain America has his shield, Aragorn wields Andúril, and David brought down Goliath with nothing but a slingshot and unshakeable faith.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Debugging Mobile Navigation Bugs with AI Code Assistants: Continue vs Copilot vs Cursor</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/Which-Code-Assistant-Fix-Real-Problems-Best" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Debugging Mobile Navigation Bugs with AI Code Assistants: Continue vs Copilot vs Cursor" />
      <published>2025-06-30T00:00:00-04:00</published>
      <updated>2025-06-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/Which%20Code%20Assistant%20Fix%20Real%20Problems%20Best</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Which-Code-Assistant-Fix-Real-Problems-Best">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A follow-up to “Which Code Assistant Actually Helps Developers Grow?” This time, testing how AI assistants handle debugging existing code problems.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, I &lt;a href=&quot;https://bekahhw.com/Which-Code-Assistant-Helps-Developers-Grow&quot;&gt;tested three AI coding assistants on building a new feature&lt;/a&gt;. This time, I wanted to see how they handle something most developers deal with daily: debugging existing code problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was debugging a mobile responsiveness issue on my Astro + Tailwind site (see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BekahHW/siblings-write/&quot;&gt;GitHub Project here&lt;/a&gt;). The navbar wasn’t collapsing on mobile, causing layout issues. Instead of a full navigation bar cramming into mobile view, I needed a proper hamburger menu. Instead of manually rewriting it, I tested how three AI code assistants—Continue, Copilot, and Cursor—would solve it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/240b8dcxjht9ly0hg9v1.gif&quot; alt=&quot;gif showing the responsive layout issue on mobile is fixed when deleting the nav bar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what I told each assistant:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“There’s an issue with mobile view on the site. I think the main problem is with the navbar. But I don’t think it makes sense to have a nav bar for a mobile site. We should make the site responsive and add a sticky nav bar with a hamburger menu instead of the full navigation bar once the site hits mobile-sized screens.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR&lt;/strong&gt;: I tested Continue, GitHub Copilot, and Cursor to debug a broken mobile navbar in an Astro-based site. Continue offered the best explanations and teaching moments, Cursor was fast but made extra assumptions, and Copilot was fast but error-prone. If you’re debugging UI bugs, Continue’s Chat mode helps you understand why things break, not just how to fix them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;can-continue-debug-a-responsive-nav-issue-in-astro&quot;&gt;Can Continue Debug a Responsive Nav Issue in Astro?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used &lt;a href=&quot;https://continue.dev/&quot;&gt;Continue&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.continue.dev/agent/how-to-use-it&quot;&gt;Agent mode&lt;/a&gt;, giving it context from &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Header.astro&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Nav.astro&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;BaseLayout.astro&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/bg21110n6vfs19es00l5.png&quot; alt=&quot;Continue.dev suggesting hamburger menu fixes in Astro project&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-good&quot;&gt;The Good&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Created a dedicated hamburger menu component&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Asked for permission between file changes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When I got a transparency issue with the menu panel, it fixed it in one go&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It added comments to understand the steps it was taking in the code and debug logs in the code to help me see what was working and when&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Everything worked within 12 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-learning-experience&quot;&gt;The Learning Experience&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I tested the same fix using Continue’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.continue.dev/chat/how-to-use-it&quot;&gt;Chat mode&lt;/a&gt; instead of Agent mode, it took longer but provided much more thorough explanations. The conversation was more educational, walking me through the reasoning behind each change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;verdict&quot;&gt;Verdict&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continue balances efficiency with learning. Agent mode got me working code fast, while Chat mode taught me the “why” behind the solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/9ss3rdoqhm59mkjjqxbl.png&quot; alt=&quot;Copilot output showing approach to fixing broken layout with overlapping nav menu&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-copilot-handles-responsive-navbar-bugs&quot;&gt;How Copilot Handles Responsive Navbar Bugs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copilot started by unnecessarily converting a Svelte component, then immediately threw a TypeScript error:
&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Argument of type 'EventTarget' is not assignable to parameter of type 'Node'&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure why it decided that the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ThemeToggleButton&lt;/code&gt; needed to be converted. At the very least, that’s outside of the scope of this PR, in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/fi883ls0s34e83ux1zra.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image description&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was able to solve the problem pretty quickly when I used the “Fix with Copilot” function, explaining, “You should cast e.target to Node when passing it to .contains() to resolve the type error.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-real-problem&quot;&gt;The Real Problem&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hamburger menu initially didn’t appear at all. The responsiveness was “fixed” because the navigation disappeared, but users couldn’t access any menu items.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After back-and-forth debugging, Copilot resorted to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;!important&lt;/code&gt; declarations (not ideal) and the old “turn the background red” debugging trick. Even when the menu became visible, clicking it did nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, we identified JavaScript as the culprit. Copilot fixed it, but then the menu links appeared directly over the page content without any background container. More back-and-forth with questionable styling decisions followed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was to the point where I definitely could fix this faster than having a back-and-forth with Copilot, so I called it. After that, I also realized there was a bug where, after expanding the hamburger menu on mobile and then switching to desktop view, the mobile menu remained open on top of the restored navigation bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/tvvd7pmfl9gm2usc0k1w.png&quot; alt=&quot;nav panel on top of page text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;: About 20 minutes, with me ultimately fixing the styles myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning Value&lt;/strong&gt;: Minimal. Copilot told me what it was doing, but didn’t really explain its approach or help me understand the underlying problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cursor-fixes-more-than-you-askhelpful-or-harmful&quot;&gt;Cursor Fixes More Than You Ask—Helpful or Harmful?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cursor’s response was immediate and organized:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/7vx5vt6fdw9b2utz4gre.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cursor's initial message detailing what needed to be done to implement the hamburger menu&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-process&quot;&gt;The Process&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Automatically read the global CSS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Outlined exactly what needed to change and why&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provided all necessary file updates&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hit the same cross-page JavaScript issue as Copilot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-interesting-part&quot;&gt;The Interesting Part&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cursor went beyond my request, automatically improving mobile styles across the site that I hadn’t asked for. This raises an interesting question: should AI assistants make assumptions about what you “really” need?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;: About 15 minutes to complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning Value&lt;/strong&gt;: Good explanations of changes. I appreciate that it gives more information on why errors were happening in the context of using Astro.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/vsk81fkbeau7jkmdtafh.png&quot; alt=&quot;showing the issue and how it understands and corrects it&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;context-switching-costs&quot;&gt;Context Switching Costs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s something I noticed that none of the assistants addressed: familiarity bias. Cursor and GitHub Copilot felt nearly identical to use, so I moved faster with them. Continue required slightly more of a learning curve, which actually slowed me down initially but provided better educational value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t a knock against Continue. It’s a reminder that switching tools comes with costs, even when the new tool might be better in the long term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;debugging-vs-building-different-skills-required&quot;&gt;Debugging vs. Building: Different Skills Required&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This debugging scenario revealed something my first test missed, that building new features and fixing existing problems require different AI assistance approaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;building-new-features&quot;&gt;Building New Features&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clear requirements&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blank slate approach&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Focus on “what should this do?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;debugging-existing-code&quot;&gt;Debugging Existing Code&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Understanding legacy decisions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identifying root causes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Focusing on “why isn’t this working?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continue did well with the debugging mindset, asking permission before changes and explaining the reasoning. Copilot and Cursor were more aggressive about “fixing” things, sometimes creating new problems in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;which-ai-coding-assistant-wins-for-debugging&quot;&gt;Which AI Coding Assistant Wins for Debugging?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For Learning&lt;/strong&gt;: Continue, especially in Chat mode. It helped me understand not just what was broken, but why the original approach failed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For Speed&lt;/strong&gt;: Cursor, if you don’t mind AI making assumptions about improvements you didn’t request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-bigger-picture&quot;&gt;The Bigger Picture&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This comparison reinforced something I mentioned in my first post: the tool is only part of the equation. Each assistant performed differently not just because of their capabilities, but because of how they approached the problem-solving process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continue treated debugging as a learning opportunity. Copilot treated it as a code completion task. Cursor treated it as a comprehensive redesign project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to know which coding assistant helps developers grow when you’re debugging, try this: Before asking for a fix, ask the AI to help you understand why the original code failed. The debugging skills you develop will be more valuable than any individual fix.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="AI" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">A follow-up to “Which Code Assistant Actually Helps Developers Grow?” This time, testing how AI assistants handle debugging existing code problems.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Which Code Assistant Actually Helps Developers Grow?</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/Which-Code-Assistant-Helps-Developers-Grow" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Which Code Assistant Actually Helps Developers Grow?" />
      <published>2025-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</published>
      <updated>2025-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/Which%20Code%20Assistant%20Helps%20Developers%20Grow</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Which-Code-Assistant-Helps-Developers-Grow">&lt;p&gt;Over the past year, we’ve had a ton of conversations at &lt;a href=&quot;http://virtualcoffee.io/&quot;&gt;Virtual Coffee&lt;/a&gt; about AI. If you’ve opened up X or LinkedIn, you probably realize that people have very strong opinions about AI. At Virtual Coffee, we’re a pretty close-knit community, so there are a lot of concerns about the impacts of AI, how junior developers grow (or stay stagnant) with AI, whether or not to adopt it as a team, and whether to use it without telling your boss. At the heart of a lot of these conversations is the feeling that you’re somehow “cheating” if you use AI, and that you won’t learn or grow if you’re using it. I think the sentiment comes from the right place, caring about people, but I think there are a lot of options and approaches you can take to prevent that. I believe that when we consider the evolving landscape in tech, we also need to think about the changing landscape of tech education. Most of us will end up using AI in our workflow, either out of necessity or because our team mandates it. That’s why I also think that AI coding assistants actually have the ability to help everyone grow in ways they couldn’t before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/ykdojo/status/1932149031196856738&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/6unkesc921s6jw892qz6.png&quot; alt=&quot;ykdogo tweet&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;learning-vs-speed-trap&quot;&gt;Learning vs. Speed Trap&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your approach to learning with AI assistants definitely matters. And not all AI coding assistants will help increase developers’ coding skills. Learning about the code you’re writing, how your team approaches problems, and how to utilize AI as part of your workflow is necessary to grow in tech. Teams don’t need someone who can prompt their way to a working solution but can’t debug it when it breaks. Most AI coding assistants are optimized for speed and not for learning. They’re designed to get you from problem to solution as quickly as possible. If your goal is skill development, you should think of AI adoption more like onboarding a mentor, rather than replacing you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;context-aware-guidance&quot;&gt;Context-Aware Guidance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most effective learning-focused assistants should understand what you’re trying to do and what you should learn from doing it. They highlight patterns, point out potential issues, and suggest alternative approaches that might teach you something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I’m testing out a couple of AI coding assistants on a new feature. (I’m interested in doing a follow-up post that uses it on an existing file. Let me know if that’s something you’d like to see!)  I tested out each coding assistant on a new feature I’m adding to my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.siblingswrite.com/&quot;&gt;writing site&lt;/a&gt;, with this simple prompt:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I want to create a game for this site, where people (not logged in) can add a word to a story. Once the story hits 300 words, it locks the submission. No one should be able to submit more than 3 words in a row.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are my takeaways for Continue, GitHub Copilot, and Cursor. I gave the same initial prompt for each of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;continue&quot;&gt;Continue&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://continue.dev/&quot;&gt;Continue&lt;/a&gt; stands out here because their philosophy explicitly addresses the learning problem. Their documentation talks about “amplifying intent” rather than replacing it, and they specifically warn against becoming a “human clipboard.” You can explore ideas through “vibe coding” during creative phases, but when it comes to production work, they emphasize that developers need to stay in control. It’s open source, model-flexible (bring your own LLM), and encourages creating custom assistants that reinforce your team’s coding standards. For teams focused on growth and increasing their developers’ coding skills, Continue offers both transparency and control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before giving me any kind of code, it gave me an initial planning response, outlining a step-by-step approach to the user story. Seeing the plan helps the user to walk through the task with Continue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/uuws98nat1n8qrflz4nn.png&quot; alt=&quot;Overview of the approach Continue takes to implement feature&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this, it provided commented code along with a reusable template. The inline comments break down some of the logic, and helps the user understand the process it went through to generate the code. After the code, it summarized all the changes it had made. 
You might notice it mentions Flask, but this is actually an Astro app. That was my mistake. When I initially set up the assistant, I had configured it with Python-focused instructions and directed it to Python documentation, since my rules were originally written for a Python assistant. Once I updated those settings and specifically shared my repository with the assistant, Continue was able to properly follow my project’s styling conventions and leverage the existing components.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, it gave both an overview of what was implemented and ideas for improvement. I appreciate that it provided more context about its approach, commented code throughout the new file, and offered inspiration for my next iteration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/3iwg6njdy7a2fk8plmf8.png&quot; alt=&quot;Overview of the approach it took and the improvements I could make&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without having to ask further questions about the decisions it made and the approach it took, I think it provided a good amount of context for the developer to understand the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;copilot&quot;&gt;Copilot&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/features/copilot/&quot;&gt;GitHub Copilot&lt;/a&gt; is known for excelling at code completion and includes agent-based features. It can speed up repetitive tasks, but the learning tends to happen through osmosis. You need to recognize the patterns in suggestions and might pick them up over time. You have to be more active with your learning by asking Copilot about the decisions it made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copilot’s approach was a lot different from Continue’s. It jumps straight into code generation without context-setting or explanation of its approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It did provide a “wrap up” after the code, but it wasn’t as thorough or complete as what I got from Continue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/3wmwmu4lse15u873zasm.png&quot; alt=&quot;Wrap up of the implementation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For what it’s worth, Copilot also told me that creating a Svelte component was the best option, and then, when I questioned it, Copilot told me that Astro was actually the best path. It was flexible with the approach once I questioned it, but it definitely required me to go down the rabbit hole with it. Learning is definitely passive with Copilot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cursor&quot;&gt;Cursor&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cursor.com/&quot;&gt;Cursor&lt;/a&gt; offers an AI-first editor experience with agent modes, but their emphasis on “AI that builds with you” raises questions about how much actual building the developer is doing during complex tasks. Although I’m just doing a basic test for this post with a brand new feature, I did experiment a bit with its interactive, AI-native IDE experience by highlighting some of the code it generated and asking, “What does this do?” I plan on doing more of that in a follow-up post for comparison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After being given the same prompt as Continue and Copilot, Cursor walked me through the approach it was taking and included what files it looked at to get there. However, it automatically created a Svelte file for the game (I did have Svelte installed in the project), and I had to do a lot of back and forth with it to understand the decisions it made and why. I’ve actually never used Svelte, so this was something I had to dig into deeper to understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/g2kk5qu91tqrqk2ewtc3.png&quot; alt=&quot;initial overview of the approach&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things I appreciated about Cursor’s experience was that it explained piece by piece and required me to accept changes. That forces the user to think about what’s being implemented. It also auto-corrected some of its own errors, which is a good learning opportunity to see how it debugs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/317dusccwjklrckjxf0s.png&quot; alt=&quot;explaining where the issues lies in the error&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish it would have automatically added code comments throughout, but the explanations were valuable. The takeaways at the end walked through what the user could do and the functionality. It was more thorough than Copilot, but I liked the improvements suggestion that Continue had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/ailxygg7jc0uprc177n0.png&quot; alt=&quot;wrap up of features and how it works&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;building-a-learning-first-ai-strategy&quot;&gt;Building a Learning-First AI Strategy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this exploration is important for new folks coming into tech, and for teams serious about using AI to help their team grow and not just ship faster. The path here should:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start with Intent&lt;/strong&gt;: Before adding any AI tool to your workflow or your team’s, clearly define your goals. Are you trying to help yourself or junior developers on the team understand architectural patterns? Learn a new framework? Improve code review skills?
Different learning goals might call for different AI approaches.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Choose Tools with Teaching DNA&lt;/strong&gt;: Look for AI assistants that were designed with education in mind, not just productivity. Continue’s emphasis on amplifying developer intent rather than replacing it is a good example of this thinking.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implement Learning Safeguards&lt;/strong&gt;: Whatever tool you choose, build processes that encourage learning by requiring explanations for AI-generated solutions, having regular code review focused on understanding, not just correctness, adding pair programming sessions where AI suggestions become discussion points, documenting decisions and trade-offs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Measure Learning, Not Just Output&lt;/strong&gt;: Track whether your developers are asking better questions over time, not just whether they’re closing tickets faster. Are they suggesting alternatives during code review? Can they debug issues in AI-generated code? Are they learning patterns they can apply without AI assistance?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want developers who are using AI to understand problems. That’s the difference between an AI assistant and an AI mentor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wrapping-up&quot;&gt;Wrapping Up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the best AI coding assistant for individuals and teams focuses on developer skill growth. Based on philosophy, approach, and explicit focus on learning, Continue seems to understand this distinction better than most. But the tool is only part of the equation. The bigger part is approaching AI adoption with learning as the primary goal, not just productivity.
The most productive teams and developers understand what they’re building, whether with or without AI help.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="AI" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Over the past year, we’ve had a ton of conversations at Virtual Coffee about AI. If you’ve opened up X or LinkedIn, you probably realize that people have very strong opinions about AI. At Virtual Coffee, we’re a pretty close-knit community, so there are a lot of concerns about the impacts of AI, how junior developers grow (or stay stagnant) with AI, whether or not to adopt it as a team, and whether to use it without telling your boss. At the heart of a lot of these conversations is the feeling that you’re somehow “cheating” if you use AI, and that you won’t learn or grow if you’re using it. I think the sentiment comes from the right place, caring about people, but I think there are a lot of options and approaches you can take to prevent that. I believe that when we consider the evolving landscape in tech, we also need to think about the changing landscape of tech education. Most of us will end up using AI in our workflow, either out of necessity or because our team mandates it. That’s why I also think that AI coding assistants actually have the ability to help everyone grow in ways they couldn’t before.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Comparing 5 AI Coding Assistants: Which One’s Right for You?</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/Comparing-AI-Coding-Assistants" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Comparing 5 AI Coding Assistants: Which One's Right for You?" />
      <published>2025-06-24T00:00:00-04:00</published>
      <updated>2025-06-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/Comparing%20AI%20Coding%20Assistants</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Comparing-AI-Coding-Assistants">&lt;p&gt;A couple of days ago, I saw &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/jeromehardaway_microsoft-ceo-admits-that-ai-is-generating-activity-7340817881154134016-Ld9Q&quot;&gt;Jerome Hardaway’s LinkedIn post&lt;/a&gt;, and it really resonated with me. I like the idea of thinking of AI coding tools as “really great intern[s]. Fast, helpful, capable in the right hands – but still needs supervision, clear direction, and someone to clean up afterward.” There are a couple of projects that I’m working on this summer: the author site that I share with my brothers that uses Astro, a new project I’m launching for &lt;a href=&quot;https://oss-communities.netlify.app/&quot;&gt;osscommunities.com&lt;/a&gt;. This seems like the perfect opportunity to find the right tool that’s worth adding tool to my workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/ah6h6875jlzj6p5oknx4.png&quot; alt=&quot;Jerome Hardaway's full post&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-ai-assistant-philosophy&quot;&gt;My AI Assistant Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve always been a proponent of using AI just like any other tool in your toolbox. It’s there to help you level up, work more effectively, and move faster. If I were a carpenter who was too afraid or skeptical to try a hammer, I wouldn’t be as effective as other carpenters. And honestly, as a mom of four, I’ve been looking for ways to be more efficient for years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we all know, your coding assistant is only as good as you guide it to be. You have to make sure to correct it when it hallucinates, to double-check its work, to help it understand what you actually need. For me, it’s all about finding the best partner for the work I’m doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ai-assistant-tools--their-promises&quot;&gt;AI Assistant Tools &amp;amp; Their Promises&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose these five AI coding assistants based on different approaches to the same problem: Continue.dev for its open source flexibility and developer-first philosophy, Cursor for its AI-native editor approach, GitHub Copilot as the established market leader, Tabnine for its enterprise angle, and Windsurf as the rebranded dark horse. In my opinion, these represent the current landscape of AI code completion tools, from open source flexibility to enterprise privacy to AI-first design philosophies. Here’s a little more on each:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-continuedev&quot;&gt;1. &lt;a href=&quot;https://continue.dev/&quot;&gt;Continue.dev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Their Promise&lt;/em&gt;:  Amplify developers, don’t replace them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My Expectation&lt;/em&gt;:  I think Continue.dev’s chat, autocomplete, edit, and agent modes in one tool sounds interesting and comprehensive. I’m hoping this flexibility translates to better suggestions for my workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-github-copilot&quot;&gt;2. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/features/copilot/&quot;&gt;GitHub CoPilot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Their Promise&lt;/em&gt;:  AI that builds with you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My Expectation&lt;/em&gt;:  I’ve used CoPilot before, so this is the obvious choice since I already have experience with it. But I’m really curious to compare it to other tools out there to see how it stacks up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-cursor&quot;&gt;3. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cursor.com&quot;&gt;Cursor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Their Promise&lt;/em&gt;:  Cursor is a powerful AI-first code editor that enhances your development workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My Expectation&lt;/em&gt;:  The real test for me is whether building the editor around AI from day one actually feels different than VS Code with AI-extensions and whether or not the experience feels disjointed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-tabnine&quot;&gt;4. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tabnine.com/&quot;&gt;Tabnine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Their Promise&lt;/em&gt;:  Tabnine claims that it is the world’s most contextually aware AI software development platform, helping mature engineering teams speed up and simplify
their entire development process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My Expectation&lt;/em&gt;:  They seem to be targeting enterprise developers, but I’m curious if their focus on “mature engineering teams” translates to better suggestions for solo projects like mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-windsurf&quot;&gt;5. &lt;a href=&quot;https://windsurf.com/about&quot;&gt;Windsurf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Their Promise&lt;/em&gt;:  Windsurf is a next-generation AI IDE built to keep you in the flow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My Expectation&lt;/em&gt;: The “dream bigger” messaging is heavy on inspiration, but there’s not a lot of specifics. I want to see how well that translates to the user experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-next&quot;&gt;What’s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not looking for the tool that writes the most code for me.  I’m looking for the best AI coding assistant that makes me a better developer while helping me ship faster. The goal isn’t just to find another autocomplete tool. My goal is to discover which AI code assistant deserves a permanent spot in my development workflow. Whether that ends up being Continue.dev’s customizable approach, Cursor’s seamless integration, or one of the other contenders, I’ll share what I’ve learned in the coming weeks. Stay tuned for the full AI coding assistant comparison and see which tool actually lives up to the productivity promises.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="AI" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">A couple of days ago, I saw Jerome Hardaway’s LinkedIn post, and it really resonated with me. I like the idea of thinking of AI coding tools as “really great intern[s]. Fast, helpful, capable in the right hands – but still needs supervision, clear direction, and someone to clean up afterward.” There are a couple of projects that I’m working on this summer: the author site that I share with my brothers that uses Astro, a new project I’m launching for osscommunities.com. This seems like the perfect opportunity to find the right tool that’s worth adding tool to my workflow.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Test Drive Before You Buy: Your Guide to AI Code Assistant Trials in 2025</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/Guide-to-AI-Coding-Assistant-Trials" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Test Drive Before You Buy: Your Guide to AI Code Assistant Trials in 2025" />
      <published>2025-06-23T00:00:00-04:00</published>
      <updated>2025-06-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/Guide%20to%20AI%20Coding%20Assistant%20Trials</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Guide-to-AI-Coding-Assistant-Trials">&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://bekahhw.com/Taking-Time-to-Breathe-A-New-Chapter-Begins&quot;&gt;my last post&lt;/a&gt;, I talked about spending time this summer looking at different AI tools. I want to get hands-on, figure out what I want to integrate into my workflow. But before I spend time (and money) testing things out, I wanted to start with the free/trial periods. So you’re starting at the beginning of this journey with me. The question that I started with is: Which AI code assistants will actually let me take them for a proper test drive? In this post, I’ll share what I found across five top AI Coding Assistants—Continue, Windsurf, Cursor, GitHub Copilot, and Tabnine—and what I’m interested in learning as I put them to the test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-trial-landscape-whats-actually-available-with-ai-assistants&quot;&gt;The Trial Landscape: What’s Actually Available with AI Assistants&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After digging through pricing pages, here’s what you can try without putting in your credit card:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://continue.dev/&quot;&gt;Continue.dev&lt;/a&gt; is one of the most flexible and accessible AI Coding Assistants out there.  It’s open source, which means you can literally use it forever for free if you just bring your own API keys, and it supports any model you choose, including Claude 4 Sonnet, 4o, llama3.1 8b. Continue’s IDE extension has gained a lot of recent attention (20K+ GitHub stars), and integrates into tools that you might already use (VS Code and JetBrains). You can also create public assistants and invite your entire team.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://windsurf.com/&quot;&gt;Windsurf&lt;/a&gt; surprised me here. Their free tier includes 25 prompt credits per month, all premium models, unlimited Fast Tab completions, and even a 2-week Pro trial to test the advanced features. Built by the Codeium team, it’s essentially giving you a full-featured AI IDE for nothing. The supercomplete feature claims to understand your entire workspace to give intelligent suggestions across files.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;tabnine.com&quot;&gt;Tabnine&lt;/a&gt; offers a “Dev Preview” that’s completely free for qualified users, giving you AI code completions for current line and multiple lines, plus AI-powered chat. There’s also a paid Dev plan at $9/month with more advanced features. The Dev plan includes their foundational AI agents that can autonomously generate code, tests, docs, and fixes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;cursor.com&quot;&gt;Cursor&lt;/a&gt; gives you a Pro two-week trial as part of their free Hobby plan, plus 2,000 completions to play with. After that, their Pro plan is $20/month. It’s a significant jump but with unlimited agent requests and tab completions, two weeks is enough time to test their agent mode on a real project and see if the autonomous coding capabilities live up to the hype.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/features/copilot&quot;&gt;GitHub Copilot&lt;/a&gt; offers a solid 30-day free trial on their Pro plan before charging $10/month. Thirty days is actually enough time to see if it clicks with your workflow or just generates more bugs than it fixes. Since it’s deeply integrated in the GitHub ecosystem, you’ll be able to see how well it understands project context.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-to-actually-test-during-your-trial&quot;&gt;What to Actually Test During Your Trial&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to avoid some of the common problems I hear developers talk about when they sign up for AI Coding Assistants. I want to do more than test drive a car and park it in a lot. Here’s the approach I’m trying to take:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-real-world-gauntlet&quot;&gt;The Real-World Gauntlet&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Test it on your actual codebase.&lt;/strong&gt; I have some existing projects that I’ve created over the years. My blog is a Jekyll site that I have done only enough updating to keep things running over the past couple of years. It definitely has some “why did past me write this” code in the codebase. I want to make sure that AI can handle past me. (I’m actually interested in creating a Continue assistant to help update my Jekyll site.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Try it on unfamiliar territory.&lt;/strong&gt; I need my AI Coding Assistant to be a force multiplier. When I’m working in my strengths, it doesn’t take me as long. But when I use it with code that I’m not super familiar with, I need it to be good. I don’t want it to help me write bad code faster. Test both scenarios. I have a new project I’ve been wanting to work on, and this seems like a good use case.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See how it handles context.&lt;/strong&gt; Can it understand your team’s coding conventions? Does it remember what you were working on five files ago? Context awareness separates the good from the great. This is not applicable for what I’m working on right now, but this is super important if you’re working with a team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-stress-test&quot;&gt;The Stress Test&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should try to push these tools to their breaking point. (Semi-related, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/AIMemory/comments/1lg6axl/so_our_smartest_llms_kind_of_give_up_when_we_need/&quot;&gt;I posted about LLMs giving up when we need them the most. Feel free to add to the conversation!&lt;/a&gt; Ask them to refactor a complex function. Have them write tests for edge cases you know are problematic. See if they can debug that one weird issue that’s been haunting your team for weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal is to find the AI Assistant that fails gracefully and teaches you something useful in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-hidden-costs&quot;&gt;The Hidden Costs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where the trial period becomes really important. Most AI assistants have usage-based pricing that can get out of hand really quick. You can eat through your budget if you’re not careful. During your trial, pay attention to those usage meters since they’re previewing your future bills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start with the free tiers. Continue if you want maximum control, Windsurf if you want simplicity, Tabnine if you just want better autocomplete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use the trial period to answer this question: Does this tool make you a better developer, or just a faster typist? At the end of the day, you’re responsible for all production code you ship. If you don’t understand your code, AI is a temporary solution to your problem, and that approach can end badly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s your homework (and we can do it together, just comment which one you’re testing below!):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pick one tool from the list above&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set it up on your current project&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use it for a week on real work (not tutorials)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask yourself: “Am I learning, or just copying?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan on starting with Continue and working my way through the list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The right AI assistant will enhance and amplify your skills, not replace them.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="AI" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">In my last post, I talked about spending time this summer looking at different AI tools. I want to get hands-on, figure out what I want to integrate into my workflow. But before I spend time (and money) testing things out, I wanted to start with the free/trial periods. So you’re starting at the beginning of this journey with me. The question that I started with is: Which AI code assistants will actually let me take them for a proper test drive? In this post, I’ll share what I found across five top AI Coding Assistants—Continue, Windsurf, Cursor, GitHub Copilot, and Tabnine—and what I’m interested in learning as I put them to the test.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Taking Time to Breathe: A New Chapter Begins</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/Taking-Time-to-Breathe-A-New-Chapter-Begins" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Taking Time to Breathe: A New Chapter Begins" />
      <published>2025-06-10T00:00:00-04:00</published>
      <updated>2025-06-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/Taking%20Time%20to%20Breathe:%20A%20New%20Chapter%20Begins</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Taking-Time-to-Breathe-A-New-Chapter-Begins">&lt;p&gt;As of June 1st, I’m no longer with the Linux Foundation. While I’ll share more details about this transition in a future post, I wanted to take a moment to reflect on what comes next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going through an acquisition is intense, especially when you’re leaving what was truly your favorite job. The experience has been both professionally enriching and personally challenging, and I’ve realized how important it is to give yourself permission to pause and process major changes rather than immediately jumping into the next thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s exactly what I’m doing this summer: taking a pragmatic approach to my career and family life. I’m giving myself time to breathe, to explore opportunities I didn’t have bandwidth for before, and to be intentional about my next steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-coming-this-summer&quot;&gt;What’s Coming This Summer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My primary focus for the coming months will be diving deep into AI tools and their practical applications. I’ve been wanting to explore more AI tools, but I haven’t had the time to until now. As someone who’s spent considerable time thinking about content strategy and audience development, I’m fascinated by how AI is reshaping not just what we create, but how we create it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can expect a lot of AI-related content from me in the weeks ahead. I don’t have an exact plan mapped out, so it might be everything from tool reviews and practical use cases to my thoughts on how these technologies are changing the content landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;looking-forward&quot;&gt;Looking Forward&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll have more to share about my long-term plans soon, but for now, I’m embracing this period of exploration. Thanks for following along on this journey. The next few months should be interesting.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Bekah Hawrot Weigel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Personal" />
      
        <category term="Career" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">As of June 1st, I’m no longer with the Linux Foundation. While I’ll share more details about this transition in a future post, I wanted to take a moment to reflect on what comes next.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed> -->
