<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BekahHW</title>
    <description>Code. Community. Feelings. It's all here.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Being a Hybrid Friend is Hard</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Before coming into tech, I saw my friends weekly. I’ve never had a lot of friends, but I’ve had friends. You know, the kind that know you and understand you and you can break into random songs in front of one minute, shit-talk them in a board game the next minute, and then break down and cry when they ask, “Are you doing ok today?” We all had the same zipcode, and regional understanding - there’s something unique and interesting and beautiful about living in an Appalachian region. When I got my first job in tech this started to change. When the pandemic hit, this &lt;strong&gt;changed&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one felt close anymore because we were isolated in our homes. We were literally trying to stay far away from each other. There weren’t friendships of proximity anymore - you know the kind where your kids are the same age and you go to the same park playdates together. We played in our own backyards. And for a while, things were really hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But from the ashes, a light appeared and we were renewed because we all had each other everywhere. We found friendships online. We found ways to safely share the challenges, the despair, the heartache, and we started to laugh again. We found that we could deeply connect with people across timezones we didn’t even know existed prior to our interactions. We grew together because we were connected by a trauma that no one had ever anticipated. And we all had a baseline of understanding each other’s lives. It was an unprecedented event in history that brought us together, &lt;strong&gt;deeply&lt;/strong&gt; together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we also had to learn to experience sorrow together. And sometimes - the world was already so heavy - some people couldn’t be there anymore. It was hard, but we understood. There are depths of sorrow that none of us were prepared for. When we lost a friend who we had never met, but felt like we had known each other forever, there was a weird internal negotiation that happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does it mean to lose a friend you’ve never hugged? What does it mean to support a group of friends online who have lost someone? How do you grieve together online? How do you survive when it’s your job to reach out to people and let them know over and over and over again that someone in your friend group has died? How do you survive being responsible for conversations about something that aches so deeply in your soul and that no one has prepared you for?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a new sorrow now, the sorrow of being a hybrid friend. You feel torn between being friends with the people you see every day and the people who you see online every day. You feel like you’re not giving enough to the in person friends or the online friends. You’re being stretched, and the pain of being pulled in two directions is exhausting and excruciating. You feel like you have to make a choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s always easier to walk away from people you don’t run into in the milk aisle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a hybrid friend is hard. A lot of us have met each other irl (in real life), and something about that solidifies the experience for a while. But being an online friend somehow defies object permanence. Kids might realize that the ball is hiding behind the couch, but when you’re an adult with a busy life and responsibilities, it’s &lt;strong&gt;hard&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not judging anyone. In some ways, life is harder now than it was in 2020 because it’s full. My kids have activities, they want to go places, &lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt; want to go places. It’s good, don’t get me wrong, but we had totally separate lives for a couple of years and that became the norm. And now we have a new norm and we’re trying to figure out how to merge and blend the two, but they’re just two different songs altogether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know how to make a harmony out of this.  I know that it’s &lt;strong&gt;hard&lt;/strong&gt;. And I want you to know that it’s ok for it to be hard and to make hard decisions. I still think part of this is realizing that our lives will never be the same. We have all be changed because of our shared trauma, and that complicates things. We can’t go back to what things were before, because none of us are who we were before. We can’t deny the challenges and sorrows we faced in the last couple of years, because whether we like it or not, they have deeply impacted every single one of us. But we also can’t deny the beauty that we experienced when we found &lt;strong&gt;our people&lt;/strong&gt;, when there were no people around.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Being-a-Hybrid-Friend-is-Hard</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Being-a-Hybrid-Friend-is-Hard</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Evolving Landscape of DevRel: Trends and Predictions for 2023</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks ago, I put out this tweet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/BekahHW/status/1721565484103938373?s=20&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/qlauo2lvar9t7do9mpgf.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tweet on the heyday of devrel&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially, this blog post was going to expand on that. But before writing, I wanted to do some research into the history of DevRel, look at some of the trends, before writing an essay to prove my assertion. What I ended up doing was writing this blog post as an exploration of the field, some of the changes and challenges we face, and where I think we’re headed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-devrel&quot;&gt;What is DevRel?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of those questions that only some people agree on the definition. I suspect a lack of a clear definition of what DevRel is and what it does is part of the problem we’re seeing with DevRel today. If leadership can’t understand it, its value decreases. If leadership hears another successful DevRel team defined differently than how their organization defines it, scrutiny and distrust often follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guy Kawasaki popularized the term Developer Evangelist at Apple in the 1980s. Developer Evangelists engaged directly with the developer community, especially around the Macintosh computer​​.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the late 1990s and early 2000s,  the rise in open-source software changed how developers interacted with technology and each other. This shifted the approach to community-led development, paving the path toward what we know as modern DevRel, focusing on community engagement, open collaboration, and shared development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As tech companies noticed the importance of developer ecosystems, DevRel roles became more formalized, focusing on both fostering community and contributing to product development feedback loops. As part of this, we saw more teams sourcing content from their communities, emphasizing collaboration and community-generated content​​.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At its core, DevRel is a bridge between a company and its developer users. It focuses on mutual benefit: supporting developers in solving their problems and using feedback to improve products and services.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within DevRel, we see specialties such as developer advocacy, technical writing, event management, and even product development.
The focus and approach will depend on the needs of the organization, but I’ve always appreciated &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.swyx.io/measuring-devrel&quot;&gt;Swyx’s post on Measuring DevRel&lt;/a&gt; for the examination of the focus on content, community, or product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;devrel-data&quot;&gt;DevRel Data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Common Room’s DevRel report from their survey provides some additional insights into the DevRel field, including information on compensation, department alignment, and primary responsibilities:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compensation&lt;/strong&gt;: The report indicates a median total gross compensation for DevRel professionals equivalent to $175,000 USD.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Department Alignment&lt;/strong&gt;: DevRel commonly report to marketing or Developer Relations/community departments.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Primary Responsibilities&lt;/strong&gt;: According to the report, 61.5% of respondents said that creating educational content and resources is their primary responsibility. Additionally, 58.6% is tasked with delivering on a primary business objective: product awareness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;where-is-devrel-in-the-organization&quot;&gt;Where is DevRel in the Organization?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://devrelcore.com/the-role-of-developer-relations-has-fundamentally-shifted-in-the-last-decade/&quot;&gt;The Role of Developer Relations Has Fundamentally Shifted in the Last Decade&lt;/a&gt;, DevRel was initially seen as an extension of marketing while also providing support for sales.  More recently, we’ve seen more focus on community-driven efforts. 
According to the 10th Annual State of DevRel Report,  Developer Advocates make up 42.8% of DevRel roles. Still, we can also see the diverse roles within the field, including leadership and managerial roles, Dev Marketing, Dev Experience, Dev Education, and community-oriented roles, and DevRel engineers​​. Although C-Level DevRel roles weren’t typical, positions like Chief Developer Relations Officer exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DevRel’s responsibilities include digital marketing (e.g., SEO, PPC, online ads), outreach through developer newsletters, nurturing campaigns, attending events, providing product demos, generating content, technical writing, developer education, and support and success tasks. These roles require a combination of technical expertise, strong research and analytics skills, social and writing skills, and in-depth product knowledge. This may be one of the reasons we see so many career-changers gravitating towards DevRel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point is, because of the variety of skills required for DevRel, which often overlap with other departments like marketing, sales, and engineering, there’s more lack of clarity around what DevRel should be accomplishing, who they should be answering to, and who they should be supporting. There’s sometimes a tug of war over whose asks should be prioritized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;devrel-trends-and-changes&quot;&gt;DevRel Trends and Changes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pandemic had an incredible impact on DevRel, forcing those in the field to focus on virtual engagement. Although initially, it would’ve appeared that the pandemic could have decimated the DevRel industry, quick adaptations, a global audience, and isolation created opportunities to grow virtual communities and relationships. So we ended up seeing the adaptability and resilience of the DevRel community and a growth of tools and platforms targeting online developer engagement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the world recovered from the COVID-19 pandemic, we saw a gradual return to in-person developer events, including meetups and conferences. Now,  developer relations teams face the challenge of balancing the benefits of online engagement with in-person interactions. This left a lot of teams required to re-engage with the community in person and provide quality content online​​. In many circles, this led to additional tasks but not necessarily additional support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anecdotally, I saw the stress of increased responsibilities and the lack of the organization’s goals and focus lead to frustration, tension, and, ultimately, burnout. 
We’ve also noticed in recent years that the DevRel field has been moving away from general developer advocate roles towards more specialized roles. The good news is that more people have realized that each advocate has their strengths and doesn’t need to be an expert in every type of DevRel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, there will continue to be general roles, but allowing specialization allows organizations to hire someone in DevRel who more perfectly fits the organization’s goals. However, this can get complicated because many organizations hire DevRel positions without fully understanding their goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;when-companies-hire-but-dont-understand&quot;&gt;When companies hire but don’t understand&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last couple of years, we’ve seen many more companies hiring their first DevRel person. Although this might seem like a positive trend, we’ve also seen a lack of understanding, which leads to tension, often micromanaging, and DevRel teams being some of the first layoffs. 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/iandouglas736/status/1721602320302014971?s=20&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/31qvnwcinbxybufzpq1a.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ian Douglas when companies do not understand devrel tweet&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hiring a DevRel team before the product-market fit is established or without a clear strategy can result in wasted resources and potentially harm the company, mainly if the frustration of the lack of focus follows the DevRel hire to the developers they’re advocating for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developer advocates need to be able to connect with developers on a personal level and build trust. I’ve seen companies, especially startups, hire their first on a DevRel team or a whole team because advisors or a board has recommended it, but no one really knows why. They think that to succeed, there needs to be a DevRel team. If you want users or, feedback or fast growth, then they need a DevRel team. They hire someone who’s a great developer but has no experience in DevRel. They hire someone who has a lot of followers on X/Twitter or TikTok or wherever their target audience is. They hire a team and then set up meetings strategizing on “how to go viral” because they “just need to do that once.”
Developer Relations is about building trust. Building trust takes time. If a team has a deadline for building trust, then that needs to be clear from the very beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s think about this in terms of relationships. How long does it take you to trust another person? How easy is it for that trust to be broken? Say you decide to go on a date with a new person. You want to get to know them a little before you decide to commit. What if that person tells you that they LOVE pineapple on pizza? And, hey, so do you! You have something in common with that person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then, a couple of weeks later, they decide they don’t like pineapple on pizza, and they don’t like pizza at all. You don’t just wake up and decide you don’t like pizza one day. Something else must be going on behind the scenes. It’s not a huge deal (maybe), but it will take you longer to build trust and find out if that person is being honest with you. You might always wonder, “Did they just say it in the first place because they knew that’s what I wanted to hear?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, I’ve seen teams formed with a strategy in mind only to have that strategy constantly change because “it’s not working,” but there’s no clear definition of what it means to work. If you’re changing your favorite food constantly, you start losing credibility and trusting relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s not to say you can’t change your strategy or target audience. But if you want to retain that trust, you can’t change your favorite food every couple of months. A better approach might be to say, “I love pineapple pizza, and I really love pierogies now, too!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hire someone who is passionate about developers and understands their challenges.
​Developer Relations success takes time; if you don’t have that, you’re setting your team up for failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;creating-devrel-goals&quot;&gt;Creating DevRel Goals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another problem I’ve seen in the last year is that companies were throwing money at their DevRel team and saying, “Do your thing. We trust you.” And then suddenly, with the market shifting, they don’t trust DevRel anymore, and worse, they often blame them for the company’s lack of success. The problem didn’t start with the market shift. The problem began with a lack of understanding of what DevRel teams do and the company’s needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve seen some DevRel teams succeed by being semi-siloed from the rest of the company, but I also think that leaves them as a target when things start to go back. “What do you all even do?” is never a good question. If those outside the team don’t understand what DevRel does, then it’s hard to tie success to your team, and that’s what needs to be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The times of companies just handing out money are over. You can’t just go to every conference because you’re on a DevRel team. You can’t sponsor every meetup or organization that asks you. You have to be able to justify being there. That justification means that you need to be able to show how you’re providing value to the company. That’s not an unreasonable ask. The justification can’t be, “I’m going to build relationships, but I can’t tell you how long that will take to pay off.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building relationships is great, but are you building relationships for your company and establishing their credibility, or are you making friends for yourself? There’s a difference. 
If someone asked you for the elevator pitch for your company, could you give it? If someone asked you questions about the product, could you answer them or point them in the right direction? 
I’ve spent more time than I would like identifying metrics and OKRs. But if you want to survive in DevRel, it’s something that you need to understand. Companies should not throw boatloads of money at someone without seeing a return on investment (ROI).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/JesseRWeigel/status/1721578794446729535?s=20&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/pav87h3afohv3actetfl.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image description&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.advocu.com/post/trends-in-developer-relations-for-2023&quot;&gt;According to Trends in Developer Relations for 2023&lt;/a&gt;, the economic downturn has led to a reevaluation of DevRel’s role within organizations. &lt;strong&gt;Teams are being asked to focus on activities with the highest impact and justify their contributions in terms of measurable outcomes​​.&lt;/strong&gt; This is not an unreasonable ask.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There has been a growing need for DevRel teams to understand how their companies make money and to align their goals with broader business objectives, which also often means closely communicating with product, sales, and marketing teams​​.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;identifying-metrics-and-aligning-them-with-devrel-and-company-goals&quot;&gt;Identifying Metrics and Aligning Them with DevRel and Company Goals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step in measuring DevRel ROI is aligning DevRel goals with the company’s larger objectives. With this, it’s easier for other departments to see the value in DevRel activities. For example, suppose a company goal is to increase the fork rate of an open source project. In that case, DevRel strategies might include engaging with developers at relevant meetups, creating helpful content, or establishing community channels​​.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s going to look different for every team, but a general approach to aligning goals might look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Understand Company Objectives&lt;/strong&gt;. This is the building block of the rest of this approach. DevRel teams should comprehensively understand the company’s broader objectives, such as revenue targets, customer acquisition, product development, or market expansion.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identify DevRel’s Role&lt;/strong&gt;. How DevRel can contribute to these objectives? This could involve community building, developer advocacy, creating educational content, or fostering product adoption. Part of understanding the answer to this question is identifying the current painpoints of the organization. For example, maybe the product has tons of sign-ups but only a small percentage of those return to use the product. What’s happening between sign-ups and using the product? How can you re-engage those developers?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set Specific DevRel Goals.&lt;/strong&gt; Create a bridge between the company objectives and the DevRel role. For example, if a company aims to retain more users, a DevRel goal might be to improve developer onboarding and user experience.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Develop Aligned Strategies&lt;/strong&gt;. How can DevRel support these goals? It’s important to be selective about activities and events, choosing those that align best with the team’s goals and capabilities​​. This could include creating content about how to use the product, improving documentation, creating technical tutorials, or gathering developer feedback.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Track and Measure Impact&lt;/strong&gt;. Find ways to measure the impact of DevRel activities on the goals. As part of that process, regular reviews and strategy adjustments help to ensure alignment with company objectives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it’s worth noting that although this can be a tedious part of the process, it can help to understand the expectations of the DevRel team and of each teammate. It can also help team members grasp what success looks like for them. When we evaluate these goals regularly, we’re better able to pivot with changes in the company, adjust to market conditions, and prevent burnout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the challenges of tracking is that DevRel activities often don’t necessarily directly correlate to revenue, but there’s a widely held belief that it can influence it positively. 
So, for example, the goals won’t be directly related to X-increase in revenue but rather, to the creation of a strong community and product, which indirectly results in increased revenue​​.
The tricky part is finding the right balance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to quantify relationship and community building, but it’s necessary to build them. We also sometimes see a fine line between marketing and relationship building coming as a top-down directive. There are things that will be easy to track: new users, returning users, and feedback submissions. But for the things that are more challenging to track, you have to learn how to tell the story and justify their importance, even if you didn’t yesterday or last month, or at the beginning of your career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;devrel-status-its-complicated&quot;&gt;DevRel Status: It’s Complicated&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been fortunate enough to know some amazing people in Developer Relations. Over the last couple of years, I’ve learned so much through my conversations with them, reading and watching their content, and asking questions. Their authenticity and depth of knowledge allow them to be approachable, encouraging, and helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also seen a lot of bitter people in DevRel. I’m not sure if this impacts all of tech equally, but I’ve definitely seen it more than I expected in DevRel. I think some of this stems from layoffs, lack of clarity of direction, organizations blocking their teams from making progress, and burnout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And somewhere in this mix of DevRel, we start to see a little bit of an echo chamber. This is a hard one to talk about. I really love the DevRel community, but sometimes we talk to each other instead of talking to developers. We write for each other, instead of writing for users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone knows the company that they’re representing, and we all like each other’s posts and go to each other’s talks because we (maybe subconsciously) know that our fellow Developer Advocate will appear to be successful with high numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another part of the problem of the echo chamber is the lack of growth in the field that comes with it. If you’re trapped in the echo chamber, you’re less likely to hear diverse ideas and which can impede the ability to understand and address the needs and challenges of a broader developer community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the job of Developer Relations teams to understand the needs of their developer community. When you don’t spend time understanding your community, there’s a disconnect and a lack of trust. You’re missing opportunities for meaningful engagement and collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest problems caused by the DevRel echo chamber is a skewed definition of success and impact. If you’re only receiving feedback and defining (or &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; defining) metrics based on your echo chamber, you’re not getting the full understanding to be able to do your job well and to create initiatives that align with your larger organizational goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another problem of the echo chamber is your perspective can create a barrier to recognizing and responding to emerging trends, technologies, and market needs. If you’re stuck in the same conversations with the same people, there’s a higher potential for becoming outdated or irrelevant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we spend more time promoting each other’s work, and the primary growth we see is only in our DevRel audience, we’re not building authentic relationships with the audience we’ve been hired to engage with. I want to point out that this is different than forming collaborations with other DevRel teams. If you can both get value out of collaborating by expanding your audience because it makes sense for both of your audiences to use these products, then you’re doing your job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your goal should focus on advocating for developers who are using your product, understanding their needs, and supporting them through your content creation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ai-and-devrel&quot;&gt;AI and DevRel&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of everything else, the recent boom of AI has further impacted the DevRel field in various ways. DevRel teams have been exploring how AI can be helpful in key areas of their work, including using GitHub CoPilot to help generate demos and code, to write documentation, and to brainstorm talks and blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve seen this both improve the speed of people in DevRel and cause controversy, with some using it to write entire articles, talks, and more. There’s no consensus on the appropriate use of AI for content creation. One of the most critical elements of success is authenticity, and there’s a negative connotation associated with using AI as part of the creation process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Complicating things further, companies have seen the capabilities of AI and imagined them as substitutes for Developer Relations roles. Why should we hire someone when we can just use AI to complete their tasks? The problem with that logic is you’re not developing relationships, which is the primary goal of DevRel. This substitution further exemplifies that there’s a lack of understanding of what DevRel is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;todays-devrel&quot;&gt;Today’s DevRel&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re in a space now where DevRel can’t be what it was before. We’ve crossed a line past the pandemic era of fully remote, but haven’t returned to the full power of in-person–although I don’t think we’ll ever see the return of in-person events like they were before, largely for the same reasons DevRel won’t be what it was before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s been a shift to a more conservative approach to DevRel. Budgets are tighter, reporting is required. But it’s not all bad news. In fact, it’s good news for the people who are good at their job on DevRel teams. 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/hummusonrails/status/1721565788581117970?s=20&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/dcpq83k420sd7dxlr9zo.png&quot; alt=&quot;Hummus on Rails tweet&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best people will continue to find jobs, and to avoid some of the common pitfalls or mistakes we’ve looked at in this post. And with that, you’re more likely to be on a stellar team of DevRel professionals. When we find ourselves in a place where we’re surrounded by the best, we’re more likely to grow and to push each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;engineers-who-devrel&quot;&gt;Engineers who DevRel&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another option I think that we’ll see increasingly more popular is engineers who do DevRel activities. What do I mean by that? Take for instance, my team at &lt;a href=&quot;https://opensauced.pizza/&quot;&gt;OpenSauced&lt;/a&gt;. I’m on the DevEx team. We have four engineers, all of whom have written blog posts for our community blog. Most of our engineers have given tech talks, or produced other forms of content, including livestreams, TikToks, and more. Their primary role is engineering, but they’re great at DevRel and community-building goals as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Engineers taking on DevRel responsibilities might bring deeper technical expertise to community engagement, and from that, we may see a shift in content that engages a broader audience of developer expertise level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blending engineering and DevRel roles could lead to more diverse career paths, allowing professionals to develop a unique combination of skills in both development and community engagement. It also helps to close the feedback loop when engineers engage with users and community members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter what, as the role becomes more multifaceted, the best DevRel professionals will likely be those who can effectively balance technical expertise with community-building and communication skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The triple threat DevRel professional excels at technical excellence, strategic thinking, and content creation and community building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does this mean for the future of DevRel? It means that we make sure that strategy, feedback, and self-review are built into our progress. We should be looking at the strengths and weaknesses of the company, the team, and ourselves. Thinking about the future of DevRel and the instability of jobs, I see a tendency for those looking for a job to try to improve their weaknesses rather than improve their strengths. But &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/from-functioning-to-flourishing/201411/ten-reasons-to-focus-on-your-strengths&quot;&gt;studies&lt;/a&gt; have shown that it’s actually more efficient to improve on our strengths that our weaknesses. So maybe, when we think about what the future looks like for us, we should think about our strengths and how we can optimize them to achieve the goals that are in front of us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/The-Evolving-Landscape-of-DevRel</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/The-Evolving-Landscape-of-DevRel</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hiring, Firing, and Becoming Indispensable</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of COVID, I lost my job. It was hard, but I navigated through it with what seemed like most people around me and then landed another job. At the beginning of 2023, I was laid off. The feelings I had when I lost my job the first time were different. Because soon after losing my job, when I recognized those feelings of hopelessness, I accidentally started Virtual Coffee. During the pandemic, it felt like we were all in this hopelessness together, which somehow brought hope. We were still able to push each other to grow, to regroup, and to affirm that, yes, indeed, it does suck. This time around, things felt different. I recently had a conversation with some people who have been in the industry far longer than I have, and we talked about hirings, firings, and being indispensable. You’ll get the highlights of that conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-evolution-of-tech-hiring&quot;&gt;The Evolution of Tech Hiring&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hiring landscape is different than when I started in tech in 2019. There have been a lot of bootcampers and self-taught folks who were given promises of fortune and a better life only to find empty promises, rejections, and the question of whether or not they should even keep trying to find a job or to return back to their previous life. The influx of juniors, paired with not enough junior-level jobs has been more than frustrating; it’s been devastating. On top of that, we’ve seen a huge shift in tech with new trends dominating the conversation from web3 to ai, and it’s hard to figure out what basket you should put your eggs in. The tech landscape is as much about the art of adaptation as it is about innovation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-current-job-market&quot;&gt;The Current Job Market&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a large supply of people looking for work in tech. There is a decreased demand for the jobs that we saw a couple of years ago. Two years ago, before I was laid off for a second time, we saw aggressive hiring. We were starting to see recovery from the pandemic, and teams were hiring tons of people at higher-than-normal salaries. If you expect hiring today to look like hiring two years ago, you’re going to be disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;shifting-employment-dynamics&quot;&gt;Shifting Employment Dynamics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over-hiring has led to companies losing faith in existing employees. Ideas we had two years ago have become outdated more quickly than ever before. This also means that you won’t see the same perks we saw during that time. You can’t demand remote work, or signing bonuses, or educational budgets. You won’t get thousands of dollars to upgrade your home office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two years ago, you had the upper hand if you were applying for a job. It was a hiree’s market. Now, it’s the company’s market, and I don’t think that’s going to change anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s complicated, as you’ll see below. There’s an increasing number of jobs, but there were vast layoffs last year. That’s all to say that it’s not impossible out there. You just have to be strategic in your approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2023-numbers&quot;&gt;2023 Numbers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;layoffs&quot;&gt;Layoffs:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2023, over 240,000 jobs were lost in the tech industry, a 50% increase from the previous year, including companies like Google, Amazon, Microsoft, Yahoo, Meta, and Zoom. We saw startups in various sectors laying off employees or even shutting their doors. 
Here’s the monthly breakdown for layoffs in tech last year:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;January: 89,554&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;February: 40,021&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;March: 37,823&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;April: 20,014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;May: 14,928&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;June: 10,958&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;July: 10,589&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;August: 9,545&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;September: 4,632&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;October: 7,331​​
    &lt;h4 id=&quot;hiring-trends&quot;&gt;Hiring Trends&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What seems like dire circumstances if we just look at the data above, might get a little more positive if we dig into the numbers a little more:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Projected net tech employment in the U.S.: 9.4 million (CompTIA’s 2023 Cyberstates report).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Projected net new tech jobs: 272,323.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Number of postings by U.S. employers for tech job openings in 2022: 4.1 million.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Estimated direct economic output of the U.S. tech industry: $1.97 trillion, representing 8.8% of the national economy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Median tech occupation wage is 103% higher than the median national wage in the U.S.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Number of tech business establishments in the U.S.: 582,120, a 7.5% increase year-over-year.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Projected growth rate for tech jobs over the next decade is nearly twice the national jobs rate​​​​​​​​​​​​.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Bureau of Labor Statistics (BLS) projects that employment in computer and information technology occupations will grow 15% from 2020 to 2030, much faster than the average for all occupations.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Indeed currently has over 1.5 million tech jobs posted in the U.S. This suggests that there is a high demand for tech workers. LinkedIn currently has over 2.5 million tech jobs posted in the U.S.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We could dive further into the data and what it means, but I’m less interested in making predictions and understanding the data for this post than I am in talking through some of the things we can do today to improve our chances of getting hired and staying hired. What’s the most valuable code in tech? Adaptability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-importance-of-adapting-in-tech&quot;&gt;The Importance of Adapting in Tech&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve seen many well-meaning people out there giving terrible advice on finding a job. They’re giving advice based on what they know from when they tried to get hired. It’s outdated. And if there’s one thing I know about this industry, it moves fast. If you don’t stop and look around once in a while, you could miss it. People saying it’s a great time to get into tech should always follow that with, “but it’s going to be hard.” It’s hard to keep a job these days! Adapting to the tech industry’s evolution isn’t just a skill; it’s a survival strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;keeping-up-with-industry-demands&quot;&gt;Keeping Up with Industry Demands&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, I was on a plane that was sitting on the runway. Something was wrong with the door. It had “slipped.” A maintenance person came to check it out, and they tried to pound it back to where it needed to be with a wrench. At the very least, this problem needed a hammer. As you might expect, we were de-planed and had to be moved to a plane on the other side of the airport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have a toolbox that you use to do your work well and be efficient. This advice isn’t just for new folks coming into tech; it’s for anyone who wants to keep their job. If you refuse to learn the tools that allow you to do your job well, you will become “outdated,” and it will be increasingly hard to find a job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about it like this: Many or most of us in tech use Git and GitHub. For those who have been in the industry long enough, you can remember the time before those “tools” were in your “toolbox.” What if you refused to learn how to use them because you couldn’t see the value or you didn’t think they made you more efficient? You’d likely have a hard time finding a job right now. In fact, most companies assume that you know how to use these tools and don’t even list them on job descriptions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons people enjoy being in tech is because there’s always something new and shiny. It’s constantly changing, and growing, and challenging us to improve But if we’re stubborn and refuse to change and grow, we can’t expect companies to want to employ us. I know a lot of people out there believe that anyone can learn anything if given the right amount of time. Time is limited, though. You need to stand out in the same amount of time as many other applicants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not a career where you can go to the office, do your time and clock out. This might not be the popular thing to say, but if you’re behind, you will have to put time in to catch up. The reality is that if you don’t, someone who is doing that will be there to take your job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This is an opportunity for juniors to take your job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For juniors, it’s good news that some people refuse to adapt to change. You can focus on adding a new skillset to your toolbox and prove that you can do the job more effectively than someone who refuses to grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with that, there is an increasing number of jobs in the office. Because many people have become accustomed to working remotely, many job seekers aren’t prioritizing in-person locations. Juniors, working on location could be a great way to get your foot in the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter what, it’s important to remember that tech careers are less about walking a defined path and more about navigating a dynamic landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;entitlement&quot;&gt;Entitlement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No one owes you a job. If you aren’t performing, if you’re not growing, if you’re not making the company money, you can’t expect to stay employed. Don’t get me wrong, I wish that everyone in tech could keep their jobs, and everyone transitioning to tech could find a job, but we are doing a disservice to everyone if we don’t provide realistic expectations. We have to be honest about the challenges facing people looking for a job and trying to keep a job in tech right now. And with so many people looking for jobs in tech right now, there’s definitely someone who is ready to replace and outperform you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We cannot expect to have all the same things that we had a couple of years ago. And we might need to work harder to get the same things we used to have. Nobody said it doesn’t suck, but understanding the present situation can help decrease frustrations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;navigating-the-interview-process&quot;&gt;Navigating the Interview Process&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hiring is a risk. You have to go on 4+ interviews not just to prove your abilities; it’s so they can decide if it’s worth it to trust you. They’re investing in not just your salary for the year, but for years to come. They’re determining whether or not you will make a good teammate. Do you fit with the current team? How long will it take you to be a productive team member? Will you be a positive influence or will you bring the whole team down with a negative–or worse yet, an entitled–attitude? This is your opportunity to build a relationship with the people who are interviewing you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite interviews was with a future teammate. We were chatting about building community, and we disagreed with the approach on to how to build community. We both shared our approach in a respectful way, asked questions, and responded to each other. My favorite interview was a disagreement. But with that disagreement, we learned that we could trust each other even when we disagreed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every interview is an opportunity to prove that you are the best person for that position. It is nearly impossible to prove that you’re the best person for the job if you’re applying to 70 jobs. Is it possible to get a job after cold applying to 70 jobs? Sure, but the odds are not in your favor. To prove that you’re the best for the job you often have to be your own marketing, sales, and engineering team. It’s a lot, but there are people out there who are willing to do all of those things and to do them well. So you can lament that you’re required to acquire new skills to get the job, or you can learn the new skills and market and sell yourself into an interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each conversation builds trust and helps the interviewers understand if you’re a good fit for the job. Sure, interviews bring out anxiety in the best of us, and they certainly can be frustrating. But don’t forget they’re about building relationships with other people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;demonstrating-value-in-interviews&quot;&gt;Demonstrating Value in Interviews&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What you’ve done in previous jobs is both important and irrelevant. It’s important to prove you can tackle complex problems, that you can work with others, that you are able to grow and improve, that you can self-motivate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’re on the team, you have to prove yourself all over again. You have to prove that you can be a team player, that you’re willing to listen, willing to support your teammates, willing to understand the needs of the organization, and willing to do what’s necessary to advance the mission of the team and goals of the organization. Proving your worth in tech means showing not just that you can keep up, but that you can lead the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;be-indespensable&quot;&gt;Be Indespensable&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best way to keep your job is to be indispensable. That’s kind of been a theme of this blog post, but I want to specifically talk about it here. How do you become indispensable? Well, you work on a team that is clearly bringing in money for the company. I’ve heard this advice a lot recently, but I’ve also seen so much push-back from people. I’ve seen a lot of &lt;em&gt;I shouldn’t have to prove my value.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to disagree here. If you want to keep your job, you need to prove your value. How can you expect to be paid if you’re not bringing in money? As a community builder, I understand that it can be hard to demonstrate the monetary gains brought in by some of your activities, but that means that you might need to reprioritize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the company’s focus right now? How can you work towards those goals? How can you work across teams to support the goals that lead to revenue?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe you’re on a project that was making the company money and was a focus last year. Is that still the focus of the company this year? If not, find a way to get transferred to the team that is making money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To be indispensable in tech, be the solution that everyone relies on, but nobody wants to replace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of asking yourself, what are the things that will get me fired, ask yourself how you can be indispensable? You need to be the linchpin on your team. To be clear here, you don’t want to be a bottleneck. You want to make your influence know at all levels. Understand what makes money and how you can contribute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be indispensable, you should be so expensive to replace because you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;carry institutional knowledge,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;lead and mentor,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;impact the decisions made on your team,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;do your job well and ship features that affect the company’s bottom-line.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;build-your-reputation&quot;&gt;Build Your Reputation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your reputation is a huge part of getting hired. Yes, it’s hard out there, but if the majority of the content you’re putting out is negative, and you’re not sharing how you’re working to improve, then that’s what people know about you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How are you demonstrating your credibility? How are you showcasing what you can and will do? How does what you’ve done in the past demonstrate that you’re the type of person someone would want to work with?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe Previte has had one of the best job-searching strategies I’ve seen out there. His documentation of the interview experience builds his credibility and reputation both with employers and anyone who’s reading about it. You can check out some of his posts here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/jsjoeio_week-5-of-my-job-hunt-as-a-senior-full-stack-activity-7104852541586198530-6CY3?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&quot;&gt;Week 5 Job Hunt Update&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jsjoeio/status/1625599827823439873?s=61&amp;amp;t=Nf66owaOwtf64FhM4eF1_Q&quot;&gt;Top Lessons Learned&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;community-support&quot;&gt;Community Support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest piece of advice I hear is you should have built your network and engaged in communities so you can reach out when you’ve been laid off or fired. Although I agree with that, there’s a caveat there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the conversation I recently had, one of the people there said there are two types of friends. Friends that you want to empathize with you when you’re going through something hard-like a layoff-and friends who motivate you to get up, regroup, and to stop feeling sorry for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we talk about communities, it’s similar. If you’re using your communities to be the first type of friend and they’re never pushing you to grow, then you might be building the wrong type of network for job searching. In the same vein, if you’re using a community to lament to-thinking it’s the first type of friend-and you’re not showing that you’re willing to put in the work, then you might inadvertently be building a negative reputation within that community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Community members who see folks who only want to talk about the negative, constantly ask others to help with their takehome tests, and don’t show growth at all, are creating a reputation as being someone who will hold back the rest of the team, who will negatively impact the business, and would not be someone that they would recommend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find that you might be in that category, it’s time to change the narrative. When I lost my job, I contacted someone in tech I consider a mentor. He said something to me that went something like this: self-assess. What are your strengths, what are your weaknesses, where can you improve? If you want something to change, you can change yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I know that there are caveats to all of this and it’s a very complex topic. There will be exceptions to everything I’ve said in here, but there’s also a lot of truth that impacts the majority of us. I saw some of the smartest people I know in the industry get laid off last year. That’s scary. The fact is that you can do everything right, and still get laid off. But you can reduce your chances by learning and growing, building your reputation, being a positive presence in your networks and communities, and becoming an indispensable team member. Just remember,  Although layoffs are  a professional setback, they can set the stage for personal comebacks. And everyone loves a good comeback story.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Hiring,-Firing,-and-Becoming-Indispensable</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Hiring,-Firing,-and-Becoming-Indispensable</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Interview Questions to Assess Company Culture Fit</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Culture is hard to define. And we all like a different type of culture. We grow, learn, communicate in different ways; there’s not one culture that benefits everyone. Having diverse cultures is a beautiful part of the industry because there’s a space for all of us. It might be hard to find sometimes; we might need to dig. But there’s the hope that we find the space that welcomes us, as ourselves. But how do we find that? It’s something I’ve thought about a lot recently. And something I’ve failed at in my career. I’m a trusting person. I was once in a behavioral interview where the hiring manager told me that it was both a strength and weakness that I was willing to have my heart broken. I’m not interested in toughening up. I don’t particularly like my heart breaking, but I’d rather put myself into a situation where my heart is in it, than one where I don’t care; and company culture plays an important role in the interview process, my success, and the questions I ask.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;culture-questions&quot;&gt;Culture Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good culture is about communication, representation, and a willingness to learn and grow. A stagnant culture is defensive, prideful, and inflexible. Avoid those spaces if you’re hope is to learn and grow. Often indirect questions give us a better idea of what the culture is like. Below is a mix of both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;general-questions&quot;&gt;General Questions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What makes a good culture?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do you provide feedback?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do you handle an employee leaving?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How did you handle a situation in the last year where a teammate was laid off?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How would you describe your senior leadership?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;leadership-questions&quot;&gt;Leadership Questions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your team is critical, but leadership is more important for long-term strategy. Understanding how leadership makes decisions, the culture they want to lead, their style of communication may not immediately impact you, but it’s very likely that your success and longevity will be most impacted by the culture they exemplify. And by leadership, I don’t mean HR/People teams. They often want to “present” the most interesting culture to candidates. I mean top level people in the organization. Because if they don’t care about diversity, it doesn’t matter who does. If they don’t care about communication, it doesn’t matter who does. If they don’t care that the team is experts in their field, then it doesn’t matter if your team lead does. Ultimately, they make the decisions. It’s to your benefit to determine who makes the decisions that affect your potential team and then ask questions about that person or people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How would you describe senior leadership?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Who makes decisions that impact this team?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have you ever disagreed with that person/persons? - What did that look like?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What’s the long-term vision of senior leadership? - How does the impact the team? How long has that been the vision? How many times has that changed since you’ve been with the company?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Who are the competitors of the company? How are we addressing competition?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;team-lead-questions&quot;&gt;Team Lead Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are your team goals? How long have those been your goals?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What were your team goals in the last three months? Did you hit those goals? Did you evaluate those goals? Did you have a team retro?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do you evaluate progress? What do your career ladders look like? When do we get evaluated for career advancement?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Give an example of when your team failed. What did that look like? How did you respond? Did anyone from leadership respond?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What does team disagreement look like for you? How do you negotiate that experience?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do you provide your team with feedback? Is that built into your process?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;culture-specific&quot;&gt;Culture-Specific&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Describe your culture. What has been done to create that culture?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Who’s in charge of defining your culture?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How important is it for you to have people who agree with you (IMO, if the answer is very, this is a warning sign that they don’t want disagreement)?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What activities do you do as a company that shapes the organization’s culture?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What’s your mission? What are your core values (if they don’t know the answer, that tells you how seriously they’re taken)?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can I talk to someone in your organization that’s a part of {cultural initiative}?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s a starter list. As human beings, we all thrive in different environments. So finding the right environment for you, the environment that allows you to thrive, is one where you ask questions to decide if it works for you. I don’t think there’s a perfect work environment. There might be compromises, but each of us–individually–knows where we draw the line. So how close to the line do you want to compromise for company culture?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Interview-Culture-Questions</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Interview-Culture-Questions</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Nontraditional Education in the Tech Industry</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In April 2020, in the midst of the pandemic, I started having virtual coffees. It started as once-a-week sessions where we talked about the pandemic and our lives, and being laid off, and homebirths, and having kids at home, and terrible interview practices, and what our hearts were broken for. And then it went to two times a week. And then it became a slack. And eventually, we became &lt;a href=&quot;https://virtualcoffee.io/&quot;&gt;Virtual Coffee&lt;/a&gt;. We’ve grown a lot. And I know that I certainly have, but it took me a while to realize that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, I was laid off. I had just finished my first year in DevRel-though I had been doing DevRel-y things since I started coding. It’s been a lot to process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/quote.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Tweet with text: &amp;quot;My last couple of weeks in tech have been such a roller coaster. I’ve been angry, sad, excited, disappointed, tired, pessimistic, and optimistic. I’m hoping to add *happy* next week.&amp;quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During that time, I felt behind. “I’m not as good a coder as I was a year ago.” “I don’t technically have experience as a developer advocate since my title didn’t reflect that work.” “I should’ve done things differently.” “What am I going to do next?” And maybe I should’ve done things differently. And maybe I could be better at some things. But someone pointed out to me that no matter what my experience in my last role was, I still have everything I’ve learned from Virtual Coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I started going through the notes from this year, just from Virtual Coffee meetings on Tuesdays and Thursdays in 2023.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just in this year, I’ve had conversations about interviewing, job hunt, career growth, salary negotiations, severance negotiations, layoffs, core skills, effective meetings, general technology, learning, hosting websites, unions, contracting and consulting, public speaking, finances, mental health, documentation, hardware, open source, mentoring, onboarding, scope creep, company culture, scope creep, kids &amp;amp; code, teaching code, listening effectively, coding best practices, effective communication, indie-hacking, adhd, effective feedback, management, AI, security, and debugging. &lt;em&gt;This year.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friends, I have been doing this for three years and I almost forgot the value I get beyond making connections with some of the most amazing people I know. I forgot that I am learning with every conversation. And I’m learning in a way that most people don’t have the opportunity to learn. I have three years of education, learning from other people at all stages of the tech industry, at all levels, in roles that encompass &lt;em&gt;most&lt;/em&gt; of tech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am privileged to say that I have one of the best educations available to anyone in the tech industry because I have been lucky enough to listen to so many different people with so many different experiences. I don’t have experience in some roles in tech, but I have heard the pain points, the success stories, the complicated experiences, and I’ve learned from those situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re in school and you’re studying a topic, you’re often three or more times removed. The author researches other people’s experiences and reports on them, and then the teacher facilitates the conversation about those experiences. I’ve had first-person conversations with the &lt;em&gt;people who have had the experiences.&lt;/em&gt; And beyond that, I’ve had them in a space where people often feel comfortable being open and vulnerable in their conversations. And we often miss that piece in higher education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am so lucky.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My greatest strength in tech is that I have learned from all of the people around me. That I have had conversations with people when they were vulnerable, at the height of their career, making a career pivot, managing other people, being their authentic selves at Virtual Coffee. I have a Master’s Degree worth experience in the tech industry, and I’m just getting started.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/A-Nontraditional-Education-in-the-Tech-Industry</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/A-Nontraditional-Education-in-the-Tech-Industry</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Create a Positive Community for Your Open Source Project</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last couple of years, I’ve spent time maintaining open source projects and an open source community. In the projects I’ve maintained and worked on, creating a positive and safe space for community members is a priority-and one that I appreciate. The people who contribute and interact with your OSS can be the backbone of your project, and cultivating a welcoming space for them is incredibly important to the health and growth of your project and users. Here are some tips to make your open source project friendly to contributors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;create-a-solid-org-level-readme&quot;&gt;Create a Solid Org-level README&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating a solid README for your organization is kind of like the prologue in a novel. In your README, you can tell the story of your project(s) and provide context to people who are interested in being a part of the community. Your README can explain who you are, what your mission is, and how people can contribute and become a part of your community. This is your chance to onboard new community members and make them feel welcomed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;onboard-new-contributors-with-individual-repo-readmes&quot;&gt;Onboard New Contributors with Individual Repo READMEs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onboarding new contributors-and doing it well-is important to your project’s success. To do this effectively, you should create a README for each individual repository. This is where you explain what the repository is all about, the technology being used, and how people can contribute. You should also provide clear guidelines for contributors of all levels, from first-time contributors to seasoned open-sourcerors. Be transparent about your level of support for new contributors, and make it clear how much support you’re able to give.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;communication-is-key&quot;&gt;Communication is Key&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clear communication is incredibly important when it comes to creating a positive experience for contributors. You should have clear paths of communication with your community members, and make sure that everyone is aware of how to get in touch with you. A couple of ways to do this include creating a contributing guide that details the process of contributing. For example, you might ask before someone raises a new issue, they start with a discussion post. If it’s determined to be a priority, the maintainers might convert it to an issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way to support positive communication includes adding issue templates to help guide contributors. You can also add Pull Request templates to make it easier for you-as a maintainer-to understand what work has been done on the repo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, it’s essential to have a clear code of conduct (COC). This creates a safe space for all of your community members to feel supported and empowered to grow. There are lots of templates available for creating a code of conduct, so you can browse through a variety of different ones to determine what works for your community. One note-if you’re using language or taking inspiration from another organization’s COC, you should provide some attribution in yours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to learn more about this, you can check out my YouTube Video &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/scE3jVz35oI&quot;&gt;Creating a Welcoming OSS Community&lt;/a&gt; or hit me up with any questions you have.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Building-a-Supportive-Open-Source-Community</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Building-a-Supportive-Open-Source-Community</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Year in DevRel</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A year ago today, I started my first job in DevRel. Before I started, I was chatting with the CEO of a consultancy, and one of the things he told me was to document publicly the work I was doing in DevRel to be transparent and have a clear record of the things I was working on. That advice has proven to be really useful over the last year, and it was one of the reasons I started the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.to/bekahhw/series/19583&quot;&gt;Technical Community Building Series&lt;/a&gt; on Dev. It’s also helped me to think through the things I’ve learned over the last year, including the challenges I’ve faced, the successes and failures I’ve had, and my takeaways for the next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;challenges&quot;&gt;Challenges&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;metrics&quot;&gt;Metrics.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I had been doing DevRel-y things the past couple of years, I hadn’t been doing the DevRel thing of tracking everything, spreadsheets, numbers, target goals, etc. Look, I &lt;em&gt;hate&lt;/em&gt; spreadsheets. Someone opens a spreadsheet and my eyes start to glaze over. However, it turns out that spreadsheets are super important in the DevRel world to help measure if things we’re doing are working, planning for the future, and breaking down projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another part of this I found really challenging was figuring out the &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt; numbers to include. “What do you think we’ll get for participation for this event?” “I have no idea, I’ve never done this before.” I’ve had to dig a lot deeper into what I know and try to make my best guesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;burnout&quot;&gt;Burnout&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the year, I took two weeks off. I hoped to do some light work with planning, drafting some blog posts, etc. What did I do instead? I got my second stomach virus in a month, and I was totally exhausted. I didn’t want to move off the couch exhausted–and that never happens to me. Strategy. Writing. Speaking. Event organizing. Twitter spaces. Social media. Planning. Meetings. Meetings. Meetings. I didn’t take breaks when I needed to during the year. I kept pushing through. And then I was so exhausting. I am happy to report that the two weeks were enough time to bring me back to life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;successes&quot;&gt;Successes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;technical-writing-blog-posts&quot;&gt;Technical Writing Blog Posts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite things I did during the year was write a series on Technical Writing for the Deepgram blog, starting with &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.deepgram.com/technical-writing-a-beginners-guide/&quot;&gt;Technical Writing: A Beginners Guide&lt;/a&gt;. The series was well recieved and combined my background as an English teacher with my new life in DevRel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;internal-community-documentation&quot;&gt;Internal Community Documentation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last couple of years, I’ve learned a lot about the importance of internal documentation. As one co-founder said to me, “you always have to be prepared if someone is in a car crash”. I know, it’s morbid, but it’s a common expression used to demonstrate the idea that there should be clear paths of communication and documentation created in case something happens to a person, myself included. If I’m no longer at Deepgram, it’s important that the processes I’ve created still live their to support their DevRel team. This includes hackathons, Twitter Spaces, Small Group Meetups, Community Discovery, and more. It’s thorough and a pretty big time investment, but it’s also an investment in the future and part of the evaluation process. What went well with this event? How can we maximize that next time? Add it to the docs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;community-engagement&quot;&gt;Community Engagement&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether it’s been in our own Deepgram properties or in other communities or at conferences, I’ve talked to a lot of people about what we do at Deepgram and how we do a really great job. One of the phrases I’ve heard repeated quite a few times is, “I wouldn’t have known about Deepgram if you didn’t work there.” That reach is hard to quantify, but getting random DMs from folks I know asking about our product has helped me know that I’m on the right track with building trust and support in the tech community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;failures&quot;&gt;Failures&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, I failed sometimes and I’m willing to admit it. This is how you grow. Look at the failures and examine &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; they’re happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hackathons&quot;&gt;Hackathons&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We didn’t get the return we wanted with the hackathons we participated in while I was on the team. I don’t think it was due to lack of opportunities, as we provided guides, resources, and live events. I underestimated a couple of things: general interest, skill level, and product interest. It can be nerve wracking to participate in a hackathon, especially one that focuses on participants working alone or maybe in pairs. Whether it’s one week or a month, there needs to be clear interest in participating in a hackathon in general. I think there’s a sweet spot for a certain skill level. Often, folks who are newer to tech hesitate a little more when getting involved, and those who have been in tech for a while on the platforms we engaged with seem to have less interest in participating in a hackathon. Finding the right audience is key to success. Lastly, as a speech-to-text API, there are very specific or limited usecases for using DG. That’s not to say that you can’t do something interesting or creative. It’s just to say that there’s a more limited use, which leads to limited user interaction as well. The key to hackathons is finding an audience who wants to use the product first. Or, like the LEGO community, having an ongoing project submission that gets voted on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;small-group-conversations&quot;&gt;Small Group Conversations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to lie. I really thought the series of three small group conversations that were followed by a Twitter Space would be popular. There are a lot of people who are asking for 1:1 meetings to talk about breaking into tech, or want to explore different parts of tech. Hundreds of people expressed interest in the topics, sign-ups were lower than that but decent, and then only a handful showed up. I think part of the problem here is that over the pandemic, we’ve gotten used to signing up for everything and then going if we feel like it. It’s kind of a bummer as an organizer, because it becomes hard to predict what attendace will look like and make something a meaningful experience. Every Tuesday and Thursday we have small group conversations at Virtual Coffee, so it fulfills my need, but I’d love to find a way to extend that experience outside of our community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;takeaways&quot;&gt;Takeaways&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find your community. I say this all the time about everything. But being able to talk to other DevRel folks really helped me get through the last year. To hear about their struggles, to learn from them, and to find more ways to grow has been invaluable to my experience.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set boundaries. That’s one of my goals for this year. Community and DevRel never stop. It’s always onto the next thing, which is one of the reasons I love it. But I frequently load up my plate a little too high and keep taking on more things. This is not good. I’ve created a Trello board to both track what I’m doing, and to give me a visual of the things I’ve taken on to decrease the chances of me overcommitting myself.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Experiment. Sometimes you get it right, sometimes you get it wrong. But what ensures success is examining what experiments worked and why and what didn’t and why. Don’t just move on to the next thing. Understand what you’ve done and the outcomes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a lot of growing pains last year, but that means I grew a lot. I learned more about what it means to be in DevRel, what my strengths are and where my weaknesses are. I learned about working on a team, asking for help, and being more vocal about the things that I think matter. Because at the end of the day, it’s people that matter. And I’m here to make sure that we see everyone as the complex and beautiful person they are.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/A-Year-in-DevRel</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/A-Year-in-DevRel</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Assume Best Intent</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Virtual Coffee has been through a progression of announcements about who we are and what we do. And we’re very thankful for the people who have shared when we get it wrong. One of the times we’ve gotten it wrong was when we included the phrase “assume best intent.” We wanted everyone to assume that we all supported each other, saw each other with an equal lens, and wanted the best for each other. And while that would be great, the truth is that it doesn’t always happen. I’m thankful that one of our members pointed it out to us, and I’m sorry if using that phrase negatively impacted any of our members without us knowing. We’ve since updated our language, and we ask that everyone “lead with kindness, and recognize that the impact of our words matters.” We share our Code of Conduct and our Code of Conduct violation form to ensure that there’s a clear space for folks to share their experiences where they didn’t feel safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a process. When we created this script, I thought that our members felt safe because of these words. And I’m so incredibly thankful that someone was willing to tell us that this often negatively impacted people who identified as part of a diverse group of people. In fact, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/rebekahbastian/2019/06/10/microaggressions-good-intent-is-not-good-enough/?sh=66bb3b357fb1&quot;&gt;according to Forbes&lt;/a&gt;, this language can often lead to microaggressions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;brief queries, comments or actions in day-to-day life that target marginalized groups. They are often not intended to be malicious, but over time they can lead to a toxic work environment and can preclude feelings of belonging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To assume positive intent often doesn’t take into consideration the lived experiences of people who are not like us. And when we assume positive intent, we often don’t take the time to consider the feelings of the person who is on the other side of the conversation. We may say something we believe in that (inadvertently) negatively impacts someone else on our team. We might not mean it that way, but that doesn’t mean that we shouldn’t take responsibility for our own actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, when we are made aware of our actions–and every community and company should provide a clear way to provide feedback–this is our own opportunity to make amends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It starts with listening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Listen to what others have to say without responding. 
Acknowledge what they’re saying.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take time to consider how this impacts our lives, plans, and our beliefs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Apologize fully. Full stop here. If you’re interested in learning more about how to apologize, here are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.canva.com/design/DAFURf8zW74/1tSJ0BleJFdhOdbWWAwYbg/edit?utm_content=DAFURf8zW74&amp;amp;utm_campaign=designshare&amp;amp;utm_medium=link2&amp;amp;utm_source=sharebutton&quot;&gt;the slides from my How to Apologize Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We apologize to show that we’re willing to grow, accept responsibility, and do better next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some resources, as aggregated by the Virtual Coffee Community, about the problems with using the phrase “assume positive intent”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://forge.medium.com/the-problem-with-assuming-positive-intent-ea8385ce961d&quot;&gt;The Problem with Assuming Positive Intent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mailchi.mp/82edd381b364/5-ally-actions-may-20-2022&quot;&gt;Ally Actions - May 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/rebekahbastian/2019/06/10/microaggressions-good-intent-is-not-good-enough/?sh=5e7ad817fb1d&quot;&gt;Microaggressions: good intent isn’t good enough&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Virtual Coffee, we’ve put a lot of time and effort into making our Code of Conduct  a living representation of our community. That means it represents who we are and how we believe we should treat each other right now. But, as a commitment to the community, we believe in always learning and growing, and that means we might change in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Virtual Coffee’s mission is to be a welcoming tech community that allows room for growth and mentorship at all levels and to create meaningful opportunities for learning, leadership, and contribution for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of this mission, we meet people where they are; we’re willing to listen and learn from their experiences, and we’re willing to admit when we’ve messed it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re not always going to get things right. And we’re willing to apologize when we get it wrong. Because what’s more important than what we’ve done in the past is the decisions we’re making right now to make those things right. We have a growth mindset, and we want to grow together.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Assume-Best-Intent</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Assume-Best-Intent</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We All Need Good Feedback</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When you touch a hot surface, you get feedback when your hand hurts. When you hug someone you care about and who cares about you, those warm feelings are feedback. When you get a like on your post, that’s a type of feedback. Feedback helps you to learn not to touch the burner, to connect you to other people who care about you too, and to decide who to write for. Feedback helps us all to grow, and that’s why it should be built into our processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-feedback&quot;&gt;What is Feedback?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, so this isn’t a difficult question. But, I think many people think it’s getting advice on how to change or just about the mistakes they’ve made. And although that can be part of it, feedback encompasses more than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Feedback is when you receive a response for something you’ve done or created. This can include positive feedback, ways to improve, and also negative responses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-teaching-taught-me-about-feedback&quot;&gt;What Teaching Taught me about Feedback&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest parts of teaching is giving feedback. In graduate school, I wrote ten to thirty-page research papers and often received one to three pages of feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a teacher, I would provide feedback on students’ rough drafts throughout their papers and overall feedback at the end of their papers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point of giving writers thorough feedback was to help them to learn more about their strengths so they could continue to lean into them, discover where they can improve, and to understand the steps they could take to improve on their weaknesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At its core, feedback is given to help someone grow. And the problem with not getting feedback is that it becomes much harder to grow, gauge your progress, and improve. This is why it’s so essential to build feedback into your projects. Not only is it helpful to get feedback, but it’s also important to give feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;giving-good-feedback&quot;&gt;Giving Good Feedback&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; to give good feedback takes time, but here are some tips to get you started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;give-honest-feedback&quot;&gt;Give Honest Feedback&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No one wins if you’re not honest. Remember, the purpose of feedback is to help the other person to grow and improve. If you’re not honest, you’re not giving the person receiving the feedback the opportunity they deserve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;give-feeback-in-a-way-its-best-received&quot;&gt;Give Feeback in a way it’s Best Received&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not everyone accepts feedback in the same form. Find out the best way to provide feedback for each person you’re giving feedback to. It might be written, oral, synchronous conversation, or a combination of methods. Timing is also important. The person should expect feedback is coming. If they’re not expecting it, you’re creating a scenario where they may be resistant or even unable to accept feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;be-specific&quot;&gt;Be Specific&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;positive-feedback&quot;&gt;Positive Feedback&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not This&lt;/strong&gt;: This is great!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do This&lt;/strong&gt;: This is great because you’ve clearly outlined what we should expect to learn by the end of this talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The revision of feedback ensures the speaker realizes that a strength is that a clear purpose statement helps the audience to better follow and understand the talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;negative-feedback&quot;&gt;Negative Feedback&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not This&lt;/strong&gt;: “I don’t understand.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do This&lt;/strong&gt;: I don’t understand how this example demonstrates what you’re asserting above. Can you explain you X relates to Y?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This improved example gives the writer a clearer idea of what you don’t understand and where they need to clarify.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;provide-an-opportunity-for-discussion&quot;&gt;Provide an Opportunity for Discussion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback shouldn’t be a one-way street. For the full benefits of feedback, discussion is essention because it gives the other person the opportunity to ask clarifying questions, to be able to go deeper into the feedback, and even to get support for developing a plan for improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-prime-for-effective-feedback&quot;&gt;How to Prime for Effective Feedback&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the situation and environment isn’t right, even the best feedback can become ineffective. In order to create the best situation for everyone, do your best to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;be empathetic;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;be honest;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;be trusted by the person;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;be consistent in your feedback and your expectations;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;be respectful;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;be private-public feedback can feel like a public shaming;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;give clear expectations at the onset of the project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Giving feedback isn’t easy. It’s especially not easy if you’re working in a space that’s not psychologically safe, where there’s not a built-in process, and where most of the experience with feedback has revolved around negative responses. Giving good feedback takes time, empathy, and care. But ultimately, when we do make it a deliberate part of the process, and we take a person-first approach; we all benefit and are better able to grow together from the experience.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/We-All-Need-Good-Feedback</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/We-All-Need-Good-Feedback</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Career Goal Setting</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m close to completing my first year on a Developer Relations team. As I evaluate my own performance over the last year and set goals for my next year as a Technical Community Builder, I wanted to share how I’ve broken down my self-evaluation and goal setting. I don’t think you need to be on a DevRel team to find this useful. Based off of my responses to these questions, I’d like to work on creating self-evaluation points and put them in my calender during the next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;self-evaluation&quot;&gt;Self-evaluation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take some time to write down as much as you want for each of these questions. Remember, it’s important to be honest with yourself. You don’t have to show this to anyone. This is just for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-are-your-strengths&quot;&gt;What are your strengths?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can be measurable: I can get a blog post written really quickly, as demonstrated by my four published posts in the last four weeks. But don’t limit yourself to traditionally measurable things: My gut reaction is often right.  And in some cases, it might be something that you consider a strength that others might not: I take my time to make sure I’ve explored a variety of perspectives before jumping into a new initiative. Some people might think this process requires too much time and isn’t necessary. For this exercise, we don’t care about them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-are-your-weaknesses&quot;&gt;What are your weaknesses?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This might be the hard part for you. Think about what impacts your day-to-day work. I want to emphasize here that weakness doesn’t mean failure. Weakness is an opportunity to improve. For example, I think one of my weaknesses is creating technical blog posts really quickly. Maybe this is a part of my background in English education or years of writing screenplays or, maybe it’s a part of me being an introvert, but I really like taking time to think through the story I’m telling, to keep my audience engaged, and create something meaningful. It’s much easier for me to create something that I’m invested in because it’s meaningful. I’m not great at writing pieces that I’m not invested in. But realistically, this is part of devrel, so I have to find a way to get better at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;where-do-you-thrive&quot;&gt;Where do you Thrive?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only understanding where you thrive will be good for you, but it will also be good to share with your manager as well. It’s your manager’s job to figure out how to utilize your strengths as part of the job. It’s your job to share what you think those strengths are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, it’s easier for me to identify my weaknesses rather than my strengths. But I’m also super lucky to be part of a great community where I can ask people what they think my strengths are. I can say that I think communicating my ideas are a strength, thinking through ideas, identifying my/our target audience, writing about what I’m passionate about, and educating others are part of my strengths. I’ve been able to identify these as strengths based on past experiences where I’ve received feedback from my superiors in different job situations. Feedback is often a gift.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really thrive when there are clear expectations. Actually, I’d say a weakness is ambiguous situations where there are no clear goals or growth journeys.  I want to know where I can grow and think about how to break down the steps to that growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-do-i-need-to-succeed&quot;&gt;What do I Need to Succeed?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all need something different. For me, I need feedback. Feedback allows me to better understand how to grow, improve, and be consistent. It’s hard to be motivated to improve if you don’t know how to improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-do-i-want-to-be-doing-more-of&quot;&gt;What do I Want to be Doing More of?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This often builds on your strengths and weaknesses, but it doesn’t have to. There might be something that hasn’t made it onto the list that you want to do more of. I spent tens years in teaching before moving over to tech. I’ve been here about 3.5 years. I didn’t realize it would happen, but I miss teaching right now. I miss the development of the course materials. I miss having discussions with students, and learning and growing with each other. I miss the sense of completion at the end of the semester. I’d love to feel the same reward I did when I was teaching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-i-want-to-be-doing-less-of&quot;&gt;What I want to be doing less of?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What sucks your energy? What makes you feel ineffective? What are the things in your calendar that make you feel like you’ve been wasting your time? Well, you may have read my [Making Better Meetings] (https://dev.to/bekahhw/making-better-meetings-469m) post and this is a big part of what I want to decrease in the next year. I want meaningful meetings with clear agendas, that are within my work hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also spend a lot of times answering DMs with the same questions. I can’t do this next year. I have four kids who are growing so fast, and I don’t have extra time to take away from them. My goal is to blog about the most common questions I receive to share with those who DM me. I’d love to be able to DM everyone back, but at this stage of my life I don’t have the capacity. I have to draw boundaries if I want to be successful next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-three-areas-i-want-to-improve-in&quot;&gt;What are Three Areas I want to Improve in?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, now I’m getting into the goal setting aspect of this. Where do I want to improve?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Public Speaking
I’m nervous every time I speak in public. Some talks I’m better than in others. This year I gave so many brand new talks and that’s not every something I want to repeat again. I think I’ve had 8 next talks in the last year. I don’t want to write a new talk in 2023. I want to improve my speaking ability, be authentic, and stay on topic. For me, it’s important to not over prepare. It’s important to me to deliver the talk with authentic emotion. I’ll continue to apply to conferences, but I think the four talks I’ll focus on in the next year:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to Apologize&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do You Really Need a Community&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Person-Centered Approach to Tech&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Power of Storytelling
To be honest, I’m in love with each of these topics. I think that makes me more effective. I can share what I’m passionate about  in a way that other people can learn from the experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;creating-boundaries&quot;&gt;Creating Boundaries&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do a really bad job of turning off work. My husband suggested I limit the post-work times I talk about work and I think it’s a good idea. Work and community strategy shouldn’t consume my thoughts all the time. In fact, I think I’d be more effective if I didn’t think about it all the time. Allowing yourself to be deliberate with what you think about is incredibly important in working towards a peaceful life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;balancing-time&quot;&gt;Balancing Time&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems like in DevRel, there’s never enough time. There’s the next thing and endeavor. So you don’t have time to improve, grow, reassess. Next year, I’ll be focused on how I can continue to grow, learn, and support others in a way that’s reasonable for me and my family. I can’t feel like I’m always working. And it’s not fair to them to feel like they come second to a slack message. But I have to be effective during working hours. This means that I want to allot a certain amount of time to each of my main tasks during the week and make sure that I don’t prevent myself from fulfilling those tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-your-2022-highlights&quot;&gt;What are Your 2022 Highlights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This builds off of your strengths, but it requires you to be more specific. Think about the things you did, that you feel made an impact in the last year. To be honest, this is really hard for me. What makes it worse it that the last quarter of the year, I’ve been struggling to feel like I’m helping, impacting, or supporting anyone. This is certainly an argument for building in retros for your projects. If you keep track of them as you work through them, it’s easier to remember them at the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m still working on this section, but I’d love to hear what your highlights are!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;career-aspirations&quot;&gt;Career Aspirations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So many of our goals are tied to what we see in our nearby future. At some point we need to look at the bigger future and our life outside of our job. What do we want our career to look like? How can we tie all the things we’ve worked on above to be a part of our career? How does our idea of our career differ from the job we have/want now?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, I would love to keynote a conference. This ties into my goals for what I want to do more of, but does’t exactly tie into what I’m doing now. If I don’t become a keynote speaker in the next year, my team isn’t going to negatively judge my progress, but I’ll realize that I haven’t put in the work to meet my personal goals. So right now, I need to create a list of steps that will help me to actualize those goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And for this part of your growth plan, you should think about your goals and how you can break them down to meet your career aspirations. There’s nothing wrong with identifying your growth plan and following it as you move forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you evaluate yourself, your progress, and your goals, consider what might be immediate to today and what might change. How will you adapt to change? What’s important to you as you work to make change a good experience? How will you take your needs into 2023 and break down those goals? How will you track those goals? Hopefully, after I’ve broken down my goals, I’ll post and do check-ins over the next year. If you want accountability for your own goals, let me know. My first DevRel planning and goal-setting session is this coming week, but I’m always down to do async sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Career-Goal-Setting</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Career-Goal-Setting</guid>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

