<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BekahHW</title>
    <description>Code. Community. Feelings. It's all here.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Create a Positive Community for Your Open Source Project</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last couple of years, I’ve spent time maintaining open source projects and an open source community. In the projects I’ve maintained and worked on, creating a positive and safe space for community members is a priority-and one that I appreciate. The people who contribute and interact with your OSS can be the backbone of your project, and cultivating a welcoming space for them is incredibly important to the health and growth of your project and users. Here are some tips to make your open source project friendly to contributors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;create-a-solid-org-level-readme&quot;&gt;Create a Solid Org-level README&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating a solid README for your organization is kind of like the prologue in a novel. In your README, you can tell the story of your project(s) and provide context to people who are interested in being a part of the community. Your README can explain who you are, what your mission is, and how people can contribute and become a part of your community. This is your chance to onboard new community members and make them feel welcomed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;onboard-new-contributors-with-individual-repo-readmes&quot;&gt;Onboard New Contributors with Individual Repo READMEs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onboarding new contributors-and doing it well-is important to your project’s success. To do this effectively, you should create a README for each individual repository. This is where you explain what the repository is all about, the technology being used, and how people can contribute. You should also provide clear guidelines for contributors of all levels, from first-time contributors to seasoned open-sourcerors. Be transparent about your level of support for new contributors, and make it clear how much support you’re able to give.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;communication-is-key&quot;&gt;Communication is Key&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clear communication is incredibly important when it comes to creating a positive experience for contributors. You should have clear paths of communication with your community members, and make sure that everyone is aware of how to get in touch with you. A couple of ways to do this include creating a contributing guide that details the process of contributing. For example, you might ask before someone raises a new issue, they start with a discussion post. If it’s determined to be a priority, the maintainers might convert it to an issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way to support positive communication includes adding issue templates to help guide contributors. You can also add Pull Request templates to make it easier for you-as a maintainer-to understand what work has been done on the repo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, it’s essential to have a clear code of conduct (COC). This creates a safe space for all of your community members to feel supported and empowered to grow. There are lots of templates available for creating a code of conduct, so you can browse through a variety of different ones to determine what works for your community. One note-if you’re using language or taking inspiration from another organization’s COC, you should provide some attribution in yours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to learn more about this, you can check out my YouTube Video &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/scE3jVz35oI&quot;&gt;Creating a Welcoming OSS Community&lt;/a&gt; or hit me up with any questions you have.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Building-a-Supportive-Open-Source-Community</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Building-a-Supportive-Open-Source-Community</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Year in DevRel</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A year ago today, I started my first job in DevRel. Before I started, I was chatting with the CEO of a consultancy, and one of the things he told me was to document publicly the work I was doing in DevRel to be transparent and have a clear record of the things I was working on. That advice has proven to be really useful over the last year, and it was one of the reasons I started the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.to/bekahhw/series/19583&quot;&gt;Technical Community Building Series&lt;/a&gt; on Dev. It’s also helped me to think through the things I’ve learned over the last year, including the challenges I’ve faced, the successes and failures I’ve had, and my takeaways for the next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;challenges&quot;&gt;Challenges&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;metrics&quot;&gt;Metrics.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I had been doing DevRel-y things the past couple of years, I hadn’t been doing the DevRel thing of tracking everything, spreadsheets, numbers, target goals, etc. Look, I &lt;em&gt;hate&lt;/em&gt; spreadsheets. Someone opens a spreadsheet and my eyes start to glaze over. However, it turns out that spreadsheets are super important in the DevRel world to help measure if things we’re doing are working, planning for the future, and breaking down projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another part of this I found really challenging was figuring out the &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt; numbers to include. “What do you think we’ll get for participation for this event?” “I have no idea, I’ve never done this before.” I’ve had to dig a lot deeper into what I know and try to make my best guesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;burnout&quot;&gt;Burnout&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the year, I took two weeks off. I hoped to do some light work with planning, drafting some blog posts, etc. What did I do instead? I got my second stomach virus in a month, and I was totally exhausted. I didn’t want to move off the couch exhausted–and that never happens to me. Strategy. Writing. Speaking. Event organizing. Twitter spaces. Social media. Planning. Meetings. Meetings. Meetings. I didn’t take breaks when I needed to during the year. I kept pushing through. And then I was so exhausting. I am happy to report that the two weeks were enough time to bring me back to life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;successes&quot;&gt;Successes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;technical-writing-blog-posts&quot;&gt;Technical Writing Blog Posts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite things I did during the year was write a series on Technical Writing for the Deepgram blog, starting with &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.deepgram.com/technical-writing-a-beginners-guide/&quot;&gt;Technical Writing: A Beginners Guide&lt;/a&gt;. The series was well recieved and combined my background as an English teacher with my new life in DevRel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;internal-community-documentation&quot;&gt;Internal Community Documentation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last couple of years, I’ve learned a lot about the importance of internal documentation. As one co-founder said to me, “you always have to be prepared if someone is in a car crash”. I know, it’s morbid, but it’s a common expression used to demonstrate the idea that there should be clear paths of communication and documentation created in case something happens to a person, myself included. If I’m no longer at Deepgram, it’s important that the processes I’ve created still live their to support their DevRel team. This includes hackathons, Twitter Spaces, Small Group Meetups, Community Discovery, and more. It’s thorough and a pretty big time investment, but it’s also an investment in the future and part of the evaluation process. What went well with this event? How can we maximize that next time? Add it to the docs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;community-engagement&quot;&gt;Community Engagement&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether it’s been in our own Deepgram properties or in other communities or at conferences, I’ve talked to a lot of people about what we do at Deepgram and how we do a really great job. One of the phrases I’ve heard repeated quite a few times is, “I wouldn’t have known about Deepgram if you didn’t work there.” That reach is hard to quantify, but getting random DMs from folks I know asking about our product has helped me know that I’m on the right track with building trust and support in the tech community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;failures&quot;&gt;Failures&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, I failed sometimes and I’m willing to admit it. This is how you grow. Look at the failures and examine &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; they’re happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hackathons&quot;&gt;Hackathons&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We didn’t get the return we wanted with the hackathons we participated in while I was on the team. I don’t think it was due to lack of opportunities, as we provided guides, resources, and live events. I underestimated a couple of things: general interest, skill level, and product interest. It can be nerve wracking to participate in a hackathon, especially one that focuses on participants working alone or maybe in pairs. Whether it’s one week or a month, there needs to be clear interest in participating in a hackathon in general. I think there’s a sweet spot for a certain skill level. Often, folks who are newer to tech hesitate a little more when getting involved, and those who have been in tech for a while on the platforms we engaged with seem to have less interest in participating in a hackathon. Finding the right audience is key to success. Lastly, as a speech-to-text API, there are very specific or limited usecases for using DG. That’s not to say that you can’t do something interesting or creative. It’s just to say that there’s a more limited use, which leads to limited user interaction as well. The key to hackathons is finding an audience who wants to use the product first. Or, like the LEGO community, having an ongoing project submission that gets voted on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;small-group-conversations&quot;&gt;Small Group Conversations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to lie. I really thought the series of three small group conversations that were followed by a Twitter Space would be popular. There are a lot of people who are asking for 1:1 meetings to talk about breaking into tech, or want to explore different parts of tech. Hundreds of people expressed interest in the topics, sign-ups were lower than that but decent, and then only a handful showed up. I think part of the problem here is that over the pandemic, we’ve gotten used to signing up for everything and then going if we feel like it. It’s kind of a bummer as an organizer, because it becomes hard to predict what attendace will look like and make something a meaningful experience. Every Tuesday and Thursday we have small group conversations at Virtual Coffee, so it fulfills my need, but I’d love to find a way to extend that experience outside of our community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;takeaways&quot;&gt;Takeaways&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find your community. I say this all the time about everything. But being able to talk to other DevRel folks really helped me get through the last year. To hear about their struggles, to learn from them, and to find more ways to grow has been invaluable to my experience.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set boundaries. That’s one of my goals for this year. Community and DevRel never stop. It’s always onto the next thing, which is one of the reasons I love it. But I frequently load up my plate a little too high and keep taking on more things. This is not good. I’ve created a Trello board to both track what I’m doing, and to give me a visual of the things I’ve taken on to decrease the chances of me overcommitting myself.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Experiment. Sometimes you get it right, sometimes you get it wrong. But what ensures success is examining what experiments worked and why and what didn’t and why. Don’t just move on to the next thing. Understand what you’ve done and the outcomes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a lot of growing pains last year, but that means I grew a lot. I learned more about what it means to be in DevRel, what my strengths are and where my weaknesses are. I learned about working on a team, asking for help, and being more vocal about the things that I think matter. Because at the end of the day, it’s people that matter. And I’m here to make sure that we see everyone as the complex and beautiful person they are.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/A-Year-in-DevRel</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/A-Year-in-DevRel</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Assume Best Intent</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Virtual Coffee has been through a progression of announcements about who we are and what we do. And we’re very thankful for the people who have shared when we get it wrong. One of the times we’ve gotten it wrong was when we included the phrase “assume best intent.” We wanted everyone to assume that we all supported each other, saw each other with an equal lens, and wanted the best for each other. And while that would be great, the truth is that it doesn’t always happen. I’m thankful that one of our members pointed it out to us, and I’m sorry if using that phrase negatively impacted any of our members without us knowing. We’ve since updated our language, and we ask that everyone “lead with kindness, and recognize that the impact of our words matters.” We share our Code of Conduct and our Code of Conduct violation form to ensure that there’s a clear space for folks to share their experiences where they didn’t feel safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a process. When we created this script, I thought that our members felt safe because of these words. And I’m so incredibly thankful that someone was willing to tell us that this often negatively impacted people who identified as part of a diverse group of people. In fact, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/rebekahbastian/2019/06/10/microaggressions-good-intent-is-not-good-enough/?sh=66bb3b357fb1&quot;&gt;according to Forbes&lt;/a&gt;, this language can often lead to microaggressions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;brief queries, comments or actions in day-to-day life that target marginalized groups. They are often not intended to be malicious, but over time they can lead to a toxic work environment and can preclude feelings of belonging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To assume positive intent often doesn’t take into consideration the lived experiences of people who are not like us. And when we assume positive intent, we often don’t take the time to consider the feelings of the person who is on the other side of the conversation. We may say something we believe in that (inadvertently) negatively impacts someone else on our team. We might not mean it that way, but that doesn’t mean that we shouldn’t take responsibility for our own actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, when we are made aware of our actions–and every community and company should provide a clear way to provide feedback–this is our own opportunity to make amends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It starts with listening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Listen to what others have to say without responding. 
Acknowledge what they’re saying.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take time to consider how this impacts our lives, plans, and our beliefs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Apologize fully. Full stop here. If you’re interested in learning more about how to apologize, here are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.canva.com/design/DAFURf8zW74/1tSJ0BleJFdhOdbWWAwYbg/edit?utm_content=DAFURf8zW74&amp;amp;utm_campaign=designshare&amp;amp;utm_medium=link2&amp;amp;utm_source=sharebutton&quot;&gt;the slides from my How to Apologize Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We apologize to show that we’re willing to grow, accept responsibility, and do better next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some resources, as aggregated by the Virtual Coffee Community, about the problems with using the phrase “assume positive intent”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://forge.medium.com/the-problem-with-assuming-positive-intent-ea8385ce961d&quot;&gt;The Problem with Assuming Positive Intent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mailchi.mp/82edd381b364/5-ally-actions-may-20-2022&quot;&gt;Ally Actions - May 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/rebekahbastian/2019/06/10/microaggressions-good-intent-is-not-good-enough/?sh=5e7ad817fb1d&quot;&gt;Microaggressions: good intent isn’t good enough&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Virtual Coffee, we’ve put a lot of time and effort into making our Code of Conduct  a living representation of our community. That means it represents who we are and how we believe we should treat each other right now. But, as a commitment to the community, we believe in always learning and growing, and that means we might change in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Virtual Coffee’s mission is to be a welcoming tech community that allows room for growth and mentorship at all levels and to create meaningful opportunities for learning, leadership, and contribution for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of this mission, we meet people where they are; we’re willing to listen and learn from their experiences, and we’re willing to admit when we’ve messed it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re not always going to get things right. And we’re willing to apologize when we get it wrong. Because what’s more important than what we’ve done in the past is the decisions we’re making right now to make those things right. We have a growth mindset, and we want to grow together.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Assume-Best-Intent</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Assume-Best-Intent</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We All Need Good Feedback</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When you touch a hot surface, you get feedback when your hand hurts. When you hug someone you care about and who cares about you, those warm feelings are feedback. When you get a like on your post, that’s a type of feedback. Feedback helps you to learn not to touch the burner, to connect you to other people who care about you too, and to decide who to write for. Feedback helps us all to grow, and that’s why it should be built into our processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-feedback&quot;&gt;What is Feedback?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, so this isn’t a difficult question. But, I think many people think it’s getting advice on how to change or just about the mistakes they’ve made. And although that can be part of it, feedback encompasses more than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Feedback is when you receive a response for something you’ve done or created. This can include positive feedback, ways to improve, and also negative responses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-teaching-taught-me-about-feedback&quot;&gt;What Teaching Taught me about Feedback&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest parts of teaching is giving feedback. In graduate school, I wrote ten to thirty-page research papers and often received one to three pages of feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a teacher, I would provide feedback on students’ rough drafts throughout their papers and overall feedback at the end of their papers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point of giving writers thorough feedback was to help them to learn more about their strengths so they could continue to lean into them, discover where they can improve, and to understand the steps they could take to improve on their weaknesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At its core, feedback is given to help someone grow. And the problem with not getting feedback is that it becomes much harder to grow, gauge your progress, and improve. This is why it’s so essential to build feedback into your projects. Not only is it helpful to get feedback, but it’s also important to give feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;giving-good-feedback&quot;&gt;Giving Good Feedback&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; to give good feedback takes time, but here are some tips to get you started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;give-honest-feedback&quot;&gt;Give Honest Feedback&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No one wins if you’re not honest. Remember, the purpose of feedback is to help the other person to grow and improve. If you’re not honest, you’re not giving the person receiving the feedback the opportunity they deserve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;give-feeback-in-a-way-its-best-received&quot;&gt;Give Feeback in a way it’s Best Received&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not everyone accepts feedback in the same form. Find out the best way to provide feedback for each person you’re giving feedback to. It might be written, oral, synchronous conversation, or a combination of methods. Timing is also important. The person should expect feedback is coming. If they’re not expecting it, you’re creating a scenario where they may be resistant or even unable to accept feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;be-specific&quot;&gt;Be Specific&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;positive-feedback&quot;&gt;Positive Feedback&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not This&lt;/strong&gt;: This is great!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do This&lt;/strong&gt;: This is great because you’ve clearly outlined what we should expect to learn by the end of this talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The revision of feedback ensures the speaker realizes that a strength is that a clear purpose statement helps the audience to better follow and understand the talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;negative-feedback&quot;&gt;Negative Feedback&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not This&lt;/strong&gt;: “I don’t understand.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do This&lt;/strong&gt;: I don’t understand how this example demonstrates what you’re asserting above. Can you explain you X relates to Y?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This improved example gives the writer a clearer idea of what you don’t understand and where they need to clarify.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;provide-an-opportunity-for-discussion&quot;&gt;Provide an Opportunity for Discussion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback shouldn’t be a one-way street. For the full benefits of feedback, discussion is essention because it gives the other person the opportunity to ask clarifying questions, to be able to go deeper into the feedback, and even to get support for developing a plan for improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-prime-for-effective-feedback&quot;&gt;How to Prime for Effective Feedback&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the situation and environment isn’t right, even the best feedback can become ineffective. In order to create the best situation for everyone, do your best to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;be empathetic;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;be honest;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;be trusted by the person;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;be consistent in your feedback and your expectations;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;be respectful;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;be private-public feedback can feel like a public shaming;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;give clear expectations at the onset of the project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Giving feedback isn’t easy. It’s especially not easy if you’re working in a space that’s not psychologically safe, where there’s not a built-in process, and where most of the experience with feedback has revolved around negative responses. Giving good feedback takes time, empathy, and care. But ultimately, when we do make it a deliberate part of the process, and we take a person-first approach; we all benefit and are better able to grow together from the experience.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/We-All-Need-Good-Feedback</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/We-All-Need-Good-Feedback</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Career Goal Setting</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m close to completing my first year on a Developer Relations team. As I evaluate my own performance over the last year and set goals for my next year as a Technical Community Builder, I wanted to share how I’ve broken down my self-evaluation and goal setting. I don’t think you need to be on a DevRel team to find this useful. Based off of my responses to these questions, I’d like to work on creating self-evaluation points and put them in my calender during the next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;self-evaluation&quot;&gt;Self-evaluation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take some time to write down as much as you want for each of these questions. Remember, it’s important to be honest with yourself. You don’t have to show this to anyone. This is just for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-are-your-strengths&quot;&gt;What are your strengths?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can be measurable: I can get a blog post written really quickly, as demonstrated by my four published posts in the last four weeks. But don’t limit yourself to traditionally measurable things: My gut reaction is often right.  And in some cases, it might be something that you consider a strength that others might not: I take my time to make sure I’ve explored a variety of perspectives before jumping into a new initiative. Some people might think this process requires too much time and isn’t necessary. For this exercise, we don’t care about them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-are-your-weaknesses&quot;&gt;What are your weaknesses?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This might be the hard part for you. Think about what impacts your day-to-day work. I want to emphasize here that weakness doesn’t mean failure. Weakness is an opportunity to improve. For example, I think one of my weaknesses is creating technical blog posts really quickly. Maybe this is a part of my background in English education or years of writing screenplays or, maybe it’s a part of me being an introvert, but I really like taking time to think through the story I’m telling, to keep my audience engaged, and create something meaningful. It’s much easier for me to create something that I’m invested in because it’s meaningful. I’m not great at writing pieces that I’m not invested in. But realistically, this is part of devrel, so I have to find a way to get better at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;where-do-you-thrive&quot;&gt;Where do you Thrive?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only understanding where you thrive will be good for you, but it will also be good to share with your manager as well. It’s your manager’s job to figure out how to utilize your strengths as part of the job. It’s your job to share what you think those strengths are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, it’s easier for me to identify my weaknesses rather than my strengths. But I’m also super lucky to be part of a great community where I can ask people what they think my strengths are. I can say that I think communicating my ideas are a strength, thinking through ideas, identifying my/our target audience, writing about what I’m passionate about, and educating others are part of my strengths. I’ve been able to identify these as strengths based on past experiences where I’ve received feedback from my superiors in different job situations. Feedback is often a gift.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really thrive when there are clear expectations. Actually, I’d say a weakness is ambiguous situations where there are no clear goals or growth journeys.  I want to know where I can grow and think about how to break down the steps to that growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-do-i-need-to-succeed&quot;&gt;What do I Need to Succeed?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all need something different. For me, I need feedback. Feedback allows me to better understand how to grow, improve, and be consistent. It’s hard to be motivated to improve if you don’t know how to improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-do-i-want-to-be-doing-more-of&quot;&gt;What do I Want to be Doing More of?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This often builds on your strengths and weaknesses, but it doesn’t have to. There might be something that hasn’t made it onto the list that you want to do more of. I spent tens years in teaching before moving over to tech. I’ve been here about 3.5 years. I didn’t realize it would happen, but I miss teaching right now. I miss the development of the course materials. I miss having discussions with students, and learning and growing with each other. I miss the sense of completion at the end of the semester. I’d love to feel the same reward I did when I was teaching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-i-want-to-be-doing-less-of&quot;&gt;What I want to be doing less of?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What sucks your energy? What makes you feel ineffective? What are the things in your calendar that make you feel like you’ve been wasting your time? Well, you may have read my [Making Better Meetings] (https://dev.to/bekahhw/making-better-meetings-469m) post and this is a big part of what I want to decrease in the next year. I want meaningful meetings with clear agendas, that are within my work hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also spend a lot of times answering DMs with the same questions. I can’t do this next year. I have four kids who are growing so fast, and I don’t have extra time to take away from them. My goal is to blog about the most common questions I receive to share with those who DM me. I’d love to be able to DM everyone back, but at this stage of my life I don’t have the capacity. I have to draw boundaries if I want to be successful next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-three-areas-i-want-to-improve-in&quot;&gt;What are Three Areas I want to Improve in?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, now I’m getting into the goal setting aspect of this. Where do I want to improve?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Public Speaking
I’m nervous every time I speak in public. Some talks I’m better than in others. This year I gave so many brand new talks and that’s not every something I want to repeat again. I think I’ve had 8 next talks in the last year. I don’t want to write a new talk in 2023. I want to improve my speaking ability, be authentic, and stay on topic. For me, it’s important to not over prepare. It’s important to me to deliver the talk with authentic emotion. I’ll continue to apply to conferences, but I think the four talks I’ll focus on in the next year:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to Apologize&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do You Really Need a Community&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Person-Centered Approach to Tech&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Power of Storytelling
To be honest, I’m in love with each of these topics. I think that makes me more effective. I can share what I’m passionate about  in a way that other people can learn from the experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;creating-boundaries&quot;&gt;Creating Boundaries&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do a really bad job of turning off work. My husband suggested I limit the post-work times I talk about work and I think it’s a good idea. Work and community strategy shouldn’t consume my thoughts all the time. In fact, I think I’d be more effective if I didn’t think about it all the time. Allowing yourself to be deliberate with what you think about is incredibly important in working towards a peaceful life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;balancing-time&quot;&gt;Balancing Time&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems like in DevRel, there’s never enough time. There’s the next thing and endeavor. So you don’t have time to improve, grow, reassess. Next year, I’ll be focused on how I can continue to grow, learn, and support others in a way that’s reasonable for me and my family. I can’t feel like I’m always working. And it’s not fair to them to feel like they come second to a slack message. But I have to be effective during working hours. This means that I want to allot a certain amount of time to each of my main tasks during the week and make sure that I don’t prevent myself from fulfilling those tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-your-2022-highlights&quot;&gt;What are Your 2022 Highlights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This builds off of your strengths, but it requires you to be more specific. Think about the things you did, that you feel made an impact in the last year. To be honest, this is really hard for me. What makes it worse it that the last quarter of the year, I’ve been struggling to feel like I’m helping, impacting, or supporting anyone. This is certainly an argument for building in retros for your projects. If you keep track of them as you work through them, it’s easier to remember them at the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m still working on this section, but I’d love to hear what your highlights are!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;career-aspirations&quot;&gt;Career Aspirations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So many of our goals are tied to what we see in our nearby future. At some point we need to look at the bigger future and our life outside of our job. What do we want our career to look like? How can we tie all the things we’ve worked on above to be a part of our career? How does our idea of our career differ from the job we have/want now?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, I would love to keynote a conference. This ties into my goals for what I want to do more of, but does’t exactly tie into what I’m doing now. If I don’t become a keynote speaker in the next year, my team isn’t going to negatively judge my progress, but I’ll realize that I haven’t put in the work to meet my personal goals. So right now, I need to create a list of steps that will help me to actualize those goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And for this part of your growth plan, you should think about your goals and how you can break them down to meet your career aspirations. There’s nothing wrong with identifying your growth plan and following it as you move forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you evaluate yourself, your progress, and your goals, consider what might be immediate to today and what might change. How will you adapt to change? What’s important to you as you work to make change a good experience? How will you take your needs into 2023 and break down those goals? How will you track those goals? Hopefully, after I’ve broken down my goals, I’ll post and do check-ins over the next year. If you want accountability for your own goals, let me know. My first DevRel planning and goal-setting session is this coming week, but I’m always down to do async sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Career-Goal-Setting</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Career-Goal-Setting</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Making Better Meetings</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We’ve all been there: a meeting that should’ve been an email or a slack message or really nothing at all. There are few things that frustrate me more than wasted time. I’ve said this before, moms are great employees because we don’t have any time to waste. Not every second of the day has to be “productive” but when you have an activity that has a primary purpose of being productive, you better make sure that it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yet, here we are, many of us living in a remote-work world settling for meetings that decrease productivity, motivation, and increase frustration. Why have we let it get to this point? And why do we ignore the fact that we’re wasting company money by holding a bunch of bad meetings? Because it’s easy. Because planning a meeting should be just as important as the meeting itself. Let’s stop having bad meetings and dive into ways to make our meetings better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;this-meeting-shouldve-beennot-a-meeting&quot;&gt;This Meeting Should’ve Been…Not a Meeting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s think of meetings as speedbumps. When you intersperse them throughout people’s days, you slow down their momentum. If there’s a meeting every other hour, you can’t expect the same productivity from your employee as you should if they have a solid block of time to work on projects, research, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it’s worth noting that meetings should not be a remote-first company’s first response to a question or issue that comes up, especially if you’re working with an international team. I don’t know if I’m ready to say they should be a last resort, but I’m close to making that assertion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sending a slack message or an email rather than having a meeting allows employees to choose when the read the message and builds flexibility into the schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should also recognize that meetings do not utilize the strengths of everyone. Extroverts and external processors are more likely to benefit from meetings, whereas introverts often benefit from having time to think through ideas, process, and return to a discussion–written or verbal–later. If you’re relying on meetings, you’re not taking into consideration the introverts in your group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;planning&quot;&gt;Planning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does it mean to plan a meeting? Don’t you just throw some calendar invites out to everyone that you think could or should be interested? This is what often happens and this is one of the reasons meetings are so wasteful. Planning meetings should take time, consideration, and more effort than spelling someone’s email correctly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;who-needs-to-be-there&quot;&gt;Who needs to be there?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not a dump-it cake. We don’t need everyone who touches the topic to be there. I’ve always loved the idea of calculating the cost of every meeting as a deterrent for inviting everyone. You can do that by calculating the hourly wage of everyone there and adding it up based on the time the meeting takes. That doesn’t mean that you should get rid of all meetings or slash and burn the invite list. It means that you need to take the time to determine who should  be there. How do you do that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start with your long list of people and let’s narrow it down together by answering the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What’s the purpose of the meeting?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Who makes decisions about this topic?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is their input an essential part of the conversation? I want to note here that there’s conversational input and there’s input that can come as part of a slack message or email. Not everyone has to be part of the conversation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Who is a subject matter expert?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Who has institutional knowledge that would benefit from being there to share or to listen?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should not ask yourself “who will get upset if I don’t invite them?” Although this is a common part of the thought process, it shouldn’t influence the invite list. What it should influence is clear communication. Why do you think this person’s feelings will be hurt? How can you communicate to them that it’s not a good use of their time or part of their job?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;scheduling-etiquette&quot;&gt;Scheduling Etiquette&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t just throw meetings on someone’s calendar without context.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t move or cancel meetings on someone’s calendar without touching base with those invited.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide an agenda.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you expect work to be done beforehand, put it in the invite.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t put an invite on someone’s calendar for a time outside of their work hours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;meeting-etiquette&quot;&gt;Meeting Etiquette&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;pre-meeting-best-practices&quot;&gt;Pre-meeting best practices&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make the meeting most efficient and a good use of people’s time, it’s important to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Establish a clear purpose. For example, to finalize strategy for a new campaign.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Define expectations both of the meeting and of the participants. Do you want the participants to share what they think are important tasks that need to be completed before launching a campaign? Do you want to discuss strengths and weaknesses?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask the participants what they want to include as part of the agenda.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clearly explain any pre-work that needs to be done as well as expectations for the day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;meeting-best-practices&quot;&gt;Meeting best practices&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please, please do not start a meeting with “I just thought we could chat about X” and then stare blankly at the zoom screen. What about X? Having an agenda is having an outline for a meeting. Use it. Other things that are important:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stick to the agenda, but don’t be so rigid to not allow any other discussion.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be respectful of people’s time. If you say the meeting is going to be an hour, it shouldn’t end after two hours.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have an agenda enforcer. You might feel some scope creep in your meeting. It happens. Sometimes it’s productive. Most times it impedes the ability to have a productive meeting. Generally, the meeting leader should be the agenda enforcer who makes sure this doesn’t happen. “That’s a really great insight, Sam. This doesn’t quite fit into the scope of today’s meeting, but we should talk about this in slack after the meeting.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have a time keeper. If you want to accomplish everything on your agenda, you need to have a sense of how long everything will take. This might mean limiting discussion time. If you’ve scheduled 5 minutes to talk about the strengths of the team, and one person has talked for the last four minutes, you’re not utilizing your time as you planned. Having a person who can say, “James, let’s give someone else time to share” or “We’re getting close to time on this. Let’s summarize the main points and determine if this part of the conversation needs to happen in slack afterward.”
Leave time to answer questions and determine next steps at the end.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make space for everyone. Often the loudest people in the room are the ones who have the opportunity to share. To ensure everyone has an opportunity to be heard, utilize support features like the handraise function and the chat to allow people to participate in ways that work for them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running a good meeting is a lot like writing a good paper. You start with a purpose–a thesis if you’re a English nerd like me–and then you create an outline of the main points of the meeting. The meeting becomes the step of the process where you fill in the outline. You have the discussion, collect the evidence, make your arguments, and by the end you should have a conclusion. At the very least, you should be able to end a chapter that will lead into the next one. The reader/participant will feel satisfied at the end of the meeting if it’s a good use of their time. They’ll be motivated to work on the next chapter. They’ll feel appreciated for accomplishing their work and meeting expectations. And if you’re not sure if you’ve hit the mark, all you have to do is ask for feedback. If you’ve cultivated a culture of honesty and sharing, this shouldn’t be a problem. If you haven’t…well, that’s a different blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Making-Better-Meetings</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Making-Better-Meetings</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Writing Your First Conference Proposal</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Maybe you’ve been thinking about speaking at a conference, but you’re nervous. You’ve been to a conference or more than you can count, you’ve thought “I could’ve given a talk like that”, and you’ve even scrolled over some cfps trying to get up the courage to submit a talk. And then you don’t. Maybe it’s because your nerves or imposter syndrome got the best of you or maybe the deadline passed and you just couldn’t think up any ideas that you thought were worth talking about. Hopefully, this blog post will help you discover an idea and/or overcome the fear of submitting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-to-consider-before-submitting&quot;&gt;What to Consider Before Submitting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First things first, just because you submit, doesn’t mean you’ll get accepted. There are frequently way more applicants than accepted talks. Don’t let that discourage you, just know that you’re in good company 😀 If nerves are preventing you from submitting, I want you to know that I’ve been doing this for a couple of years now and I still get nervous when I submit and even more when I speak. But there’s always value in pushing yourself out of your comfort zone, leading to growth, innovation, and self-satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you’re researching the submission process, there are a couple of different ways you can get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reach out to other speakers to ask them about their experience. If it’s your first talk, you want to make sure that the conference speaking experience is a good one.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Think about the conferences you’ve most enjoyed. This might help decrease some of the nerves.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://sessionize.com/&quot;&gt;sessionize.com&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.papercall.io/&quot;&gt;papercall.io&lt;/a&gt; to discover conferences with open calls for proposal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-writing-the-proposal&quot;&gt;On Writing the Proposal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you speak for the first time, it’s helpful to speak on a topic that you know and understand well. That frees up some brain space that would’ve otherwise been devoted to worrying about whether or not you can handle answering questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s get started by jotting down some ideas that you’re comfortable talking about. Depending on your technical level, this could vary. I prefer speaking on core skills topics most of the time, so I generally stay in that track. Some examples might be: “how to navigate the self-taught journey”, “Migrating your project to TypeScript”, “Which JS framework should you learn next?”, or “The Importance of  Community for Developer Growth.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might think, I’ve heard these talks though. That’s fine. That doesn’t mean that the talk you give should be the same. You have a unique voice. Use that to your advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now, jot down 3-5 subtopics under each of those topics. What could you talk about as you develop those ideas? For example, if I were brainstorming about “How to Navigate the Self-Taught Journey,” I would add bullet points for finding community, working on collaborative projects, and incorporating open-source contributions into my learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you have some subtopics, you can write more about them. But before you dive right in, consider the purpose of the talk–this will determine how you develop the talk. Do you want it to inspire, teach, motivate the audience to do something, or inform the audience? Identifying the purpose might seem like a minor step, but it’s incredibly important to developing the content, proposal, and tone of the talk. And if you know why you’re giving the talk, you’ll better be able to get your audience on the same page. Note: I did not include promoting myself or my product in the purpose section. It’s possible to do that well in a talk, but it shouldn’t be the primary purpose or your audience will check out quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step is to think about why this should be a talk and not a blog post or tiktok or some other form of media. Why is sharing as a talk important? Maybe you’re planning on live coding and taking questions live. Maybe there’s interactivity built in. Maybe the impact of sharing live in front of the audience is really important. How can you convey this in your cfp?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, what do you want the audience to take away from your talk? Are there next steps? Do you want them to take an action? Do you want them to put a new behavior into practice?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;writing-your-proposal&quot;&gt;Writing Your Proposal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don’t have a lot of words to write your talk, so you have to get to the point. Find a way to grab the reader’s attention, convey your purpose, and highlight your main ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure your proposal has a logical order. You wouldn’t start with writing a test if your audience doesn’t know what testing is, right? Each part of your presentation–and by extension, your cfp, should flow logically. If the reader can’t follow what you’re saying or understand where you’re going in your presentation, you haven’t properly organized the proposal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We each have a style or voice, just as each conference has its own style. This means you might need to revise the proposal as you submit to a different conference. Things to consider: Is this a formal situation or something more casual? Are jokes appropriate or problematic? Should they be included in your cfp? How important is style to the conference?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot to consider when you write cfps, but don’t get hung up on it. Write it, and ask for feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;examples&quot;&gt;Examples&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the description-what I used when I submitted my talk-for my first talk of the new year for &lt;a href=&quot;https://yougotthis.io/events/broadcasting-service/&quot;&gt;You Got This! Conf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Sometimes apologies don’t quite &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; right, and it can be hard to figure out why. Often, it’s because they weren’t really apologies; they were performances made to deflect responsibility, excuse away behavior, and with the hopes of calming negative feelings. Whether you’ve received one of these types or given them yourself, this talk will allow you to recognize what makes a good and authentic apology and how to construct one yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href=&quot;https://cfe.dev/sessions/testing-with-cypress/&quot;&gt;Browser Testing with Cypress for CFE.dev&lt;/a&gt; talk:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We write tests to give us confidence that things won’t break and to save time. But it takes time to write tests. How does that save time? When you use the JavaScript testing framework Cypress, you’ve got the Swiss Army Knife of end-to-end testing. Cypress has bundled together the tools you need to get up and testing fast. We’ll take a look at how to get started with Cypress, how to write reliable tests to give you confidence in your code, and how using Cypress enables you to get the mission accomplished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;moving-forward&quot;&gt;Moving forward&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve written your cfp, it’s great to get some feedback from others. Often, because we’re the ones writing the description, it can be hard to see what we’ve missed, whether or not we’re clear, or if we’ve accurately conveyed the topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ask a person to read through your cfp. Then ask them to tell you what they think the talk will be about. Have they captured the main ideas of your talk? Did they convey what you want to talk about? Did they miss a key idea or misunderstand the purpose of the talk? Having that feedback can be a great way to improve your cfp and your writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, this is enough to get you to submit. I have a lot more tips for actually preparing for and giving the talk. If you want to hear those, let me know!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Writing-Your-First-Conference-Proposal</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Writing-Your-First-Conference-Proposal</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>This week in DevRel: Planning and Progress</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Some weeks, you’ll have a lot of tangible checkmarks on your to-do list. Other weeks, it feels like you haven’t done anything. Still, in reality, you’ve spent a lot of time planning for things in the future, thinking deliberately–rather than just reacting–about the people in your community, their needs, and how you can support them as the community builder for your own community. This is one of those weeks for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;blogging&quot;&gt;Blogging&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still got my blog posts in. We’re announcing the winners of the Deepgram + Learn Build Teach Hackathon, and I added to my Reading List series with a post on &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.to/bekahhw/reading-list-the-community-builder-edition-3d2h&quot;&gt;Community Builders Resources&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;live-events&quot;&gt;Live Events&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went for two this week, with a Twitter Space with Julia Seidman, “Developer Growth: Writing to Learn” and a livestream working through adding Cypress to a React Application for a blog post that will come out later this month. I’ve been working on building a practice of creating content and repurposing it. And that’s been on my mind this week as I did these live events. I may write a post with the takeaways of the Twitter Space, but for now, you can see &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/DeepgramAI/status/1590402513488203777?s=20&amp;amp;t=oiC2XyLeYyHboxBvGDo7yA&quot;&gt;my notes&lt;/a&gt; in the Twitter thread from the space. (If you’ve seen any cool ways to reuse Twitter Space content, I’d love to know!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;processes-and-planning&quot;&gt;Processes and Planning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last couple of years, I’ve talked about a content creation lifecyle. Here’s what I mean by that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Say you want to publish a tutorial. The end goal of the content creation lifecycle would be to end up with a video, written tutorial, code snippets, Twitter thread and maybe a Space, live demo, and a short-form video. The video might be a livestream of you implementing what you’ll be writing about for the tutorial–but it’s something you can definitely link to. From that video, you can clip for your short-form video (YouTube, Instagram Reels, tiktok, etc.). You can even transcribe the video to help write the blog post and the Twitter Thread. Finally, that code gets put into stackblitz or codepen so users can test it out live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t nailed that process quite yet because of the pace we’re going in other things, but I keep thinking, “What about the community?” For me, so much of the content that I create is to build community. I write for myself, but I love when it means that I get to engage with others and hear their thoughts on what I’m writing about. Where does the community fit into the content creation lifecycle? We have to find ways to make space for those in our community to be a part of this conversation. Because that’s the content I want to produce; the kind of content that creates conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of my planning and thinking deliberately about this included using Twitter Spaces to extend the conversation. What have I started talking about? How can I continue this conversation with interested people? Can I repurpose Twitter Spaces to be a blog post? Sure. They can extend the conversation from both angles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how else can we extend the conversation? Well, we can do things the old-fashioned way and have a face-to-face conversation. Why not have a small group discussion about the topic or a workshop if it’s a tutorial? Interact with the community in ways that are meaningful to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m ideating on the best way to do this and ensuring I’m not building an echo chamber. I want to find more ways to listen to others and learn from each other. To do this properly, however, requires quite a bit of planning, and it always feels like there’s not enough time in the day to do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One way I’m ensuring my planning time happens is committing to time away from the computer and phone to think things through. Write them down on notebook paper, and remove the distractions of slack, email, Twitter, etc. And since I work from home, it’s also important to remove the distractions of laundry, kids, and the bills sitting on my desk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to try to commit to one morning or afternoon a week outside of the home without device distractions. I’ve tried this before on Friday afternoons because I thought it would help me to disconnect from work for the weekend, but then I ended up feeling like there were too many loose ends to wrap up, and I couldn’t turn work off. For now, I’ll play it by ear and find a good two to three-hour time period where I can be afk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another part of the planning process I worked on this week was community campaigns. It might seem like creating simple discussion posts doesn’t require that much time, but if you want to weave a story of information, listen to what the community wants and needs, and create plans to act on those wants and needs, you have to research and create space for meaningful conversations with consistency. A lot of times that means building out posts ahead of time and implementing them when the situation is right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I build out these processes and think more holistically about all the things that I’m creating, I want to find a way to make this a smooth and repeatable process. It’s not something I’ve thought deeply about, but I hope that as I build in time to think through these things, I’ll be able to share more about that here. And that we can maybe even have a conversation about it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/This-Week-in-DevRel-Planning-and-Progress</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/This-Week-in-DevRel-Planning-and-Progress</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reading List: The Community Builder Edition</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I go through phases of information consumption. At the beginning of the pandemic, it was tech podcasts all the time. Then it was audiobooks, mostly self-help kind of stuff. Now it’s a mix of audiobooks, podcasts, and YouTube videos of all different genres. But sprinkled in there has been a variety of Community Building books and Resources. I’m going to use the word “Reading List” loosely here in place of a resource list, as I give you some of my favorites over the past couple of years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;books-for-community-builders&quot;&gt;Books for Community Builders&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-art-of-community-seven-principles-for-belonging-by-charles-h-vogl&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.charlesvogl.com/books&quot;&gt;The Art of Community: Seven Principles for Belonging&lt;/a&gt; by Charles H. Vogl&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Community is the opposite of isolation; there’s a need for community now more than ever as there’s an increasing report of lonliness. This book describes seven principles of community. Among the key takeaways are creating boundaries to preserve your community, finding ways to onboard new members, creating unique rituals for belonging, connection through storytelling, community structure and organization, and defining what makes your community special and allowing for unique growth within your community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-business-of-belonging-by-david-spinks&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/55180348-the-business-of-belonging&quot;&gt;The Business of Belonging&lt;/a&gt; by David Spinks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Focusing on brands and brand communities, Spinks dives into strategy, higher-order thinking, and measuring the activities that inform business decisions. As Spinks writes about community, he defines it in terms of the potential it has for the business, from evangelists to employees. What’s important to remember when we talk about communities and business is that authenticity has to be at the center of it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-art-of-gathering-by-priya-parker&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.priyaparker.com/book-art-of-gathering&quot;&gt;The Art of Gathering&lt;/a&gt; by Priya Parker&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the great things about this book was the examples. Learning through experiences makes the concepts come to life, and helps you to determine your role as part of the community, as the host, as the guest. Understanding our role, and the roles of those around us can empower us to create gathering spaces that address the needs and imagination of all those involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;stories-that-stick-how-storytelling-can-captivate-customers-influence-audiences-and-transform-your-business-by-kindra-hall&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Stories-That-Stick-Storytelling-Captivate-ebook/dp/B07KF2328Z&quot;&gt;Stories That Stick: How Storytelling Can Captivate Customers, Influence Audiences, and Transform Your Business&lt;/a&gt; by Kindra Hall&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might not seem like it fits with the other books in this list, but you have to be able to share the story of your community, whether that’s with people who may become community members, current members, or potential funders. Knowing how to share the story of your community, its purpose, and why it matters helps us to connect to others. Humans weren’t meant to be alone; we’re meant to be together and have meaningful experiences. These experiences come through stories. But whether or not those stories impact the listener depends on how we tell them. This book helps you to share them in a meaningful way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;podcasts-about-community-building&quot;&gt;Podcasts about Community Building&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-before-the-lock&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ib4tl.fm/&quot;&gt;In Before the Lock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love In Before the Lock, not only because the hosts Erica Kuhl and Brian Oblinger are incredibly knowledgeable, insightful, and report on industry news, but also because they’re fun to listen to and have quality audio. They don’t always agree–and those are some of the best episodes–but they bring examples and reasoning to their opinions. Another great part of the podcast is they aren’t shy about sharing their hot takes. If you want to listen to a podcast where the hosts aren’t afraid of pushing you to think about things from a different perspective, this is a great one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-community-experience&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.smartpassiveincome.com/blog/introducing-the-community-experience-podcast/&quot;&gt;The Community Experience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This podcast follows the traditional path of a host interviewing an industry expert. The thing I like most about this podcast is the guests are from a variety of different industries. This diversity of industry brings new ideas, different perspectives, and allows me to learn about community experiences I may never consider as someone from outside of those communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my Community 101 reading and listening list. Each of these provides the basics of community building and then goes in depth to help community builders discover more about the community experience. I have another list of resources that isn’t a “traditional” take on community that I might write about in the future, but it’ll take a more thorough explanation of why I think it should be on your community builder reading list.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Reading-List-The-Community-Builder-Edition</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Reading-List-The-Community-Builder-Edition</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>This Week in DevRel: Life Moves Fast</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, my “This Week in DevRel” series has turned into this “couple of months” in DevRel. In the words of Ferris Bueller, “Life moves pretty fast. If you don’t stop and look around once in a while, you could miss it.” And I feel like a lot of the last two months, I’ve been moving fast and not taking the time to look around. I’m working on it. This post is more of a highlight reel; I plan on writing a reflection on how I plan on building time into looking around more than once in a while later in the month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;highlights&quot;&gt;Highlights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;conferences&quot;&gt;Conferences&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was lucky enough to have the opportunity to give my talk &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zoo0B7GFvo8&quot;&gt;Does your Org Need a Community&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.magnoliajs.com/&quot;&gt;MagnoliaJS&lt;/a&gt; this year and to attend &lt;a href=&quot;https://momentumdevcon.com/&quot;&gt;Momentum Conf&lt;/a&gt;.
I did a lot of learning at these conferences. Some of it was when I was listening to talks, including one on community and one on burnout. Some of it was talking to other people in the field. I gravitate towards people who are doing some type of community building, whether or not that’s in their job description. Having this conversations helps me to get a pulse on the wider tech community, bounce ideas off of community professionals, and explore new ideas and initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hacktoberfest&quot;&gt;Hacktoberfest&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s my favorite time of the year! This year I participated as a mentor, contributor, and maintainer. I got to work on my postpartum wellness app with others and launch a new Deepgram project as a maintainer that I really enjoyed working on. It’s a chrome extension that allows the user to get transcripts in a browser tab, and we’re working on functionality to have translation available as well. I plan on keeping this going as long as the ideas are flowing and folks find it helpful. If you want to check it out, here’s the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/deepgram-devs/dg-translation-chrome-ext&quot;&gt;GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. I also supported the &lt;a href=&quot;https://virtualcoffee.io/&quot;&gt;Virtual Coffee&lt;/a&gt; Hacktoberfest Initiative. If you want to read more about that, check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.to/virtualcoffee/virtual-coffee-hacktoberfest-2022-roundup-1c2k&quot;&gt;Dan Ott’s post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;livestreams&quot;&gt;Livestreams&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did THREE in October! I did some TypeScript on Virtual Coffee’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twitch.tv/virtualcoffeeio&quot;&gt;TypeScript Tuesday Twitch Stream&lt;/a&gt;. I was also a guest on Mia Moore’s stream where we talked about all things open source, and I also did a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PMQb5qN5ob8&quot;&gt;Project Showcase stream with Appwrite&lt;/a&gt;, where we walked through Deepgram open source projects and talked about some of the ways we try to make our repos contributor friendly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;blogging&quot;&gt;Blogging&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I haven’t been able to have the cadence I want with blogging, but I did get a couple of posts in, including this one on [Open Source Projects for Hacktoberfest]
(https://dev.to/deepgram/open-source-projects-for-hacktoberfest-2022-4cia), yesterday’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/rkob8LcmsO&quot;&gt;post on imposter syndrome&lt;/a&gt;  and a new one on 5 Reasons to Contribute to Open Source Projects that will be up soon. The good news is, our monthly challenge for Virtual Coffee is &lt;a href=&quot;https://virtualcoffee.io/monthlychallenges/nov-2022&quot;&gt;Let’s Write 100k words together!&lt;/a&gt;, so you’ll be reading a lot more from me this month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hackathon&quot;&gt;Hackathon&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ran a hackathon internally with the Learn Build Teach Community. We provided support, ran a couple of workshops, and are in the judging stages. This is the first time we ran an internal community hackathon, so this was a real learning experience. As part of the post-hackathon experience, we’re doing evaluation of what worked and what didn’t, and what our strategy will be going forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;twitter-spaces&quot;&gt;Twitter Spaces&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m back on the Twitter Space game! I’m running them through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/DeepgramAI&quot;&gt;@DeepgramAI&lt;/a&gt; Twitter account. I’ve been doing them most Wednesdays at 1pm ET. So if you’re not following us, you might want to. Another option is to check out our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/orgs/deepgram/discussions/categories/events&quot;&gt;Events discussion&lt;/a&gt; in our Community Forum where I’m posting our spaces at least a week in advance. If you have questions or comments before the space, feel free to drop them in there and we’ll talk about it on the space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this is a pretty good overview of the things that I work on as a technical community builder. Oh, and one last achievement I want to share. I received one of the Twilio spotlight awards. If you want to know more about it and me, you can check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/sc/meet-the-inspirational-leaders-creating-a-better-future-for-developers?utm_campaign=devsearchlight2022_reveal&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter&amp;amp;utm_medium=twiliodevs&quot;&gt;the Business Insider article&lt;/a&gt; Being a Technical Community Builder requires a lot of pivoting, versatility, and getting outside of my comfort zone. But if I wasn’t spending time getting out of my comfort zone, then it wouldn’t be that fun, would it?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/This-Week-in-DevRel-Life-Moves-Fast</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/This-Week-in-DevRel-Life-Moves-Fast</guid>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

