<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bekah HW blog</title>
    <description>A blog about my journey into tech</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>2020: A Year in Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It was the best of times, it was the worst of times, it was the age of wisdom, it was the age of foolishness, it was the epoch of belief, it was the epoch of incredulity, it was the season of light, it was the season of darkness, it was the spring of hope, it was the winter of despair.&lt;/em&gt; - Charles Dickens&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mean, how could you expect me to start this post with anything else? 2020 was an entire lifetime, it was emotions that no one has ever felt before. It was &lt;em&gt;a&lt;/em&gt; thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t have huge goals coming into 2020, but I was ready for it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;2019 was my warmup year.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Bekah Hawrot Weigel (@BekahHW) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BekahHW/status/1211954474706714625?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;December 31, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Well, you know, I thought I was ready for it. And I did make some small, but very meaningful goals:
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Make a site for my memoir with Gatsby, keep learning what I need at my job.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Bekah Hawrot Weigel (@BekahHW) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BekahHW/status/1212511229123670018?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 1, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Did I meet those goals? Actually, kind of and more. I did build a &lt;a href=&quot;https://beautyinthescar.com/&quot;&gt;site&lt;/a&gt; for my memoir, and I did learn new things for my job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I wasn’t ready for 2020. And it took me a long time to get over that. I had this idea in my head that since &lt;a href=&quot;https://beautyinthescar.com/the-first-one/&quot;&gt;I had gone through trauma&lt;/a&gt;, I could navigate other traumas that came my way, that I could leverage that experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then I found myself crying every single night after I lost my job because of COVID, after my children’s school closed and I was supervising four kids doing at home learning while I was trying to interview for jobs. When I learned that &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.to/bekahhw/job-searching-in-the-time-of-covid-19-1jei&quot;&gt;tech interviews can be soul-crushing&lt;/a&gt;. And all I could think about was: why can’t I do &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; trauma?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This trauma, this global trauma of a pandemic wasn’t just about me. It wasn’t a hurdle that I could navigate. It was my trauma, my kids trauma, my family’s trauma, and it was the trauma of every single person affected by the pandemic. You don’t navigate the trauma of the world by yourself. And that’s very much what made this year the year I found people I call my friends, the year that I felt like I belonged, the year that Virtual Coffee became a huge part of my story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I lost my job, I felt alone, empty. I knew that feeling. And I knew that I had to do something before it turned into despair. And so &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.to/bekahhw/what-is-virtual-coffee-4omm&quot;&gt;Virtual Coffee&lt;/a&gt; was born. The highlight from that post is this line about what the point of Virtual Coffee is: &lt;em&gt;The point is to form community. To meet new devs. To learn from each other. To offer advice. The point is to not feel alone.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s what it did. I felt better about making my way through the job search because there were friends there to support me. I felt better about taking a contract using React Native for the first time, because there were people cheering me on. I felt understood when I was diagnosed with &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.to/bekahhw/adhd-the-quarantine-and-me-4apa&quot;&gt;ADHD&lt;/a&gt;. I felt joy when my job opened back up and I had the mentorship to grow as a frontend developer, to learn new things, to have confidence in myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so 2020 became the year where I had the support to do things that I didn’t dream of. 2020 became the year where I founded a community of developers, the year that I mentored when I didn’t think I knew enough to mentor, when I could finally call myself a developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the year that I became an open-source maintainer for my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BekahHW/postpartum-wellness-app&quot;&gt;post-partum wellness app&lt;/a&gt; because my friends encouraged me to have faith in myself. It was the year that I organized three online events for our community, where I gave my first technical talk on end-to-end testing with Cypress the same week that I MCed my first lightning talk event. It’s the year I recorded my first podcasts as a co-host and not as a guest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the year where I was inspired by people around me. Where I learned that it’s ok to lean on other people when you need it. When sometimes the people I least expected to accept me–all of me–to encourage me, to push me, to support me, did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the year that I learned that sometimes progress is not what you think it looks like. That sometimes hard conversations are the ones that you need to have. That therapy is good. That sometimes all you need to do is ask for help or advice or guidance. That growth is painful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the year that I cried and cried and cried. It was &lt;em&gt;hard&lt;/em&gt;. It &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; hard. And complicated. And some days the anxiety keeps me up at night. And some weeks I can’t stop thinking about how awful some of the moments have been. But those beautiful moments, they’ve been so much more intensely beautiful because of the contrast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a lot of ways, my year of coding, my year of life, can best be described by this paragraph from my first post in my &lt;a href=&quot;https://beautyinthescar.com/the-first-one/&quot;&gt;trauma blog&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And so this is my project. This is the space for vulnerability. This is the place for rawness and being allowed to be. This is the place where I show my scars. Where my body is mine. Where the scar that horrified and disgusted me has become a mark of pride. A reminder that I have survived. That I am a better person everyday for the ways I’ve changed. This is about the journey through trauma, the dirty and dark parts, the parts that I’m proud of, the parts where I say this was the worst experience of my life, but would never in a million years take it back. This is about finding beauty in the scar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/12/28/2020-A-Year-in-Review</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/12/28/2020-A-Year-in-Review</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I Came into Tech via Trauma</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I don’t have a traditional path into tech. I came into tech because my organs ruptured when I had my fourth kid. I came into tech because I had PTSD. I came into tech because I have &lt;a href=&quot;https://bekahhw.github.io/blog/2020/08/03/ADHD,-the-Quarantine,-and-Me&quot;&gt;ADHD&lt;/a&gt;. I came into tech because after I had surgery to remove one organ and restructure another, I overdosed on morphine and then spent the next six days teaching from a hospital bed because I didn’t have any rights as an adjunct instructor. I came into tech because I just wanted it to stop. I wanted my brain to stop. When I coded, it stopped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My journey into tech isn’t typical. And depending on how honest I am, my story is shocking. I didn’t mean to make a career change. I just wanted to have something, to feel like I could succeed at anything at all. I came into tech because the last six years of being an adjunct instructor I fought to have rights, to get a pay increase, to create a community. And I left with nothing. I came into tech because I found support, a community that I was seeking for years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four days after having my fourth kid, I went into my OBGYNs office. It haunts me. I told her about the horrific symptoms I was experiencing, and she told me “it’s not my problem.” I’ve told this story a thousand times, and it still hurts to say it. And it hurts because she said it to me, but it hurts because I’m not the only one who has felt abandoned in the room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not the only one who has felt like there was no hope. I’m not the only one who’s felt like no one could ever understand. I’m not the only one who has been left alone in the corner to watch every other person go on living their life while I died a little bit more inside everyday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s everybody’s problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is not a moment in time that I don’t carry that with me. I carry it with me because I very much do not ever want any other person to feel that way. I carry it with me, because it drives a force inside of me to do what I can to change the systems that make people feel like they are nothing, like they are not worthy, like no one should help them. When I left that room that day, I thought that I was not worth anyone’s time. I wasn’t a person; I was a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have always been a passionate person. I have always been intense. It has both been a characteristic that drives me and one that has isolated me from people. Sometimes I’m too much for people. I am more than they can handle. But I can’t help being fully myself. I can’t help that I can’t stop myself when I see new paths for change or growth or whatever that are driven by this intense desire to make sure that no one feels alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started a &lt;a href=&quot;https://beautyinthescar.com/&quot;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; to talk about my trauma and this is a crossover post. I learned to code because it stopped the trauma from repeating over and over in my head while I sat in front of the computer. I kept coding because I had community. I got excited about coding because I realized that code could’ve prevented what happened to me. But that’s women’s health, and not enough people care about women’s health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If no one will do the thing that needs to be done, I will. But I also know that when we work in isolation, we will never be as effective as we can be with a community. Because with a community there is support. With a community there is meaning and purpose and growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of years ago I was at JSConf Hawaii, and I told a woman that although my trauma was the worst thing that ever happened to me, I wouldn’t take it back. I’m a better person. Without that trauma, I don’t know the importance of community. WIthout that trauma, I don’t get into tech. Without trauma &lt;a href=&quot;https://virtualcoffee.io/&quot;&gt;Virtual Coffee&lt;/a&gt; is never started. Without trauma I don’t understand the importance of vulnerability, of meeting people where they are at, of letting people &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; me; I guard and protect myself. I don’t become the developer that I can be. I don’t find a way to push through those times when people tell me that I can’t do both; that I can’t create community and be a developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is very much about how I became a developer, but it’s very much more about how I became &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt;. And that’s the important part. Because I am a person first. And being human, recognizing the diverse experiences and challenges and talents and perspectives of the people around us matters.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/12/07/I-Came-into-Tech-via-Trauma</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/12/07/I-Came-into-Tech-via-Trauma</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We need to talk: More on the problems juniors are facing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I spend a lot of time talking about the challenges junior developers face when they are trying to break into tech. And honestly, there’s probably a whole book to write about this, a whole chapter on how most education (university, bootcamp, and online paths) doesn’t prepare new devs in the ways that they need to, how junior devs cost companies money, about how some companies let others mentor junior devs just so they can poach them with huge salary increases, about how creating a system of training and transition from support roles to developer roles could be a better way to approach the issue, about how talking more openly about it and about how trying to think about how to flip the hiring process on its head is a good place to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to write about any of that. I’m just going to point out some of the problems juniors are facing and suggest where we might want to start rethinking this process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;clear-exploitation&quot;&gt;Clear Exploitation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Having junior devs write code that goes into your code base without paying them and without making that clear during an interview.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;An interview is not an excuse for free work.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Asking junior devs to do work on your projects with no intention of hiring.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Interviewing a ton of juniors just to figure out who you can get for the least amount of money. (Tangent: when I lost my job during COVID, I interviewed for a position. I did the best on the take home test and was offered the position. But the catch was that the founder offered me $30/hr and told me that she was hoping to get me for less of an hourly wage since I was more junior and then I could work more hours.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Posting a job and interviewing without a real commitment to hiring.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Crushing a candidate’s soul in an interview–some of it is toxic culture, and some of it is trying to check their resilience—that is not what that does—to make the candidate feel grateful for being offered a job.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;other-problems-to-consider&quot;&gt;Other problems to consider&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Portfolios don’t always capture what you’re looking for or are mixed with other people’s work or are the same projects over and over and over (to-do list anyone?). New tangent: I think that being able to communicate code, ask questions, and talk about process and approach can be a better way of judging a candidate. So even opening up one of their projects from GitHub or portfolio and asking them to walk through it and talk about the process, and ask what they would do differently, where they were challenged, etc. could be as useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Giving a coding challenge doesn’t ensure you’re receiving a candidate’s work. I’ve heard hiring managers say that they’ve hired ppl who have done well on take-home tests, but couldn’t keep up with the job or couldn’t explain concepts at work that they applied in the take-home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of this whole problem is that being a junior looking for a job is a rat race. And everyone knows it.
We are exploiting desperation by over-requiring and having unreasonable expectations in interviews.
With a ton of juniors trying to break into tech, a ton of companies without an honest interest in hiring, and then juniors githubs stacked with multiple 4-hour take-home tests, spending 40 hours a week trying to find a job, and frequently for months, there’s a boat-load of problems. And it’s a catch 22 because juniors need more experience. How are they supposed to do that when they’re spending 40hrs a week trying to find a job?
These circumstances do not mimic the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t have a solution here. I just see the problem and the frustration and know that tech is losing good people because most of it isn’t even trying to figure it out. In a sense, this model is survival of the fittest, and I’m not okay with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I want is maybe idealistic. I want to see people and not candidates. I want a clear recognition that each of these people have lives and responsibilities. I want to see the value put on communication. I want to see people and organizations who have the ability to mentor and support to do it. I was lucky to get my first job as a developer. I didn’t have a take-home test or a whiteboard interview. I had a conversation. And that won’t work in every scenario, but I’ll tell you what, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;seeing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; the person in the interview is a good place to start.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/11/30/We-need-to-talk-More-on-the-problems-juniors-are-facing</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/11/30/We-need-to-talk-More-on-the-problems-juniors-are-facing</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I am a Woman in Tech</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;i-am-a-woman-in-tech&quot;&gt;I am a Woman in Tech.*&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That means that I am technical.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that I am a community builder.
That means that I can give a technical talk in the same week that I mentor and MC an event.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that I don’t want to be put in the project management track.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that there are unexplored tech fields out there, and I’m going to explore them.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that I will get stuck sometimes and ask for help.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that I will be willing to share my experiences.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that I will tell other women about who to avoid in tech.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that I will know the answer or how to find it.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that I am devoted to growing and learning and figuring it out.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that what I value most is good people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;i-am-a-mom-in-tech&quot;&gt;I am a mom in tech.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That means that I will not apologize when I put my kids first.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that sometimes my kids will come into my camera range and wave or scream or cry or kick each other.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that when I have time to code, I will put all the more drive into it.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that tech will never be the most important thing in my life.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that I recognize the importance of community, dependability, and flexibility.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that I do not have time to waste.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that I will not work with people who have a problem with that or who passive-aggressively comment on the number of children I have.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that I have specific opinions, viewpoints, and perspectives on things that most other people in tech do not have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;i-am-a-community-creator-in-tech&quot;&gt;I am a community creator in tech.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That means that I have a community that I am fiercely in support of.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that I see every person as a human being before I ever look at them as a dev.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that I allow myself to be vulnerable because I know how important that is.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that I value community over competition, caring over pushing people to the very limits of their emotional wellbeing.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that I value growth and mentorship and teaching at all levels.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that I meet people where they are.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that I value exploration.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that people are what matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;i-am-an-adhd-person-in-tech&quot;&gt;I am an ADHD person in tech.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That means that I communicate differently than a lot of people I know.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that sometimes when I’m really excited about an idea, I talk loud and fast and for a long time without realizing it.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that sometimes I hyper-focus and it takes a longgggg time to break out of it.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that other times, I can’t focus at all.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that sometimes I feel things very intensely and find it hard to communicate.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that sometimes I over-communicate.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that I value my systems.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that sometimes when other people are going to sleep I just can’t stop myself.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that I deeply value the people who have agreed to come on this journey with me. &lt;br /&gt;
That means that I’m running a marathon, but sprinting the whole time–and I love it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a person in tech.&lt;br /&gt;
I am dynamic and complex.&lt;br /&gt;
I reserve the right to change at any time.&lt;br /&gt;
I will not be labeled as one thing.&lt;br /&gt;
I can do all of the things that I want, and if you tell me I can’t I’ll take that as a challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was 18, an adult woman told me, “Bekah, you can’t change the world.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;*This is not met to represent anyone else; it’s solely based on my feelings and experiences.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/11/27/I-am-a-Woman-in-Tech</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/11/27/I-am-a-Woman-in-Tech</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Let Them Write Tests: An Argument for Cypress</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When I was learning to code, testing was covered a little bit, but I didn’t grasp the full awesomeness of what we test and why we test it. But I have been lucky enough–yes, I said lucky–to learn more about testing and dive into Testing Library and Cypress, but I’m just going to talk about Cypress here. Not only did I learn how to test, and strategies behind testing, but I also learned a lot about the codebase I was working in, how the components work together, how the user interacts with the program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is a big win. These are things that new devs struggle with. Yes, I may have had a couple of nightmares about the tests I was writing. Yes, I may have been stuck in testing hell for a while. But learning these things helped me to gain confidence as a developer. Letting new devs write tests benefits everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And Cypress is a pretty good place to start for your frontend needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you’re still not convinced that you should be writing E2E tests, let &lt;a href=&quot;https://kentcdodds.com/blog/confidently-shipping-code&quot;&gt;Kent C. Dodds&lt;/a&gt; convince you: “I write tests because they allow me to accomplish more than I could otherwise. I now have thousands of Kents in the form of automated tests telling me whether changes are breaking use cases.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-cypress&quot;&gt;What is Cypress&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cypress is An open source, JavaScript end-to-end (E2E) testing framework that bundles tools and libraries to get your tests up and running quickly. And one of the cool things about it is that it runs in the browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-is-cypress-good-for-beginners&quot;&gt;Why is Cypress good for beginners?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;its-readable&quot;&gt;It’s readable.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;context(&quot;Login&quot;, () =&amp;gt; {
  beforeEach(() =&amp;gt; {
    cy.visit(&quot;localhost:8080/login&quot;);
  });
  it(&quot;finds and types email&quot;, () =&amp;gt; {
    cy.get(&quot;#email&quot;)
      .type(&quot;leslieKnope@pawnee.gov&quot;)
      .should(&quot;have.value&quot;, &quot;leslieKnope@pawnee.gov&quot;);
  })
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just looking at the test above, you get an idea of what’s happening. Before each test is run in this section, the testrunner visits the url that’s specified. The “it” block tells what to expect and checks for the outcome. Also takes a callback (“verb”) and checks the assertion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you keep reading, you see that it’s finding the input, typing, and checking that the value is there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(And if you’re familiar with Testing Library, you can also add Cypress Testing library to leverage those commands as well–highly recommend.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-testrunner-rocks&quot;&gt;The testrunner rocks.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you run cypress open, the testrunner opens in the browser. The testrunner allows you to see exactly where each part of the test is happening and where it fails. You can see each step in the browser. So if we’re looking at the example above, you would see the email address being typed in the input. When you test a button click, you see that as the test runs. You see what you wrote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And along with that, when your test fails, you see exactly where it fails and there are usually really great error messages that go along with the failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the ease of setup–getting it up and running only takes a couple of minutes–the readability of tests, and the testrunner giving a really clear picture of what the tests are doing and how you’re interacting with your software, using Cypress to test your frontend shouldn’t be a hard decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you’re new to the devlife and you’re wondering what to learn next or to add to your project, this is a great place to start.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/11/21/Let-Them-Write-Tests-An-Argument-for-Cypress</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/11/21/Let-Them-Write-Tests-An-Argument-for-Cypress</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I'll say it again: Kindness Matters</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The world can be a really messy and hard and sad place sometimes. And we’re all carrying our own stories. Some of us wear them on our sleeves. Some of us let them slip out from time to time. Some of us keep them very well hidden. Some of us do them all. But at the end of the day, it doesn’t matter if we’re a frontend dev–or if you know how to spell it–a backend dev, a data scientist, or learning to dev. We’re all human. And kindness matters. I said it &lt;a href=&quot;https://bekahhw.github.io/blog/2018/04/14/If-one-of-your-goals-isn-t-to-help-someone,-you-re-doing-it-wrong&quot;&gt;before&lt;/a&gt;, and I’ll say it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here’s the thing, yes, you should be a decent human being, but also, being a kind and empathetic human being allows so much more room for growth for those around you. I feel kind of gross even saying that thing; productivity shouldn’t be your motivation to be a kind person, but, hey, if that’s what gets you there, fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve talked about going through trauma, and if you want to hear more of that story, you can check out my &lt;a href=&quot;http://beautyinthescar.com/&quot;&gt;trauma-blog&lt;/a&gt; that I just started, but two of the most important things I took from that experience are 1. community matters and 2. the person-centered approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, person-centered care–a term I’m stealing from the medical community–is when a person puts your experiences, wellbeing, needs and feelings at the centre of the caring and support process, and means we seek to understand and have empathy for your daily experience. If we remember that each of the people in our communities aren’t just workers and they’re dynamic human beings with multiple responsibilities who both succeed and fail everyday, we’ll do a better job of avoiding becoming a gatekeeper and creating stronger communities. The person-centered approach is driven by empathy and the mindset that each person on your team has something valuable to contribute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;be-a-gandolf&quot;&gt;Be a Gandolf&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we use this person-centered approach, a couple of things should happen: empathy is increased and we move away from a Me/Them model towards a We/Us model. What exactly does that mean? It means that we work together as a team to accomplish a goal, rather than making someone feel excluded from the team. This is not to say that there’s no leadership. If anything, the leader should establish this mentality and make it easier for the other teammates to follow suit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;let-the-hobbits-speak&quot;&gt;Let the Hobbits speak&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allowing everyone to become active participants in establishing the type of community that helps everyone to thrive, helps to create the “we” instead of “them.”
If you’re doing these things–inclusivity, positivity, we-mentality, person-centered approach–it should create an environment where everyone learns from each other. I think this is one of the most important parts of creating positive community and decreasing gatekeepers. By keeping our minds open to learning from anyone in an organization no matter the status or role, we allow ourselves to be versatile and open to growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;but-how-does-that-contribute-to-productivity&quot;&gt;But &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; does that contribute to productivity?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A growth mindset is one where the individual believes hard work, openness to input from others, and learning can develop talents as opposed to a fixed mindset where a person is more likely to believe they are born with talents. According to Harvard business review, “[employees from companies with a growth-mindset] report feeling far more empowered and committed; they also receive far greater organizational support for collaboration and innovation. In contrast, people at primarily fixed-mindset companies report more of only one thing: cheating and deception among employees, presumably to gain an advantage in the talent race.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;employees-in-a-growth-mindset-company-are&quot;&gt;Employees in a “growth mindset” company are:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;47% likelier to say that their colleagues are trustworthy,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;34% likelier to feel a strong sense of ownership and commitment to the company,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;65% likelier to say that the company supports risk taking, and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;49% likelier to say that the company fosters innovation -&lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/archive-toc/BR1411&quot;&gt;Harvard Business Review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hearing the horror stories of other early devs makes my heart hurt. It’s not that hard to be a kind human being. This has been a &lt;em&gt;really, really&lt;/em&gt; hard week for me. My PTSD from an event four years ago was triggered and it took me a while to figure out what the heck was happening with my brain, why I couldn’t sleep, why that anxiety was crushing my chest. But do you know what makes it feel manageable? Having kind and caring people around me. The people who care first about &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt; as a person and not what I got done this week. And a side-effect of that, &lt;em&gt;yes&lt;/em&gt; is that I got stuff done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote a presentation and tests and refactored code and wrote blog posts and organized events and mentored people. None of that happens if I don’t know that I have support. If no one asks me how I’m doing, and &lt;em&gt;means&lt;/em&gt; it. But also, it’s okay if I did none of that. Be kind to your employees, be kind to your co-workers, and be the best listener you can be. Because you don’t know what anyone else has been through, and acknowledging everyone’s experiences and supporting each other is more important than that code you’re writing anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/11/08/I'll-say-it-again-Kindess-Matters</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/11/08/I'll-say-it-again-Kindess-Matters</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hacktoberfest 2020: The Best One Yet</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year, I didn’t complete Hacktoberfest. And I felt pretty bad about that.I spent hours looking through issues, hoping to find one that was tagged as a “good first issue” that was actually a good first issue and not a 20-hour project. It didn’t happen. And honestly, it made me sad. I wanted to try to get into open source, but it didn’t feel very open. Fast forward to this year. I started a little thing called Virtual Coffee in April, and by September I had a co-founder to help me support the community, and we decided to create a team to do our first major event with Hacktoberfest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A lot of work&lt;/em&gt; was put into planning and executing this event. But, wow, was it worth it. This year I was a contributor, maintainer, and mentor. Never would I have imagined that I would go from last years’ disappointment to fulfilling all these roles and learning so much along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But here’s the thing: Last year I failed because I didn’t have community, because I didn’t feel supported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;as-a-maintainer&quot;&gt;As A Maintainer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn’t prepared for this at all. My React Native project was a ball of tangled yarn to start with. I had started the project when I had no business starting it–which, by the way, I totally recommend–and then abandoned it for a while (or a year). With the encouragement of some amazing &lt;a href=&quot;https://virtualcoffee.io/&quot;&gt;VirtualCoffee&lt;/a&gt; members, I decided to see what I could do. And what I learned is that I can do far more with a community of people who care about the project who have had no experience in React Native than I ever could do by myself. I also learned that experienced developers were there to support me, encourage me, and spend time talking me through everything from MVPs to dev experience to issues I had setting up my first open-source coding project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also learned, it’s damn hard and time consuming to write good issues, but that makes the difference in building community. One of my favorite moments of the entire month is when a contributor tweeted that my project had the best documentation that she’d read. And that documentation doesn’t happen without my Hacktoberfest team. With them, especially &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tkshillinz&quot;&gt;Kirk&lt;/a&gt; I learned how to create better documentation and issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;as-a-mentor&quot;&gt;As A Mentor&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In no universe did I ever feel ready to be a mentor. I’ve got about a year and a quarter under my belt and it seemed very unreasonable to mentor anyone at any stage.The thought of it sent imposter electricity up and down my spine. And here’s where community comes in again. Talking through my self-doubt can be really hard. But I’m lucky that I’ve been able to be vulnerable with the people in my community. When I told &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/danieltott&quot;&gt;Dan&lt;/a&gt; about my insecurities, he had a lot of great advice. It’s a learning experience. And if you’re honest about where you are and you let them know that some of this will be learning together, everyone grows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a lot of looking things up together. There were/are some unanswered questions. But honesty and vulnerability are kind of the thing I’m always working towards. I’m a work-in-progress and that won’t ever stop. But that’s what coding’s about. And if I can show that to someone else, someone with less experience than me, and if they can find some self-acceptance there, then that’s my biggest win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;as-a-contributor&quot;&gt;As A Contributor&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are no fireworks wins here. My last PR was a one word update to a ReadMe. But I wrote some Elm code for the first time ever with the help of a great maintainer, and I learned about how important it is to value contributors, to allow them to be part of the community. I know that I’m more likely to want to contribute to the people who are on my team, who I know I can talk to and ask questions and it’s the people who never make me feel like I am bothering them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open source is an amazing place to be. And there’s so much talk about how it’s a great place for new coders to get experience. Except everyone forgets to mention that a lot of, and maybe even most, OSS projects are not friendly to new coders. Friendly is creating documentation that everyone can understand. Friendly is creating an environment where everyone knows they can ask any question they have. Friendly is inviting opportunities to develop that community from the ground up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t matter if you hit those four PRs and earned a t-shirt. What matters is you were open to trying. There are some projects that make it a better experience than others. Open-source projects don’t end with Hacktoberfest. I think the best thing that I learned this year was that with the right community–for me, that’s not necessarily the most technical, it’s the one with the heart and passion to keep learning and moving forward–it’s a movement to build things for everyone. And that’s the energy I want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Hacktoberfest was a beautiful experience, and I am so very thankful for the Virtual Coffee team that made it possible. I’m thankful for all their volunteer hours and their desire to help everyone in our community to grow. I am thankful for the maintainers who paired and offered their projects to our community. I am thankful for the mentors who spent time with our community members helping them to grow. I am thankful for the mentorship I had to be able to be a maintainer, contributor, and mentor. Community matters, folks. And I am a part of the best one 💖&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/11/02/Hacktoberfest-2020-The-best-one-yet</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/11/02/Hacktoberfest-2020-The-best-one-yet</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New Devs: Make Pairing a Priority</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the questions I’ve been asked most frequently is also one that I asked most frequently when I first started: “when will I start to feel comfortable, like I’m good enough to be a developer?” One of the most common answers was between eight and twelve months into your first job. And although I think this is accurate, it doesn’t quite get at what I think should be the question: What will help me to be more comfortable as a developer? And while I have a handful of ideas, I think one of the most important things is pairing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I taught college English I frequently had complaints about my attendance policy. Why did they have to be there? Because when you’re talking about literature, you aren’t memorizing facts, you’re learning how to talk and grow and to think critically. And the best way to do this is to both discuss your observations and analyses with other people and to listen to other people’s perspectives and approaches. And I think the same thing happens when you’re coding, and it’s one of the things that many bootcamp grads and self-taught devs don’t get the opportunity to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At its core, coding is writing and style and communication. You’re communicating with the program. You’re communicating with other developers, project managers, and users. If you can’t communicate your ideas, if you can’t write them in a way that’s logical, then things don’t work or you don’t understand why they work. I don’t think you need a complete, in-depth understanding, but you need to have a sense of why you used this approach for this problem and what this approach does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pairing not only forces you to communicate your ideas, but it also gives you the opportunity for feedback, questions, and discussion. One of the biggest challenges when you’re learning to code is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;you don’t know, what you don’t know, until you know it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pairing can be overwhelming when you first start. So here are a couple of tips:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Pair with someone who is one step ahead of you. Sometimes this can take the pressure off.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Take turns driving and navigating. Sometimes you’ll do the typing while someone else gives you the directions and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ask a more senior dev if you can watch them work through a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If someone offers to pair with you, take them up on it, no matter how nervous you are.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Don’t be afraid to ask for someone to pair with you on a project. It might be their open source project, your project, or something for work. If you have someone you are comfortable with, that’s great. But if you don’t, ask a slack group you’re a part of or even Twitter. In my experience, if someone offers, it’s because they want to help.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish I had spent more time pairing when I was learning. Learning to communicate clearly and getting comfortable asking questions was the most important part of feeling like I was a developer. The fastest way I can see to getting there is by pairing or working on a team. It also might look like the scariest, but with a supportive community there’s only progress.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/10/26/New-Devs-Make-Pairing-a-Priority</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/10/26/New-Devs-Make-Pairing-a-Priority</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Thing About Trauma Is...</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The thing about trauma is, it doesn’t stick to your timeline. The thing about trauma is, when you think you’re done with it, it creeps back in. The thing about trauma is, you find yourself in constant fight or flight and you second guess every single decision you make and whether or not you’re too much for the people in your life. You wonder if you’re overreacting. You wonder if the people you call your friends will stop being your friends because that’s all you can focus on. You wonder if you will always feel alone. The thing about trauma is, even when you have worked so fucking hard, it still creeps up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monday is my fourth trauma anniversary. It’s complicated. Monday is my youngest kids’ fourth birthday. We simultaneously celebrate her life while I remember the pain of my organs rupturing into each other. When I remember the doctors not believing me. When I remember being sent home with “Sometimes moms of four go through this.” When I remember crying next to my bed thinking that I could not live the rest of my life like this. Trauma is not forgiving. And I try my hardest every year to focus on how thankful I am for where I am in my life. I am thankful that trauma lead me to code. I am thankful for having the best people in my life. I am thankful for understanding myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But even though my brain accepts these things, my body doesn’t. I haven’t had a good night’s sleep in probably a week and a half and it’ll probably be another three or four weeks before I do. As soon as I leave a state of hyperfocus, I can feel the anxiety in every single part of my body. My body thinks it’s not safe. My body remembers, and it won’t let me move forward. If it doesn’t sleep, it won’t come close to dying. If it doesn’t sleep, nothing bad will happen. If it doesn’t sleep, it won’t…If it doesn’t sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried really hard this week. I tried to keep my schedule full. I went to therapy twice. I tried to pretend things were normal. I tried to help other people. I tried really hard this week, and I feel like I failed at every. single. turn. I felt alone in that hospital room. I was back there. No one believed me. No one helped me. And I couldn’t breath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week was a constant challenge to breath. I wanted to do my best for the people around me, but I couldn’t breath. The entire week was a battle with myself. A battle to prove to myself that I was more than my trauma. A battle to prove I that I was not that 31 year old in the doctor’s office who was not the doctor’s “problem.” It was a battle to prove that I had worth, that I was a solution, that I mattered enough to someone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it’s hard when your mind and your body are fighting you. It’s hard when you second guess what everyone says to you because this time of year triggers a general distrust. It’s hard that you don’t feel good enough, worth enough, to be around amazing people. It’s fucking hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it’s hard to talk about. I don’t know how long I’ll leave this post up, but probably not forever. It’s hard to tell people who don’t understand trauma how broken you feel. It’s hard to explain that you want to feel differently, but something you don’t know how to control won’t let you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did my best this week, but it feels like I fell short by a million miles. It feels like I didn’t do anything worth while. It feels hard and sad and like I’ve fallen down. Down. Down. And I don’t know how to get up or climb out or forge a new path. It physically hurts. It’s like part of my soul is continually being sucked out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know I’m not at fault. And I’ve been in treatment for a while. I’m four years past my trauma, and it’s still hard. Trauma doesn’t just stop. So if you’re heart hurts right now, I’m sorry. I’m sorry it hurts. My heart hurts right with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/10/02/The-Thing-About-Trauama-Is</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/10/02/The-Thing-About-Trauama-Is</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Building Community is just as Important as Building Products</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Move fast and break things. You hear that a lot in tech. And I’m here to call bullshit. Because you don’t build relationships fast and break them. You don’t create trust by breaking things. You don’t depend on things that break. You don’t step on the ice of a pond with a pair of ice skates to figure out if it’s strong enough to hold you. You figure it out before you trust it. You know if it’s solid. And &lt;em&gt;that’s&lt;/em&gt; what enables you to soar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What enables you to glide across the ice, what allows you to soar is the trust that comes from having that solid base. And it doesn’t matter how great the software is if you don’t have great people behind it, because if you don’t have great people the software will eventually fail. It’s possible to push through and make something great, but that doesn’t last without injury. When you push the people on the team so hard that they don’t have time to recover, that they never feel like they’ve won a minute in their career, you are responsible for the breakdown of the product, goals, and/or organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you have a community who can trust each other, when you have a community who supports each other, when you have a community who can be honest and transparent, &lt;em&gt;that’s&lt;/em&gt; when you have the potential to make amazing things. That’s when you have the potential to change this industry. Because you have the ability to soar because you can trust each other, because you know that if someone stops you, it’s for good reasons, because when they let you go, they’ll be there to support you even if the ice starts to feel a little thin. They’ll get you back to the shore and you’ll re-evaluate for next time. But you’ll be damn sure that no one lets you make the same mistake again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my all-time favorite quotes is from James Clear in &lt;em&gt;Atomic Habits&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Nothing sustains motivation better than belonging to the tribe. It transforms a personal quest into a shared one.
Previously, you were on your own. Your identity was singular. You are a reader. You are a musician. You are an athlete.
When you join a book club or a band or a cycling group, your identity becomes linked to those around you. Growth and change is no longer an individual pursuit. We are readers. We are musicians. We are cyclists.
The shared identity begins to reinforce your personal identity. This is why remaining part of a group after achieving a goal is crucial to maintaining your habits. It’s friendship and community that embed a new identity and help behaviors last over the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Driven by empathy and the mindset that each person on your team has something valuable to contribute, communities that have a growth-mindset, the ones that have each-others backs are the ones that change the industry. I’m not interested in being a part of something that doesn’t want to change the industry. I’m not interested in doing the things the way they’ve always been done. I’m interested in working with good people because I know that they are interested in changing the world. I know that they will inspire me, when I feel uninspired. And I’ll be there to inspire them some day too. Because, for me, there is no point in doing things if it’s not to change things for the better, if it’s not to make products or changes in the industry that will improve the lives of someone we know. I’m a firm believer that it doesn’t happen unless we can trust the people around us. And when both of those things align, something beautiful will happen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/09/22/Building-Community-is-just-as-Improtant-as-Building-Products</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/09/22/Building-Community-is-just-as-Improtant-as-Building-Products</guid>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
