<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bekah HW blog</title>
    <description>A blog about my journey into tech</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting Out of My Comfort Zone</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;like&lt;/em&gt; my comfort zone. A lot. It’s a familiar space. It’s a warm blanket, a cup of coffee, in front of a fire. It’s the crack of the bat against a baseball on a hot July day. It’s hearing that song from when I was eleven and still knowing all the words. I think comfort zones are good, but pushing ourselves out of them, pushing ourselves into unknown territories, those are the places we grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last twelve months have been a lot of growing, and I didn’t even have to push myself to do it. The world did it for me. But there are times when I felt like I had been comfortable for too long, and I needed to push myself to do those things that scared me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes that thing was asking for help instead of going deeper down the rabbit hole by myself. Sometimes it was accepting someone’s offer to help. Sometimes it was jumping into a new adventure without all the planning and discussions I would have done if I wanted to make sure the moment was just right. Taking my first dev job, almost two years ago, was pushing myself way out of my comfort zone. Sometimes it’s sharing these moments with others. Some of these things I talk about on this &lt;a href=&quot;https://virtualcoffee.io/podcast/0109-bekah-dan/&quot;&gt;Virtual Coffee podcast episode&lt;/a&gt;, which itself is one of the things that I did to force myself out of my comfort zone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently decided I was going to livestream talking through and working on my postpartum wellness app, which was absolutely terrifying. But I was inspired by Drew Clements talking about how he livestreams working on &lt;a href=&quot;https://protege.dev/&quot;&gt;Protege.dev&lt;/a&gt; as an accountability tool. It’s not enough that I’m still very much new to React Native. I wanted to add to that the accountability that comes with livestreaming.I’ve only done it a couple of times, but I learned that it’s not about having all of the answers; it’s about communicating when you don’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s ok to have questions. It’s ok to look things up. It’s ok to forget how to do something you’ve done 100x before. It happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s about not getting frustrated when you don’t have those things. It’s about learning how to move forward, how to grow. And it’s remembering that process the next time you have that feeling of not being good enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are so many times that I’m mad at myself for not knowing more or for feeling like I should be better at coding than I am. That I should have more done than I do. And that’s not productive; negative self talk does not help me grow. (I’m going to say it again, for the people who need to hear it; also, me. I need to hear it again.) Negative self talk does not help me grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting out of your comfort zone and growing is hard. And sometimes it means hearing things that are hard to hear. Sometimes, it’s having those hard conversations when you want to ignore the problem and hope it disappears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend said to me the other day, “Bekah, there’s a reason they’re called growing pains. It doesn’t feel good.” I think it’s about embracing that pain by getting out of your comfort zone, but not being &lt;em&gt;stuck&lt;/em&gt; in the place you were last time, last week, last tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t solve problems by ignoring them. You tackle the error in your console one piece at a time. And sometimes it’s minutes and sometimes it’s days, but damn it feels good when you finally have that project up on the screen. And that’s worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/03/13/Getting-Out-of-My-Comfort-Zone</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/03/13/Getting-Out-of-My-Comfort-Zone</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Complicated Anniversaries: It's Ok to Not Be Ok</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Life has been &lt;em&gt;weird&lt;/em&gt; lately. It’s been complicated, and I’ve had a hard time understanding why. And then I read this tweet:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;We're coming up on a year of being in this pandemic, there's some sort of weird existential dread hitting a lot of us.

The bad news: we're all in this at the same time, together. The good news: we're all in this at the same time, together.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Sarah Drasner (@sarah_edo) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sarah_edo/status/1360023399104274433&quot;&gt;February 11, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that was it. That was the moment where I thought “oh, I know how this goes.” I know about trauma anniversaries. I know what they do to me. I know how I struggle through thinking through things. I know how I’m anxious. I know how I’m irritable. I know how my mind races at night, how I wake up at 2am and can’t go back to sleep, I know how I feel like a wrecking ball of emotions because I’m freaking doing the best I can do and I feel like I’m letting every single person down because the world is fucking overwhelming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know this feeling  well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I have desperately tried to get away from it for the last four and a half years. And, “hello, trauma, we meet again. And you’re compounding yourself on top of what I’m already going through. And this time, fuck you, because you’re stacking yourself on top of my kids too. And I could barely hold on when it was &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; me. But now you’re trying to take them down too. And I will not stand for it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Last time, it was almost all of me. I couldn’t see my life past trauma, until one person, just one, reached out and said, I’ve been through this. It was different, but also the same. And I heard the words that I thought in my head. And I understood the self-dount, and I heard the voices of every single person who doubted me in my life and I said “Fuck you.” But this time, it’s not just me. It’s me, it’s my kids and my family, it’s my friends–who I love deeply–it’s the community that has held tight to each other. And it’s hard. I am trying so very hard to be the one who can hold everyone up. And I know that we all hold each other up, but it’s hard. It’s a trustfall, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here’s the thing: we fail at a trustfall if we’re not honest with ourselves. It’s ok to not be ok. It’s ok to say that. It’s a good thing to reach out for support. We’re all very much going through this together–and some of us are dealing with extra things on top of it–and if anything, we learn about the importance of honesty, of commmunication, of empathy. And we all come out the other end as a stronger community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for now, can we be ok struggling together? Can we be ok having off weeks together? Because this is all normal–a normal trauma response–and let’s acknowledge that for many of us, that’s what the entire last year has been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it’s ok for the last year to have some amazing and bright spots. It’s ok for the last year to feel empty. But now, more than ever, I want you to know that I am here for you. I am here if we have never spoken, I am here if we’ve had a million conversations but haven’t felt close, I am here for you wherever you are in your life if you feel this way. Because I will never leave anyone in isolation. I’m here. And it doesn’t matter what role you’ve had in my life. I am just here for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/02/12/Complicated-Anniversaries-It's-Ok-to-not-be-Ok</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/02/12/Complicated-Anniversaries-It's-Ok-to-not-be-Ok</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Five Hot Takes for the New Year</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I spend a lot of time stuck in my head, wondering if what I say is going to hurt someone or lead them on the wrong path, or flat-out be wrong. And that’s exhausting. I love going on podcasts, but the after-effect is that I rethink my every statement to see if it could possibly hurt someone. And there have been times that I’ve asked podcasts to cut something. But the truth is, we all live our own story. And sometimes we say things wrong, but we give the right advice. And sometimes our advice is meaningful for a bunch of people, but not one. And sometimes our stories impact one person and that’s it. But I’m here for that one person. Because if you have ever felt alone, like you are the only one who understands your experience, that &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; experience that you can relate to, can make the &lt;em&gt;biggest&lt;/em&gt; difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this post isn’t going to give all the details, because I have spent my detail energy for the week, but it will give you my hot takes, that I want to reserve energy for in upcoming posts, if you want it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let people know when they provide you with valuable information
I cannot tell you how many times I have considered stopping whatever I was doing, but then I got one message that affirmed what I did or said, and that was enough. Over at &lt;a href=&quot;http://virtualcoffee.io/&quot;&gt;Virtual Coffee&lt;/a&gt;, we’re planning our second round of Lightning Talks. Last round, I strong-armed my way through a lot of the event organizing alone. This time, I’m working to create processes and engage and empower members to create this event. In our meeting on Monday, I was honest with them: Last time I was so exhausted that I wanted to sleep for a month. And then I started seeing how much our members appreciated it, how proud our speakers were. And then I said, “how soon can we do this again.” And someone responded, “The post-conference high.” And that’s very much the feeling I get when one person tells me about how my sharing has impacted their lives. So if someone has written, spoken, tweeted, whatever, in a way that has motivated you, &lt;em&gt;tell them&lt;/em&gt;, because that will motivate them too.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’re never going to be ready, so start.
I have four kids, and I always laugh when people tell me they aren’t ready to have kids. I wasn’t ready for any of this. In fact, I never had dreams or goals of being married or being a mom. Fun fact, I was 21 when I got married, and 24 when I had my first kid. I’m not going to apologize for telling my story. I’m not telling &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; this is your story. But this is one of the times that I pushed past fear and made meaning in my life. And it was hard. A lot. But, I most certainly grew leaps and bounds. When I started my blog, I didn’t even know that dev tools were a thing. And if you go back far enough in my code, you can see that I didn’t know that.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have the hard conversations.
Hard conversations are…hard. But they are worth it. If you can come out the other end of very difficult conversations, if you can disagree with someone and find a meeting point, if you can approach them with empathy, honestly, and leave with clarity, then you can do so much. &lt;em&gt;And&lt;/em&gt; you’ll know the people you can do it with.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reach out to people in your network.
The worst thing you can get is a no or no response. I feel like I have had a masters class in entrepreneurship in the last couple of months because I have &lt;em&gt;asked&lt;/em&gt; founders, owners, consultants, to talk to me about my use-case. And nearly all of them have said yes and been amazing. Early-2020 Bekah wouldn’t have done that. And I can’t explain exactly what happened, except I allowed myself to think of myself as a capable person who was willing to stake a small embarrassment for the opportunity of learning from the people I value most in the tech community.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You are not defined by others, and along with that good communities will help you when you feel alone.
There have been a number of times where I’ve felt &lt;em&gt;used&lt;/em&gt; as a promotional story. I would help &lt;em&gt;them&lt;/em&gt; to elevate themselves because they helped &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt;, a mom of 4 kids, a career-changer, a trauma-survivor. And then when I reached out to them, when I asked for support, there was nothing. And it hurt. A lot. But here’s the thing: I am a mother of four. I am a career-changer. I am a trauma-survivor. And I have a community of people who love and support me. And if you are reading this and you feel like you have no one, I can 100% guarantee that &lt;a href=&quot;https://virtualcoffee.io/&quot;&gt;Virtual Coffee&lt;/a&gt; has a place for you. We are here to meet every person where they are. To support, and to guide, to mentor and provide for. And I know my community, and I know that they will be your people if you let us.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/01/28/Five-Hot-Takes-for-the-New-Year</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/01/28/Five-Hot-Takes-for-the-New-Year</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Let Them Write Tests: Writing Your First Cypress Test</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a continuation of &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.to/bekahhw/let-them-write-tests-an-argument-for-cypress-19o2&quot;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like writing tests. I like the structure. I like when they find bugs. I even like when they give me nightmares. But I think I like them most because they’re accessible and getting Cypress setup is quick and painless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve already made my case for why you should write tests. Now I’m going to take you through getting Cypress up and running and writing your first test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In your terminal:
Cd into your project path: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cd /your_project/path&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, I might have a project called coding-blog in my Project folder. So when I open my terminal, I put in: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cd Project/coding-blog&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Capitalization doesn’t matter here, but spelling and order do.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we’re ready to get it installed. (For more detailed instructions, &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.cypress.io/guides/getting-started/installing-cypress.html#npm-install&quot;&gt;the docs&lt;/a&gt; are the place to be.) For less detailed instructions: In your terminal put &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;npm install cypress&lt;/code&gt; (if you’re using npm). If you’re using yarn, type: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;yarn add cypress&lt;/code&gt;. It shouldn’t take that long to install, but while you’re waiting I recommend checking out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.cypress.io/guides/overview/why-cypress.html#In-a-nutshell&quot;&gt;Cypress docs&lt;/a&gt;, because I can guarantee you’ll be spending quality time there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once it’s all done installing, you’re ready to explore some folders. You’ll notice in your file directory that you now have a Cypress folder. In that folder, you’ll find fixtures, integration, plugins, and support. You’ll also notice that you have a cypress.json file in your file structure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s start there. You’ll see that you can customize this. For this go-round, we’re just going to use the localhost address for the baseUrl that you’ll be using to test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;{
  &quot;baseUrl&quot;: &quot;http://localhost:3000/”
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok. We’re getting closer. Now open your Cypress folder, and click on integration. This is where we’ll write our first tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we need to figure out how to write the tests. Let’s pretend we’re testing a new user form. The file we’re testing is called NewUser.js, so we’ll create our new file with the name newUser.js in the Cypress/integration folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two main pieces of a Cypress test. First, an example. Then the explanation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;describe('new user form', () =&amp;gt; {
  it('displays form validation', () =&amp;gt; {
    cy.visit('/users/new')
    cy.get('#first_name').type('Bekah')    
    cy.get('#first_name').should('have.value', 'Bekah', 'be.visible')
  })
})
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;explanation&quot;&gt;Explanation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The test is looking for an input with the id “first_name.” It finds the input, types in the name and then checks that the name is visible in the input. But what are these sections?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;describe&quot;&gt;Describe&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Has two arguments: a string (“subject”)–in this case “new user form” and the callback (“it”) that the runs the code&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;it&quot;&gt;It&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This block tells what to expect and checks for the outcome. Also takes a callback (“verb”)–in this case “displays the form”–and checks the assertion-&amp;gt; should have a value and be visible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each “it” block is a test. You can include multiple it blocks in a describe. For example, you might want to test validation on the form. If the user tries to submit without entering their name, an error appears on the screen. That should have it’s own “it” block.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you know what to test? Well, that’s another post. But you want to be sure that users can use your software. So start there.
To run the test, you can either open it in the testrunner, which runs in the browser and lets you actually see the action happening, or you can run it headlessly with the command &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cypress run&lt;/code&gt;.
To run the command in your terminal, you’ll either start with yarn or npm, depending on which your project uses and then the appropriate command. So in this case, I would run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;yarn cypress open&lt;/code&gt;. 
The test runner would open, and then I would select the file I want to test and watch the tests run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cool, right? And the nice thing about tests is if something isn’t working or if it breaks, you know right away.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/01/17/Let-Them-Write-Tests-Writing-Your-First-Cypress-Test</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/01/17/Let-Them-Write-Tests-Writing-Your-First-Cypress-Test</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2020: A Year in Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It was the best of times, it was the worst of times, it was the age of wisdom, it was the age of foolishness, it was the epoch of belief, it was the epoch of incredulity, it was the season of light, it was the season of darkness, it was the spring of hope, it was the winter of despair.&lt;/em&gt; - Charles Dickens&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mean, how could you expect me to start this post with anything else? 2020 was an entire lifetime, it was emotions that no one has ever felt before. It was &lt;em&gt;a&lt;/em&gt; thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t have huge goals coming into 2020, but I was ready for it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;2019 was my warmup year.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Bekah Hawrot Weigel (@BekahHW) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BekahHW/status/1211954474706714625?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;December 31, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Well, you know, I thought I was ready for it. And I did make some small, but very meaningful goals:
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Make a site for my memoir with Gatsby, keep learning what I need at my job.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Bekah Hawrot Weigel (@BekahHW) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BekahHW/status/1212511229123670018?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 1, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Did I meet those goals? Actually, kind of and more. I did build a &lt;a href=&quot;https://beautyinthescar.com/&quot;&gt;site&lt;/a&gt; for my memoir, and I did learn new things for my job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I wasn’t ready for 2020. And it took me a long time to get over that. I had this idea in my head that since &lt;a href=&quot;https://beautyinthescar.com/the-first-one/&quot;&gt;I had gone through trauma&lt;/a&gt;, I could navigate other traumas that came my way, that I could leverage that experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then I found myself crying every single night after I lost my job because of COVID, after my children’s school closed and I was supervising four kids doing at home learning while I was trying to interview for jobs. When I learned that &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.to/bekahhw/job-searching-in-the-time-of-covid-19-1jei&quot;&gt;tech interviews can be soul-crushing&lt;/a&gt;. And all I could think about was: why can’t I do &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; trauma?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This trauma, this global trauma of a pandemic wasn’t just about me. It wasn’t a hurdle that I could navigate. It was my trauma, my kids trauma, my family’s trauma, and it was the trauma of every single person affected by the pandemic. You don’t navigate the trauma of the world by yourself. And that’s very much what made this year the year I found people I call my friends, the year that I felt like I belonged, the year that Virtual Coffee became a huge part of my story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I lost my job, I felt alone, empty. I knew that feeling. And I knew that I had to do something before it turned into despair. And so &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.to/bekahhw/what-is-virtual-coffee-4omm&quot;&gt;Virtual Coffee&lt;/a&gt; was born. The highlight from that post is this line about what the point of Virtual Coffee is: &lt;em&gt;The point is to form community. To meet new devs. To learn from each other. To offer advice. The point is to not feel alone.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s what it did. I felt better about making my way through the job search because there were friends there to support me. I felt better about taking a contract using React Native for the first time, because there were people cheering me on. I felt understood when I was diagnosed with &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.to/bekahhw/adhd-the-quarantine-and-me-4apa&quot;&gt;ADHD&lt;/a&gt;. I felt joy when my job opened back up and I had the mentorship to grow as a frontend developer, to learn new things, to have confidence in myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so 2020 became the year where I had the support to do things that I didn’t dream of. 2020 became the year where I founded a community of developers, the year that I mentored when I didn’t think I knew enough to mentor, when I could finally call myself a developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the year that I became an open-source maintainer for my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BekahHW/postpartum-wellness-app&quot;&gt;post-partum wellness app&lt;/a&gt; because my friends encouraged me to have faith in myself. It was the year that I organized three online events for our community, where I gave my first technical talk on end-to-end testing with Cypress the same week that I MCed my first lightning talk event. It’s the year I recorded my first podcasts as a co-host and not as a guest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the year where I was inspired by people around me. Where I learned that it’s ok to lean on other people when you need it. When sometimes the people I least expected to accept me–all of me–to encourage me, to push me, to support me, did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the year that I learned that sometimes progress is not what you think it looks like. That sometimes hard conversations are the ones that you need to have. That therapy is good. That sometimes all you need to do is ask for help or advice or guidance. That growth is painful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the year that I cried and cried and cried. It was &lt;em&gt;hard&lt;/em&gt;. It &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; hard. And complicated. And some days the anxiety keeps me up at night. And some weeks I can’t stop thinking about how awful some of the moments have been. But those beautiful moments, they’ve been so much more intensely beautiful because of the contrast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a lot of ways, my year of coding, my year of life, can best be described by this paragraph from my first post in my &lt;a href=&quot;https://beautyinthescar.com/the-first-one/&quot;&gt;trauma blog&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And so this is my project. This is the space for vulnerability. This is the place for rawness and being allowed to be. This is the place where I show my scars. Where my body is mine. Where the scar that horrified and disgusted me has become a mark of pride. A reminder that I have survived. That I am a better person everyday for the ways I’ve changed. This is about the journey through trauma, the dirty and dark parts, the parts that I’m proud of, the parts where I say this was the worst experience of my life, but would never in a million years take it back. This is about finding beauty in the scar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/12/28/2020-A-Year-in-Review</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/12/28/2020-A-Year-in-Review</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I Came into Tech via Trauma</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I don’t have a traditional path into tech. I came into tech because my organs ruptured when I had my fourth kid. I came into tech because I had PTSD. I came into tech because I have &lt;a href=&quot;https://bekahhw.github.io/blog/2020/08/03/ADHD,-the-Quarantine,-and-Me&quot;&gt;ADHD&lt;/a&gt;. I came into tech because after I had surgery to remove one organ and restructure another, I overdosed on morphine and then spent the next six days teaching from a hospital bed because I didn’t have any rights as an adjunct instructor. I came into tech because I just wanted it to stop. I wanted my brain to stop. When I coded, it stopped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My journey into tech isn’t typical. And depending on how honest I am, my story is shocking. I didn’t mean to make a career change. I just wanted to have something, to feel like I could succeed at anything at all. I came into tech because the last six years of being an adjunct instructor I fought to have rights, to get a pay increase, to create a community. And I left with nothing. I came into tech because I found support, a community that I was seeking for years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four days after having my fourth kid, I went into my OBGYNs office. It haunts me. I told her about the horrific symptoms I was experiencing, and she told me “it’s not my problem.” I’ve told this story a thousand times, and it still hurts to say it. And it hurts because she said it to me, but it hurts because I’m not the only one who has felt abandoned in the room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not the only one who has felt like there was no hope. I’m not the only one who’s felt like no one could ever understand. I’m not the only one who has been left alone in the corner to watch every other person go on living their life while I died a little bit more inside everyday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s everybody’s problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is not a moment in time that I don’t carry that with me. I carry it with me because I very much do not ever want any other person to feel that way. I carry it with me, because it drives a force inside of me to do what I can to change the systems that make people feel like they are nothing, like they are not worthy, like no one should help them. When I left that room that day, I thought that I was not worth anyone’s time. I wasn’t a person; I was a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have always been a passionate person. I have always been intense. It has both been a characteristic that drives me and one that has isolated me from people. Sometimes I’m too much for people. I am more than they can handle. But I can’t help being fully myself. I can’t help that I can’t stop myself when I see new paths for change or growth or whatever that are driven by this intense desire to make sure that no one feels alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started a &lt;a href=&quot;https://beautyinthescar.com/&quot;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; to talk about my trauma and this is a crossover post. I learned to code because it stopped the trauma from repeating over and over in my head while I sat in front of the computer. I kept coding because I had community. I got excited about coding because I realized that code could’ve prevented what happened to me. But that’s women’s health, and not enough people care about women’s health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If no one will do the thing that needs to be done, I will. But I also know that when we work in isolation, we will never be as effective as we can be with a community. Because with a community there is support. With a community there is meaning and purpose and growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of years ago I was at JSConf Hawaii, and I told a woman that although my trauma was the worst thing that ever happened to me, I wouldn’t take it back. I’m a better person. Without that trauma, I don’t know the importance of community. WIthout that trauma, I don’t get into tech. Without trauma &lt;a href=&quot;https://virtualcoffee.io/&quot;&gt;Virtual Coffee&lt;/a&gt; is never started. Without trauma I don’t understand the importance of vulnerability, of meeting people where they are at, of letting people &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; me; I guard and protect myself. I don’t become the developer that I can be. I don’t find a way to push through those times when people tell me that I can’t do both; that I can’t create community and be a developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is very much about how I became a developer, but it’s very much more about how I became &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt;. And that’s the important part. Because I am a person first. And being human, recognizing the diverse experiences and challenges and talents and perspectives of the people around us matters.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/12/07/I-Came-into-Tech-via-Trauma</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/12/07/I-Came-into-Tech-via-Trauma</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We need to talk: More on the problems juniors are facing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I spend a lot of time talking about the challenges junior developers face when they are trying to break into tech. And honestly, there’s probably a whole book to write about this, a whole chapter on how most education (university, bootcamp, and online paths) doesn’t prepare new devs in the ways that they need to, how junior devs cost companies money, about how some companies let others mentor junior devs just so they can poach them with huge salary increases, about how creating a system of training and transition from support roles to developer roles could be a better way to approach the issue, about how talking more openly about it and about how trying to think about how to flip the hiring process on its head is a good place to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to write about any of that. I’m just going to point out some of the problems juniors are facing and suggest where we might want to start rethinking this process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;clear-exploitation&quot;&gt;Clear Exploitation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Having junior devs write code that goes into your code base without paying them and without making that clear during an interview.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;An interview is not an excuse for free work.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Asking junior devs to do work on your projects with no intention of hiring.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Interviewing a ton of juniors just to figure out who you can get for the least amount of money. (Tangent: when I lost my job during COVID, I interviewed for a position. I did the best on the take home test and was offered the position. But the catch was that the founder offered me $30/hr and told me that she was hoping to get me for less of an hourly wage since I was more junior and then I could work more hours.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Posting a job and interviewing without a real commitment to hiring.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Crushing a candidate’s soul in an interview–some of it is toxic culture, and some of it is trying to check their resilience—that is not what that does—to make the candidate feel grateful for being offered a job.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;other-problems-to-consider&quot;&gt;Other problems to consider&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Portfolios don’t always capture what you’re looking for or are mixed with other people’s work or are the same projects over and over and over (to-do list anyone?). New tangent: I think that being able to communicate code, ask questions, and talk about process and approach can be a better way of judging a candidate. So even opening up one of their projects from GitHub or portfolio and asking them to walk through it and talk about the process, and ask what they would do differently, where they were challenged, etc. could be as useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Giving a coding challenge doesn’t ensure you’re receiving a candidate’s work. I’ve heard hiring managers say that they’ve hired ppl who have done well on take-home tests, but couldn’t keep up with the job or couldn’t explain concepts at work that they applied in the take-home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of this whole problem is that being a junior looking for a job is a rat race. And everyone knows it.
We are exploiting desperation by over-requiring and having unreasonable expectations in interviews.
With a ton of juniors trying to break into tech, a ton of companies without an honest interest in hiring, and then juniors githubs stacked with multiple 4-hour take-home tests, spending 40 hours a week trying to find a job, and frequently for months, there’s a boat-load of problems. And it’s a catch 22 because juniors need more experience. How are they supposed to do that when they’re spending 40hrs a week trying to find a job?
These circumstances do not mimic the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t have a solution here. I just see the problem and the frustration and know that tech is losing good people because most of it isn’t even trying to figure it out. In a sense, this model is survival of the fittest, and I’m not okay with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I want is maybe idealistic. I want to see people and not candidates. I want a clear recognition that each of these people have lives and responsibilities. I want to see the value put on communication. I want to see people and organizations who have the ability to mentor and support to do it. I was lucky to get my first job as a developer. I didn’t have a take-home test or a whiteboard interview. I had a conversation. And that won’t work in every scenario, but I’ll tell you what, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;seeing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; the person in the interview is a good place to start.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/11/30/We-need-to-talk-More-on-the-problems-juniors-are-facing</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/11/30/We-need-to-talk-More-on-the-problems-juniors-are-facing</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I am a Woman in Tech</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;i-am-a-woman-in-tech&quot;&gt;I am a Woman in Tech.*&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That means that I am technical.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that I am a community builder.
That means that I can give a technical talk in the same week that I mentor and MC an event.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that I don’t want to be put in the project management track.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that there are unexplored tech fields out there, and I’m going to explore them.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that I will get stuck sometimes and ask for help.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that I will be willing to share my experiences.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that I will tell other women about who to avoid in tech.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that I will know the answer or how to find it.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that I am devoted to growing and learning and figuring it out.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that what I value most is good people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;i-am-a-mom-in-tech&quot;&gt;I am a mom in tech.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That means that I will not apologize when I put my kids first.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that sometimes my kids will come into my camera range and wave or scream or cry or kick each other.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that when I have time to code, I will put all the more drive into it.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that tech will never be the most important thing in my life.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that I recognize the importance of community, dependability, and flexibility.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that I do not have time to waste.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that I will not work with people who have a problem with that or who passive-aggressively comment on the number of children I have.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that I have specific opinions, viewpoints, and perspectives on things that most other people in tech do not have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;i-am-a-community-creator-in-tech&quot;&gt;I am a community creator in tech.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That means that I have a community that I am fiercely in support of.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that I see every person as a human being before I ever look at them as a dev.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that I allow myself to be vulnerable because I know how important that is.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that I value community over competition, caring over pushing people to the very limits of their emotional wellbeing.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that I value growth and mentorship and teaching at all levels.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that I meet people where they are.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that I value exploration.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that people are what matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;i-am-an-adhd-person-in-tech&quot;&gt;I am an ADHD person in tech.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That means that I communicate differently than a lot of people I know.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that sometimes when I’m really excited about an idea, I talk loud and fast and for a long time without realizing it.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that sometimes I hyper-focus and it takes a longgggg time to break out of it.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that other times, I can’t focus at all.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that sometimes I feel things very intensely and find it hard to communicate.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that sometimes I over-communicate.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that I value my systems.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that sometimes when other people are going to sleep I just can’t stop myself.&lt;br /&gt;
That means that I deeply value the people who have agreed to come on this journey with me. &lt;br /&gt;
That means that I’m running a marathon, but sprinting the whole time–and I love it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a person in tech.&lt;br /&gt;
I am dynamic and complex.&lt;br /&gt;
I reserve the right to change at any time.&lt;br /&gt;
I will not be labeled as one thing.&lt;br /&gt;
I can do all of the things that I want, and if you tell me I can’t I’ll take that as a challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was 18, an adult woman told me, “Bekah, you can’t change the world.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;*This is not met to represent anyone else; it’s solely based on my feelings and experiences.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/11/27/I-am-a-Woman-in-Tech</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/11/27/I-am-a-Woman-in-Tech</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Let Them Write Tests: An Argument for Cypress</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When I was learning to code, testing was covered a little bit, but I didn’t grasp the full awesomeness of what we test and why we test it. But I have been lucky enough–yes, I said lucky–to learn more about testing and dive into Testing Library and Cypress, but I’m just going to talk about Cypress here. Not only did I learn how to test, and strategies behind testing, but I also learned a lot about the codebase I was working in, how the components work together, how the user interacts with the program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is a big win. These are things that new devs struggle with. Yes, I may have had a couple of nightmares about the tests I was writing. Yes, I may have been stuck in testing hell for a while. But learning these things helped me to gain confidence as a developer. Letting new devs write tests benefits everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And Cypress is a pretty good place to start for your frontend needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you’re still not convinced that you should be writing E2E tests, let &lt;a href=&quot;https://kentcdodds.com/blog/confidently-shipping-code&quot;&gt;Kent C. Dodds&lt;/a&gt; convince you: “I write tests because they allow me to accomplish more than I could otherwise. I now have thousands of Kents in the form of automated tests telling me whether changes are breaking use cases.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-cypress&quot;&gt;What is Cypress&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cypress is An open source, JavaScript end-to-end (E2E) testing framework that bundles tools and libraries to get your tests up and running quickly. And one of the cool things about it is that it runs in the browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-is-cypress-good-for-beginners&quot;&gt;Why is Cypress good for beginners?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;its-readable&quot;&gt;It’s readable.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;context(&quot;Login&quot;, () =&amp;gt; {
  beforeEach(() =&amp;gt; {
    cy.visit(&quot;localhost:8080/login&quot;);
  });
  it(&quot;finds and types email&quot;, () =&amp;gt; {
    cy.get(&quot;#email&quot;)
      .type(&quot;leslieKnope@pawnee.gov&quot;)
      .should(&quot;have.value&quot;, &quot;leslieKnope@pawnee.gov&quot;);
  })
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just looking at the test above, you get an idea of what’s happening. Before each test is run in this section, the testrunner visits the url that’s specified. The “it” block tells what to expect and checks for the outcome. Also takes a callback (“verb”) and checks the assertion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you keep reading, you see that it’s finding the input, typing, and checking that the value is there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(And if you’re familiar with Testing Library, you can also add Cypress Testing library to leverage those commands as well–highly recommend.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-testrunner-rocks&quot;&gt;The testrunner rocks.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you run cypress open, the testrunner opens in the browser. The testrunner allows you to see exactly where each part of the test is happening and where it fails. You can see each step in the browser. So if we’re looking at the example above, you would see the email address being typed in the input. When you test a button click, you see that as the test runs. You see what you wrote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And along with that, when your test fails, you see exactly where it fails and there are usually really great error messages that go along with the failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the ease of setup–getting it up and running only takes a couple of minutes–the readability of tests, and the testrunner giving a really clear picture of what the tests are doing and how you’re interacting with your software, using Cypress to test your frontend shouldn’t be a hard decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you’re new to the devlife and you’re wondering what to learn next or to add to your project, this is a great place to start.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/11/21/Let-Them-Write-Tests-An-Argument-for-Cypress</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/11/21/Let-Them-Write-Tests-An-Argument-for-Cypress</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I'll say it again: Kindness Matters</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The world can be a really messy and hard and sad place sometimes. And we’re all carrying our own stories. Some of us wear them on our sleeves. Some of us let them slip out from time to time. Some of us keep them very well hidden. Some of us do them all. But at the end of the day, it doesn’t matter if we’re a frontend dev–or if you know how to spell it–a backend dev, a data scientist, or learning to dev. We’re all human. And kindness matters. I said it &lt;a href=&quot;https://bekahhw.github.io/blog/2018/04/14/If-one-of-your-goals-isn-t-to-help-someone,-you-re-doing-it-wrong&quot;&gt;before&lt;/a&gt;, and I’ll say it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here’s the thing, yes, you should be a decent human being, but also, being a kind and empathetic human being allows so much more room for growth for those around you. I feel kind of gross even saying that thing; productivity shouldn’t be your motivation to be a kind person, but, hey, if that’s what gets you there, fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve talked about going through trauma, and if you want to hear more of that story, you can check out my &lt;a href=&quot;http://beautyinthescar.com/&quot;&gt;trauma-blog&lt;/a&gt; that I just started, but two of the most important things I took from that experience are 1. community matters and 2. the person-centered approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, person-centered care–a term I’m stealing from the medical community–is when a person puts your experiences, wellbeing, needs and feelings at the centre of the caring and support process, and means we seek to understand and have empathy for your daily experience. If we remember that each of the people in our communities aren’t just workers and they’re dynamic human beings with multiple responsibilities who both succeed and fail everyday, we’ll do a better job of avoiding becoming a gatekeeper and creating stronger communities. The person-centered approach is driven by empathy and the mindset that each person on your team has something valuable to contribute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;be-a-gandolf&quot;&gt;Be a Gandolf&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we use this person-centered approach, a couple of things should happen: empathy is increased and we move away from a Me/Them model towards a We/Us model. What exactly does that mean? It means that we work together as a team to accomplish a goal, rather than making someone feel excluded from the team. This is not to say that there’s no leadership. If anything, the leader should establish this mentality and make it easier for the other teammates to follow suit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;let-the-hobbits-speak&quot;&gt;Let the Hobbits speak&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allowing everyone to become active participants in establishing the type of community that helps everyone to thrive, helps to create the “we” instead of “them.”
If you’re doing these things–inclusivity, positivity, we-mentality, person-centered approach–it should create an environment where everyone learns from each other. I think this is one of the most important parts of creating positive community and decreasing gatekeepers. By keeping our minds open to learning from anyone in an organization no matter the status or role, we allow ourselves to be versatile and open to growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;but-how-does-that-contribute-to-productivity&quot;&gt;But &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; does that contribute to productivity?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A growth mindset is one where the individual believes hard work, openness to input from others, and learning can develop talents as opposed to a fixed mindset where a person is more likely to believe they are born with talents. According to Harvard business review, “[employees from companies with a growth-mindset] report feeling far more empowered and committed; they also receive far greater organizational support for collaboration and innovation. In contrast, people at primarily fixed-mindset companies report more of only one thing: cheating and deception among employees, presumably to gain an advantage in the talent race.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;employees-in-a-growth-mindset-company-are&quot;&gt;Employees in a “growth mindset” company are:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;47% likelier to say that their colleagues are trustworthy,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;34% likelier to feel a strong sense of ownership and commitment to the company,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;65% likelier to say that the company supports risk taking, and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;49% likelier to say that the company fosters innovation -&lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/archive-toc/BR1411&quot;&gt;Harvard Business Review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hearing the horror stories of other early devs makes my heart hurt. It’s not that hard to be a kind human being. This has been a &lt;em&gt;really, really&lt;/em&gt; hard week for me. My PTSD from an event four years ago was triggered and it took me a while to figure out what the heck was happening with my brain, why I couldn’t sleep, why that anxiety was crushing my chest. But do you know what makes it feel manageable? Having kind and caring people around me. The people who care first about &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt; as a person and not what I got done this week. And a side-effect of that, &lt;em&gt;yes&lt;/em&gt; is that I got stuff done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote a presentation and tests and refactored code and wrote blog posts and organized events and mentored people. None of that happens if I don’t know that I have support. If no one asks me how I’m doing, and &lt;em&gt;means&lt;/em&gt; it. But also, it’s okay if I did none of that. Be kind to your employees, be kind to your co-workers, and be the best listener you can be. Because you don’t know what anyone else has been through, and acknowledging everyone’s experiences and supporting each other is more important than that code you’re writing anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/11/08/I'll-say-it-again-Kindess-Matters</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/11/08/I'll-say-it-again-Kindess-Matters</guid>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
